[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 24]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
Healer Lin
really has the ability to find a cure.
Just in a few minutes,
my shoulders and neck
feel much more comfortable.
Next time when I draw my sword,
I tell you,
it's absolutely...
There is nobody left.
Just leave.
♪Where to hear the song
in the earthly life?♪
♪The night is half bright
when coming back♪
I haven't heard such a sweet song
for a long time.
Could you please sing it for me again?
Will you pay me?
They paid for my songs.
Is the reason why you want to make money
that you want to find your mother?
♪Beacon smoke rises from the vast desert♪
♪The moon shade waves
above the mountains♪
♪The flute blows away the cracked dream♪
♪Into the dark cold night,
the song I pursue♪
That's beautiful.
Are you mocking me?
Why would you say that?
I do feel the song is pleasant to hear.
Really?
My mother taught me that.
Your mother also likes singing?
But he doesn't like it.
My mother always sings secretly.
He
is your stepfather?
Does he treat your mother badly?
He is just an animal.
Miss Shiyi,
how about
telling them to come back?
In case a real fight breaks out,
we have the advantage of more men.
That's right.
Call more men
in case of emergency.
No need.
I will definitely get the roster.
Do you think they will fight each other?
Most likely.
Then,
you should go have a look.
Go quickly and return soon.
Okay.
Just because your mother and you
were given to him to settle a debt,
he takes both of you
as his property
that he can beat and scold at will.
In his eyes,
only money matters.
If he feels unhappy,
he takes his anger out on my mother.
My mother used to have
a very beautiful red dress,
but he didn't like it.
He forbade my mother from wearing it.
On one of my mother's birthdays,
she wore that dress
and looked gorgeous.
But when he found out,
he...
He beat my mother.
That man got along well
with your mother?
I... I've seen it.
That man once gave my mother
a bag of money.
He often bought her delicious treats.
Come on.
Taste it.
Eat.
When
did he leave?
I mean,
he and your mother.
Half a month ago,
they disappeared suddenly.
By the way,
my mother told me
that she would take me to the capital
to learn singing
and become the most popular singsong girl.
She said that.
So, she will come back for me.
Right?
Naughty girl.
Naughty girl!
A menial girl
dares to dream
of becoming a singsong girl
and making money by singing.
Wei,
go to Commander Xiao
and give this to him.
Ask him to come over quickly
with his men.
Tell him that…
Di Renjie wants to meet him.
Di Renjie?
You are Di Renjie?
Trust me.
I will definitely find your mother.
Naughty girl, where are you going?
You come back.
Wei Sheng,
I am the magistrate of Lanfang County,
Di Renjie.
Di Renjie?
I'm asking you,
last night,
what on earth did you go off to do?
I...
de-delivered the goods.
Delivered goods.
What goods?
To whom?
Where were you delivering the goods to?
Didn't I tell you?
It
has nothing to do with you.
It has nothing to do with me.
But it concerns Wei's mother.
It concerns
your wife.
I guess,
last night,
the carriage you were driving
wasn't carrying dead sheep at all.
It was
her corpse.
It was not just one corpse,
but
two corpses.
She didn't elope with another man.
She was
killed by you.
[Green Bird Inn]
You talk nonsense!
Everyone in the town knows
that indecent woman
eloped with a foul man.
I am the victim!
You... you keep accusing me of murder.
Where is the justice in that?
Where is the justice?
Di Renjie,
do you solve cases purely on guesses?
You say they were corpses,
then they were corpses?
You say I killed her,
then I must have killed her?
Where is the evidence?
You don't have evidence
and yet falsely accuse me of murder.
You're slandering me!
Magistrate Di is seeking justice here.
Who dares to be disrespectful?
[Green Bird Inn]
Now,
the magistrate of Lanfang County
presides over the case
of the disappeared Wei Sheng's wife.
Hold court trial.
Wei Sheng,
your wife
eloped with another man.
Is that true?
Yes.
That is true.
Up to now,
you still don't tell the truth?
I...
No.
- Wei Sheng,
- I...
you are a stingy person.
That
does not violate the law.
But your stinginess drove you
to commit murder.
Your wife,
in your eyes,
is no more than a possession.
She is just a slave
who must keep working.
As long as you saw
she got close to any guest,
you would think
they committed adultery.
You killed them
and took that man's property.
Is that true?
Wei,
please go out
and get some fresh air.
No.
I want to hear this.
Magistrate,
you wronged me.
All of this is your imagination.
Evidence.
Where is your evidence?
You don't have it.
These
are your wife's belongings.
The biggest flaw in your murder
is that you didn't burn them.
You're too greedy for money.
You keep everything
left behind by travelers
coming and going.
You even wanted
to sell them to me.
Let me take you to see something good.
You have good taste, Healer Lin.
It's just a bit expensive.
You have never
regarded her as your wife.
So you never know
how much she loved this
red dress.
No.
You said she eloped with another man.
But why didn't she
take her favorite dress with her?
That seems unreasonable.
Also,
the robe I'm wearing
belonged to that man.
Wei can testify to that.
This robe seems to belong to that guest.
You are so greedy
that you even took
a dead man's clothes
and sold them.
The corpses
were tossed out into the wilds by you.
I'm afraid I can't find them.
But as for the place
where you hid them,
I can make it clear to you.
Mr. Lang,
the two corpses were hidden
in your warehouse.
I'm afraid
you didn't know about that.
In my warehouse?
Those two corpses
were hidden in my warehouse?
Wei Sheng,
you were afraid of being caught
transporting the bodies out of the inn.
So, you took the corpses
to Mr. Lang's warehouse
and dismembered them
with the aim to dispose of them.
Until last night,
I came here
and ruined your plan.
Mr. Wei,
where did you go driving a carriage
in the middle of the night?
Healer Lin.
This was
made for me by my mother.
If it weren't this immoral woman,
how could I...?
Have you made up your mind?
Come with me.
Please don't do that.
How is it? Is it delicious?
She always looked down on me,
and she often flirted with guests.
You are right.
I killed her.
They deserved it.
You animal!
Give me back my mother!
You...
Kill them!
They were both killed by me.
Give me back my mother!
You animal!
Take him away.
Animal!
[Green Bird Inn]
Magistrate Di,
you truly live up to your reputation.
I have told you
that the Chief always plans carefully.
Magistrate Di,
please give me the thing.
What thing?
Our Chief said
that Heiyan's messenger disappeared
mysteriously.
As long as the case was given to you,
you would find out the reasons behind it.
I doubted it before.
But now it seems that
our Chief
does foretell things accurately.
You are from Heiyan.
Magistrate Di,
thanks a lot
for this case.
Mr. Lang,
can you
speak more clearly?
Sure.
More than ten days ago,
our messenger
compiled a new roster
of the members in Lanfang County
and was to give it to our Chief.
Unexpectedly,
when he passed by Qingchuan,
he
disappeared mysteriously.
I came here
with the aim of seeking the reason.
But our Chief said
the quickest way to find out the reason
was to give this case to you.
Am I
clear enough?
Magistrate Di,
let's be straightforward.
Give me
the roster.
What roster?
I truly
don't know.
Magistrate Di,
have you ever heard
a nursery rhyme?
Boqi.
Boqi
eats nightmares at night.
This world
is just a nightmare.
Heiyan, however,
exterminates nightmares.
Nightmares are gone,
and welfare comes.
Heiyan's
roster of Lanfang County.
It seems that Heiyan
wants to stage a comeback.
Thank you
for helping Heiyan fulfill its dream
in Qingchuan.
Where is
that roster?
Magistrate Di.
Di Renjie.
You are unmatched in intelligence.
Please don't joke with me.
You have found the messenger,
so the roster is surely in your hands.
Be sensible
and give it to me.
Di Renjie,
our Chief
didn't say we should take your life.
But the Chief
didn't say we should not
take your life, either.
So, the man killed by Wei Sheng
was the messenger of Heiyan.
So,
he invited me to Qingchuan
because he wanted to use me
to investigate the case
that your messenger lost the roster
of Lanfang County.
Yun Tian.
Okay.
What's going on?
Attack!
It seems that your reinforcements
won't be able to come.
His reinforcements.
You would always be a good official,
won't you?
Okay.
I got it.
In such a world,
people like him
are rare these days.
What...
I have paid you.
Such a person
is so shameless!
Shameless!
Yanzhou rock oil!
[*Ancient oil]
Healer Lin,
you really know a lot.
Since you know this thing,
you must know my determination
of getting the roster.
Give it to me.
The way of great learning
consists in manifesting
one's bright virtue
and loving the people.
But can manifesting one's bright virtue
change such a world?
Can loving people ensure
everyone eats his fill?
I
have read all the pre-Qin classics,
but I am still confused.
Then, I met the Chief.
He made me understand
that all things in this world
were born and nurtured by nature.
They follow the way
of mutual generation and restriction.
Their ultimate goal is just to live.
In order to live,
we can't be trapped by kindness.
Then, why is it
up to you
whether a person should live or die?
Anyway,
the roster
can't be handed to the imperial court.
If you insist on keeping it,
I will choose to die
with you.
Naughty!
Be careful of the fire!
Di Renjie.
You
insist
on the benevolence.
But in my eyes,
that is stupid.
Sorry.
It's not my fault...
He is so weak.
You can't save a man
who wants to die.
I put the water here.
The meal is ready.
Please go and have some.
Okay.
Also,
I have finished transcribing
the document sent here yesterday
by the state government,
and I put it in the study.
Please give it
to the Magistrate Assistant later
and don't delay the official duties.
Okay, sure.
I'll buy some medicine for Qiao Tai.
When I'm not with you,
you should take care of yourself.
Don't worry.
I'm also bewitched by her.
Let me ask you a question.
As for the roster,
what do you
plan to do with it?
Who are you
exactly?
I am just
a passer-by.
I simply find you agreeable,
so I decided to help you.
Is there anything wrong with that?
Fine.
You are just a passer-by.
I am
an official appointed by the court.
Now,
I finally got Heiyan's roster.
I should bring it back
and give it to the court.
It should be handled
according to the Tang Code.
What's next?
Next?
The army marches here
and kills
all of the common populace
listed on the roster.
Common populace?
Exactly.
In the past,
the influence of Heiyan covered
Lanfang County.
Many of the local populace
chose to join it,
or they had relatives who joined it.
Heiyan wrote all of their names
into the roster.
As for the people on the roster,
few of them knew
what Heiyan was
and what Heiyan was going to do.
They had no choice.
They only submitted a petition.
What is their crime?
What do you mean?
A long time ago,
Confucius
passed by Pu to reach the Wei state.
But he was attacked by the Pu people.
So, he signed a covenant with them,
saying that he wouldn't go to Wei state.
But thereafter,
Confucius still went to Wei state.
Zigong was confused by this.
[*One of Confucius' disciples]
He thought that
in his heart,
Confucius was always righteous and honest.
How could he go back on his own words?
So, Zigong went to ask Confucius.
Confucius said
that a covenant
signed under duress
wouldn't be approved
by Heaven.
You want me
to spare those people on the roster?
Those stubborn people
should surely be eradicated.
But for those who don't know the case,
even Heaven
won't blame them.
In this place,
everyone could be from Heiyan.
He is from Heiyan.
I could also come from Heiyan.
Mr. Wei could also be from Heiyan.
But Mr. Wei
was guilty of murder,
not of being from Heiyan.
Even that little girl's mother
could be from Heiyan.
How is that possible?
How is that impossible?
Do you know how Heiyan
managed to recruit
these people?
It's nothing more
than coercion and temptation.
Right!
Coercion and temptation.
In Lanfang County,
in Qingchuan Town,
there is no order.
How can an ordinary man
withstand their
coercion and temptation?
If
you hand the roster
to the court,
when the army marches here,
lots of people will die.
Do
all the people listed in this roster
deserve to die?
Do
they deserve to die
in your hands?
[Herbal Shop]
Here is your medicine. Please take it.
Thank you.
Take care.