[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 28]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
He left the dagger
as a warning.
But why did he take away
the little wooden sword?
Look at this.
Hong,
tell me,
what else do you know?
I think you must have guessed it.
I want you to tell me yourself.
Heiyan
is
your brother.
Just leave.
I'll be back.
I thought
the character Ying carved
on the little wooden sword
[Ying]
was my courtesy name.
Now it seems
the little wooden sword
was my brother's toy.
The character Ying
is my brother's given name.
That's right.
Heiyan is Di Ying.
Di Ying.
When did you know
he's in Lanfang County?
I saw the drawing on the pottery shard.
He hasn't changed.
You two run slowly. Don't fall.
Ying, slow down.
Wait for me.
Come. Hurry up.
You knew he is Heiyan.
Why didn't you tell me?
How could I possibly bring this up to you?
Back then, His Lordship
personally drove him away.
It was my father?
If Chu Lei is really your brother,
will you commit fratricide?
Ying, I also want a sword.
No way. You are still young.
You need to study hard.
You're no longer
a member of our family.
Just leave.
Tai,
the five-day deadline isn't up yet.
Chu Lei went back on his words.
They were cut by several different knives.
There should be more than one assailant.
Chu Lei might not be the murderer.
If it wasn't Chu Lei,
who else could it be?
The murderers may be among them.
Magistrate,
these four people have confessed.
The victims were killed by them.
Tell me your names
and occupations.
Chen Tai.
I'm Wang Liu.
Meng Qi.
Han Fang.
I run a teahouse in the east of the city.
Meng Qi
is a scholar preparing for the exams.
Wang Liu is a blacksmith.
Chen Tai
works in a pharmacy.
Do you plead guilty?
We killed them.
Why?
Not for money,
not for revenge.
No grudge among us.
Just to survive.
How did the two
who were killed
threaten your lives?
It is written clearly on Heiyan's notice.
Within five days,
if one man leaves Lanfang County
without permission,
one man chosen at random will be killed.
If two people leave the county
without permission,
two people chosen at random
will be killed.
On that day, the two of them
tried to leave the county
without permission,
and we discovered it.
Have you made up your mind?
When shall we leave?
Today at the Zi hour.
What do you want to do?
Murder!
You are running away
without considering the lives
of the people in the county.
They wanted to run away
without the need to worry about anything.
But our whole families
are still here.
Where can we go?
Besides,
after they left,
some people in the county would be killed.
There was nothing wrong
with us doing that.
- Right.
Right. We are not guilty.
We also want to survive.
Sheer nonsense.
You really can't tell
right from wrong.
Meng Qi,
you are a scholar.
Because of a notice
and
a false rumor,
Tongkang Village
was wiped out.
Now,
there is another notice.
Are you trying to make Lanfang County
suffer the same fate as well?
I'm asking you,
Meng Qi,
if the notice says
as long
as everyone
in your family,
old and young,
dies,
the people in Lanfang County
can be safe.
Will everyone in your family
commit suicide?
Answer me!
If you can
punish the culprit
and bring Heiyan to justice
as you said,
the people in the county
don't have to worry anymore.
Right.
We don't want to be like this, either.
We just want to live.
Take them away.
Yes.
We did this for the people of the county.
Hurry up.
We didn't do anything wrong.
Magistrate.
Get them all on duty.
Take turns to patrol the streets.
Don't let anything like this happen again.
Leave the court.
It's unfair.
Nobody cares about the lives
of the people.
[Starting from today, Heiyan will recruit
new members in five days.]
[Five days later, those who are not
members of Heiyan will be killed.]
Huaiying.
From today on,
stay in the Magistrate's Office.
Things have gone this far.
You don't have to put yourself
in harm's way.
Magistrate,
you have thought of a solution?
No.
Magistrate,
a man like him isn't worth it.
You have your limits.
But it might harm the people around you.
Go have a rest.
Thank you.
Huaiying,
what's your plan
for the next step?
If Chu Lei
really is Di Ying,
he will come to me.
Even if he will come,
it will be after the five-day deadline.
When the five-day deadline is up,
he will do what he said.
What do you think
I can do?
I think
you should report an emergency
to the governor
and ask him to send troops
to Lanfang County
to capture those with Heiyan tattoos.
At least, it will stabilize
the current chaos.
If we capture all the people
with Heiyan tattoos,
the number of people is too many
for the prison of the Magistrate's Office.
But when the five-day deadline is up,
people with Heiyan tattoos will
be everywhere in Lanfang County.
Did you forget the chaos
when we just came to Lanfang County?
Those with Heiyan tattoos
are just ordinary people.
They didn't break any law.
They
just want to survive.
Heiyan, please don't kill me.
It is hung there.
I also have this. Yeah.
Come back.
Don't run.
- It's for your own good.
- I don't want it.
You...
Come back with me.
What are you doing?
Magistrate,
I have no Heiyan tattoo.
I'm not afraid of dying.
Don't kill me.
Let my child survive, Magistrate.
Thank you, Magistrate.
No!
Go.
- No!
- Go!
Hurry up and go.
No.
Hong,
do you still think
I should report to the governor
and ask him to send troops
to capture these people?
Don't kill me.
Let's go back.
Heiyan, please, don't kill me.
They are really running wild.
Such a scene on the street.
Do we still have to patrol the streets?
[Lanfang County Magistrate's Office]
Huaiying,
what are you doing?
I'm still thinking about Chunyu's case.
Now,
the murder case of Mr. Chen (the Sixth)
and his wife,
the case of the death of Loong,
and
the tragic case of Tongkang Village
have all been solved.
But I still can't figure out
one thing in Chunyu's case.
Chu Lei
has already
punished Lin Fan.
If Chunyu
was really killed by Chu Lei,
here is the problem.
Why did he take revenge
after ten years?
Chunyu's case
was the beginning of the series of things.
The murder case of Mr. Chen (the Sixth)
and his wife,
Loong's case,
and the tragic case of Tongkang Village
correspond respectively
to love,
hatred,
desire,
and ignorance.
Also,
the five-day deadline in Lanfang County
corresponds
to greed.
How will Chu Lei
concretize anger
and dislike?
We are just reacting blindly.
This way, we only end up
at a disadvantage in every situation.
If I can't solve Chunyu's case,
I won't be able to do anything.
Are you enjoying
your stay here?
I'm just waiting for death.
Anywhere is the same.
I want you ask you
about one thing.
Please tell me the truth.
Please go ahead.
I won't lie to you.
After Chunyu married
into your Lang family,
how did she
get along with your son?
They didn't get along well.
At the beginning,
I really liked Chunyu.
She was beautiful,
skilled,
and kind.
But after she married
into our family,
she never smiled.
It wasn't until she was abducted
that I knew she had never
slept with my son.
Such being the case,
why didn't you
break off their engagement?
Our Lang family
was a big family which was respected
in Tongkang Village.
Why should we
break off their engagement?
Was my son supposed
to sacrifice his own feelings
for Chunyu and her poor sweetheart?
Sweetheart?
Yes.
She
and her sweetheart secretly pledged
to marry long ago.
It was just that her father,
the shopkeeper of Xiao's Dyeing House,
got in the way.
That was why they couldn't get married.
Let go of my daughter!
Get lost!
I tell you,
if you don't have any accomplishments,
you'll never see my daughter again.
Get lost!
- Chunyu.
- Father, let go of me!
Wait for me.
Go.
Chu Lei,
don't go.
Go.
Chu Lei.
- Don't go.
- Go with me.
Chu Lei.
But when I asked you,
didn't you say
you had never heard of Chu Lei?
I really don't know this man.
Nor have I ever met him.
I don't want to know who he is.
Well?
I asked my son to divorce Chunyu.
Do you think it's improper?
I was thinking
if you
had fulfilled them
and had broken off the engagement
that led to the marriage in name only,
Tongkang Village
would not have been wiped out.
Perhaps
your son
could have survived.
This was the truth on that night.
That night,
your daughter Chunyu
came home to visit you on the surface.
In fact,
she and Chu Lei had decided
to elope overnight.
Chu Lei
entered Chunyu's bedroom
through here
so that they could meet.
When Chu Lei
was climbing,
the drunk Loong
suddenly passed by.
Chu Lei.
When I climbed up,
Loong saw me.
What shall we do then?
Can we still leave?
It might not be a bad thing.
At that time,
he came up with a plan.
Chu Lei
climbed out
carrying a paper effigy
from Xiao's Dyeing House,
which was made by Chunyu.
He wanted
Loong
to see
he had abducted
Chunyu.
He did so
to protect Chunyu's reputation.
A married woman
eloped with someone.
That would be a terrible thing to hear
if it got out.
That explains one thing.
You found Chunyu's room was a mess.
But you were so close.
Yet you didn't hear any noise.
Where were you when it happened?
I was in the next room.
How come you didn't hear the commotion
in your daughter's room?
Chunyu was married at that time.
How could she possibly do
something so out of line?
Magistrate,
don't ruin my daughter's innocence.
Shopkeeper Xiao,
do you know
after Chunyu married into the Lang family,
she never slept
with her husband?
You...
You knew it.
You must know
another thing.
That night,
Chunyu left
with all her valuable belongings.
You would know it after checking it.
Chunyu and Chu Lei
must have eloped.
You hid all the facts,
leading to Chu Lei's imprisonment.
Chunyu
is still missing.
Well,
were you protecting
your daughter's reputation
or saving your own face?
I...
Look at this.
[Chunyu]
Chunyu?
I found this
on Loong's table.
That night,
Loong accidentally saw the figure
on the second floor
of Xiao's Dyeing House
and saw through Chu Lei's plan.
Then
evil thoughts crept into his mind.
When Chunyu saw him putting out the light,
she went out secretly
with her bag
according to their plan.
[Xiao's Dyeing House]
At this time,
Loong saw there was no one around.
He pounced on Chunyu
and dragged her into his meat shop.
What do you want to do?
Are you planning to elope
with your secret lover?
If you make out with me...
He didn't know
Chunyu's earring
fell in the street.
Later, Chu Lei waited a long time
for Chunyu but didn't see her.
He came back to look for her.
Outside the meat shop,
he picked up Chunyu's earring.
After the incident,
Loong accused him of guilt.
You helped
put Chu Lei in jail.
Later on,
Loong sold Chunyu's belongings one by one.
Good thing he couldn't read much.
He didn't know
[Chunyu]
the two characters Chunyu.
So,
the cloth-wrapper was kept
[Chunyu]
and was used to wipe knives
and wrap meat.
My daughter!
Chunyu.
Shopkeeper Xiao,
you might never expect
that the murderer
who killed your daughter
lived across the street
from Xiao's Dyeing House.
Shopkeeper Xiao,
you covered it up deliberately,
so the real murderer
went free.
A good man
died in his boots.
Loong has died
and can't be punished.
Do you know you are guilty?
Yes, I'm guilty.
I'm guilty.
Take him away.
My daughter...
Magistrate,
your way of solving the case
is really clever.
Well,
Chunyu's case has been solved.
But what does it mean
for Chu Lei's five-day deadline?
Cases
should be solved one by one.
As for the five-day deadline,
just spend every and each day.
Heiyan showed up at Lin Fan's house.
Did he just want to punish Lin Fan?
You killed Lin Fan?
He shouldn't have revealed my secret.
I have to somehow punish him.
It's very easy for Heiyan to kill a man.
Why did he spare Lin Fan's life?
Lin Fan.
Miss Cao,
I just passed by
and heard you were playing the instrument.
I couldn't help listening for a while.
If I've disturbed you,
please don't mind.
Please don't mind.
I don't mind.
How was the piece of music?
I'm a vulgar man.
I don't understand music.
But I feel it is pleasant to hear.
I can't explain why.
I already knew you were a scholar.
Why do you pretend to be a vulgar man?
Miss Cao,
if there is nothing else,
I will...
I want to see him
before the Magistrate meets him.
Who?
You know whom I'm talking about.
I also know
you can take me to him.
[Lanfang County Magistrate's Office]
Magistrate, we knew we were wrong.
We knew we were wrong.
Shut up.
Magistrate.
You
killed innocents.
You should be beheaded
according to the Code.
I have reported
the case to the Ministry of Justice.
You will be punished
according to the Tang Code.
Today
is the last day
of the five-day period defined by Heiyan.
I know
you
are all afraid of Heiyan.
You all intend
to get a Heiyan tattoo.
I am incompetent.
I still
don't know
who Heiyan is,
nor do I know
what Heiyan
is up to.
I can understand
you are afraid of Heiyan.
Heiyan made it clear on the notice
that people without a Heiyan tattoo
would be killed.
Fine.
The Magistrate's Office
[Lanfang County Magistrate's Office]
has prepared
a strip of cloth with Heiyan's mark
for everyone.
In this way, everyone
is Heiyan now.
Heiyan
can't kill any innocents then.
They can't kill anyone
who is a member of Heiyan.
From today on,
among all the people in Lanfang County,
only I, Di Renjie,
have no Heiyan's mark on me.
If they want to kill someone,
just kill me.
If
Chu Lei
still avoids me,
he will lose.
Magistrate,
you are putting yourself in danger.
I just want to leave him no other choice.
He can only meet me.
Almost everyone in Tongkang Village
was slaughtered.
There is only one survivor.
He still did it.
Just because Chunyu
married into the Lang family.
He did not do it
just for personal revenge.
Chunyu's case
was the beginning of the series of things.
The murder case of Mr. Chen (the Sixth)
and his wife,
Loong's case,
and the tragic case of Tongkang Village...
Also, the five-day deadline
in Lanfang County...
What does he get
out of it?
He wants nothing from it.
He isn't doing it for personal gain.
He just wants Lanfang County
to be what he wants it to be.
Magistrate.
Magistrate,
something happened.
Miss Cao is missing.
Magistrate,
the runner of the Magistrate's Office
guarding the gate said Miss Cao left
about two hours ago.
Why didn't he tell us earlier?
Maybe it's because
Miss Cao often goes out.
So he didn't see
anything unusual about it.
But the situation is different now!
Huaiying,
what did she say in the letter?
She wants to quell the chaos
in Lanfang County on her own.
How could she have such an idea?
What's her relationship with Di Ying?
He just taught her how to play music.
How could Di Ying listen to her?
I'll figure this out.
Lin Fan.
He took Cao An away.
Cao An has Heiyan's mark on her.
He won't break his promise, will he?
He won't.
You've solved all the mysteries.
Take me to him.
Okay.
Just we two.
Aren't you afraid this is a trap?
You are with me.
I'm not afraid.
Have you thought about one issue?
Why is the difference in character
between the Chu Lei I described
and the Chu Lei you analyzed so great?
I don't think
the difference is great.
Would the Chu Lei I described
let Loong
live those ten years?
Why did the Chu Lei you described
take revenge after ten years?
Exactly.
Because Chunyu,
Loong,
or all the people in Tongkang Village
had nothing to do with him.
Why did he commit the crimes then?
Because of me.
Because it was fun.