[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 1]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
[Imperial Harem]
[Chen's Residence]
[Governor of Yangzhou]
[Chen Zhuliang]
The Governor of Yangzhou, Chen Zhuliang,
you went against the rules of Heaven
with ill intention.
[Empress's Seal]
You are ordered to commit suicide.
Heavenly Fire
set the Ancient Tree on fire.
[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[The Phoenix Seal]
[Chang'an]
[Homeward Inn]
[Hong Liang]
You're up early today.
[Di Renjie, courtesy name Huaiying]
It's not even noon yet.
Early in the morning,
why did you go to the Imperial Academy?
Imperial Academy?
I... I didn't.
Wuben Ward
in the fifth month of the year...
[Imperial Academy]
The scent
of sophora flowers is all over Chang'an.
At this time of the year,
the sophora flowers
outside of the Imperial Academy
in the Wuben Ward
are in full bloom.
The sophora flowers
still have the morning dew on them.
I went to see your mentor, Wei Wuji.
He's now the Grand Secretariat
of the Institute
for the Advancement of Literature.
The examination for classicists
is tomorrow.
Here's the admission ticket.
I'm not going.
Huaiying,
you know what.
The Empress has reformed the examination
this year.
No matter where you come from,
no matter what your background is,
everyone has a chance.
Those commoners
all applied for the examination
and traveled thousands of li
to the capital.
Who doesn't want to pass the examination
and follow the right path?
You're drinking my water again.
How about ordering two dishes?
It won't cost you much.
Excuse me.
Sir.
Thanks.
Morning.
Morning...
Did you hear what I said?
In the future,
I can teach
or write documents for others.
At worst, I can be a bookkeeper.
Chang'an is so big.
I'll be able to make a living.
Huaiying,
to travel to Western Regions,
you had to get a passport
from a guarantor.
Do you know how much you owe?
You two.
It's time to pay the rent.
The rent has been overdue for days now.
Sir,
please give us a few more days.
You've been in arrears for days.
Well, you two
have money to eat and drink with your kid
but no money to pay the rent.
You two stop right there.
Where's the money you owe?
I'm telling you,
all of you,
And
you stayed in the Western Regions
for many years.
Now you're finally back in Chang'an,
but you don't go back to your home
and choose to live here.
That's fine.
I'll put up with it.
Excuse me.
Sir.
I'd like one bowl of goat soup
and three naan.
Sure.
That's enough.
How much do they owe you?
It's on me.
Ask him for it.
Bake the naan a little longer.
Go.
Sure.
One bowl of goat soup with three naan.
Bake the naan a little longer.
You still want to eat?
I've been so worried
about your examinations
that I don't even feel like
eating a single bite.
I...
Even my belt became loose.
Sir.
Here's your goat soup and naan.
- That's it.
- Wait.
Take this.
Sure.
If you keep on like this,
I'll fail my master.
It's from the mister over there.
Did you hear what I just said?
I'm listening.
I owe others money, idle away the time,
and don't go home, right?
You brought those two bandits with you.
Do you even know them?
Ma Rong and Qiao Tai, right?
Where are they?
[Qiao Tai]
[Wensheng Music House]
[Xiao, Ta, Lu]
[Ma Rong]
On the first day of the fifth month,
a big event happened in Chang'an.
Who knows?
What is it?
Outside the palace,
there was the Empress's
favorite Wutong tree.
It's said to attract the phoenix
to bless our Great Tang.
But on the first day of the fifth month,
the tree
was struck by lightning.
Guess who did this?
- Wasn't it nature? A natural disaster.
- A natural disaster.
- Exactly.
I think it's a man-made disaster.
It can't be a man-made disaster.
It's a natural disaster.
How can it be a man-made disaster?
Let's bet on it.
A natural disaster.
Yeah, you guys bet on it.
Dare you?
Come on, bet on it.
I'll take it.
Bet.
How to bet?
Traditional betting.
Two whites and three blacks
are called ''Xiao'', a natural disaster.
Three whites and two blacks
are called ''Ta'', a man-made disaster.
Let's bet on it
[Lu]
and see who wins.
[Ta]
Place your bets...
Come on, Xiao...
Xiao. Lu. Ta.
Ta.
Come on... Go ahead.
- Go ahead...
- Come on.
Come on.
Come on. Place your bets.
Xiao. Lu. Ta.
Lu.
You organized gambling and cheated.
That's a baseless accusation.
I didn't cheat.
But you did discuss state affairs.
What...
Stop there.
Show me your passports.
I'm pissed off to hear that.
And
from tomorrow,
stop wearing that Hu clothing.
It looks terrible.
Put on the Jinzi I bought you.
I'll get it for you.
Fence this place in.
Yes, Sir.
Officer.
Don't move.
No one is allowed to leave the inn.
Check every corner.
You go over there.
I'll go upstairs.
Go...
Go and check upstairs.
You get out.
Quick.
You go over there.
All get out.
Go. Quick.
Don't move.
Quick.
Quick. Go.
My lychees.
Lychees?
Come out.
Come out. Quick.
You, get up.
You can go.
You. Still eating?
Up.
Search carefully.
Five days ago,
the Tongling Store in the East Market
lost a precious pearl.
Yesterday,
we caught a dealer purchasing loot.
According to him,
the thief and the loot
are in this inn.
Who sold you the pearl?
Officer,
I've told you everything.
I only agreed to trade here
at noon today,
but I don't know
who I'm dealing with.
Officer, he's lying.
How could this
possibly happen in our inn?
Bring me the register.
Okay...
We don't do that kind of thing.
Officer.
You don't even write the date.
It's a scribble.
How can I read it?
No, Officer.
It's a small inn.
We don't have enough staff
to write down everything.
I beg your pardon.
What's it got to do with us?
- Right.
- That's right.
Nothing to do with us.
You can't frame good people.
Right.
Shut up.
Since no one admits it,
we'll take everyone back.
Why?
You must see clearly.
Officer, we're all innocent.
Sir,
tomorrow is the imperial examination.
You can't just arrest anyone you see.
Right.
We're here to take the examination.
We have to take the examination tomorrow.
How can we still take it?
That's right.
Stop! Who is there?
Catch him.
Quite skillful.
What?
You stole and want to run away?
I didn't steal anything.
This move...
Bring it on.
Take this thief back.
Stop.
It's not him.
How do you know?
He's just a deserter.
Desertion is a capital offense.
He's hiding in this inn.
I've never even seen him.
Look at him.
His skin is dark.
His cheeks are red.
This is the typical face of one weathered
by years of being on duty
in the Western Regions.
The red color on the dagger
is the tie on the chain mail
of our Tang soldiers.
You've taken off your armor
and put down your sword,
but you still can't let go
of the red color that accompanied you
through thick and thin, right?
My mother is seriously ill.
I just want to see her again.
Give me the register.
[Register of Guests]
[Xu Hui]
Xu Hui
is a charcoal seller.
He cuts firewood
and makes charcoal all day long.
He's suffering from tuberculosis.
It's killing him.
The only thing
he wants to do in his life
[Thank Her Majesty]
is to take this year's
[for the reforms]
new imperial examination.
He's been taking
Butiandazaowan
[*A traditional Chinese pill]
just to regain his vitality.
He
wouldn't steal.
Liu Ben
[Liu Ben]
is from Dayu County,
Qianzhou, Jiangnan Circuit.
He's walked from Dayu
to Chang'an.
He's worn out pairs of straw shoes.
He couldn't afford to eat
and had to make do with cold water.
His hands shook from hunger,
but he didn't miss his exam preparation.
For two days,
he didn't eat a bite of rice
and only drank water.
He wouldn't steal.
[Zhou You]
Zhou You,
from Jiannan Circuit.
Transporting lychees
from Jiannan to Chang'an
takes days,
even at top speed.
In this weather,
lychees can stay in this shape
and don't rot
for less than four days.
What are you doing? Get in line.
Sorry, I can't hold it any longer.
I had some rotten fruit yesterday.
Come out quickly.
The pearl was lost five days ago, right?
So,
it can't be him.
[Feng Mengliu]
Feng Mengliu,
from Yangzhou.
Zhaodi Temple in the city,
recently,
has been restoring the mural
Scenes of the Hell.
They've called on painters
from all over the country.
He's one of them.
He's working in a closed environment.
Of ten days,
only one day off is allowed.
That's today.
He couldn't make it.
[Zhang Hu]
Zhang Hu,
[Wu Bing]
Wu Bing,
with a kid.
Since they got to Chang'an,
the boy always wanted to go out.
But they're
only focused on preparing for the exam.
These days,
they haven't left the inn.
When can we go out and have fun?
That's right.
We've been here for so many days,
but we haven't left the inn.
After the examination tomorrow,
I'll take you to the West Market
the day after tomorrow.
Great!
So it's impossible
for them to steal.
Liu Hai
and Liu Xuantong
are from Longzhou.
Liu Xuantong's been bedridden.
Liu Hai's been with him
and never left the inn.
Yuchi Sinian.
A poor child.
Ever since he came to the inn,
he's been working as a laborer.
And him,
Sun Zizhi.
He's a musician.
Pingkang Ward
is where he works every day.
And the Ashina tribe.
They just want to have a good time
in Chang'an
after the imperial examination.
They
don't have time.
Chen Mingjian.
Since he arrived,
he's never left.
I don't think it's him.
Wu Jingkai.
He left the inn once,
but the place he went
was just in front of the inn.
Guo Chuan hasn't left the inn
since he arrived.
Then, it's Zhong Xiaofei.
Zhong Xiaofei?
I don't think it's him.
It's not him...
Who in the inn is most likely
to steal the pearl?
If your register is correct,
then it's him.
He looks unfamiliar to me.
He
is not on the register either.
If there's a suspect,
it could only be him.
Take him down.
I'm just passing through.
My name's Chen Yaoguang.
Take him down.
I'm just a bookkeeper.
My referee is Yan Mao.
He's in Xinchang Ward.
If you don't believe me,
go to him and ask him.
It's not me.
It could be him.
He's not on the register either.
Sir.
Don't joke with me.
I'm the innkeeper.
How can I be on the register?
I've been here for ten years.
You know what I'm talking about.
You may know what people appear to be,
but you don't know their true colors.
Sir, I'm innocent.
Take him down.
- Yes, Sir.
Officer, I'm innocent.
Officer.
Officer, I'm innocent, Officer.
We got him.
Where's the pearl?
Abacus.
Give it to me.
Hand it over.
Officer, I...
It's not in here.
It's not my abacus.
It's his.
I told you I'm innocent.
Sir, it's not me.
Sir, what are you doing?
Sir, I really didn't take it.
I really didn't take it.
Look, he's the thief.
This is not mine.
He's the thief.
I said I'm innocent.
I'm innocent.
Wait.
This is not his.
Oh heavens.
Bring some water.
Officer.
Look.
There's
a layer of grease on it.
It's because
the innkeeper used it
during his daily grind.
And that abacus
belonged to the fake bookkeeper.
He switched it.
We've got the thief and the loot.
This is
the truth.
I've been stealing for over ten years,
but I never thought I'd get caught
by you guys in Chang'an.
We've got the thief and the loot.
Take him back.
Yes, Sir.
Get up.
Move it.
Quick. Go.
Officer.
Can you spare
that deserter's life?
Thank you, sir.
[West Market]
Huaiying,
the debt,
the return to the house,
I won't talk about them, okay?
You like to get into trouble outside.
I don't care either.
From now on,
you can do whatever you want.
But one thing.
Tomorrow,
can you go to the examination?
You can do whatever you want
from then on.
I...
Look.
Huaiying,
Western Regions are a mess.
Qiao Tai
and Ma Rong,
you don't even know them well.
You brought them back
to Chang'an with you.
Aren't you afraid
of what they'll get you into?
Excuse me.
Take a look...
Make way.
Stop there.
Make way, please.
Stop.
Stop there.
Move aside.
My wine.
Stop.
Stop there.
Make way.
This is too dangerous. This...
Stop there.
Stop.
[Young He Dajing]
Stop there.
Stop.
[Young He Dajing]
He Dajing,
stop there.
[Young Di Renjie]
Huaiying, help me.
Stop there.
We're just fooling around
with He Dajing.
Do you want to keep doing that, then?
Let's go. Let's go home.
[Imperial Academy]
Huaiying,
thank you.
You're welcome.
Stop there.
Huaiying,
this has nothing to do with you.
Huaiying.
Don't hit me...
[He Dajing]
Sir.
Huaiying?
Kill him.
Really a busybody.
Mr. Di.
I'm coming to help.
Make way.
Mr. Di.
Huaiying, run.
Tomorrow you have to...
Make way.
So many people.
Mr. Di, run!
My father is the Minister of Personnel.
Arrest them all!
Take them down.
Don't move...
Don't move.
Be gentle... Looser...
Too... Too tight...
Too tight.
Why did you let them go?
They beat people up.
Yes, they're the ones who beat people.
You can't let them leave.
Crouch down.
Look at you.
Such a big man,
after all these years,
still having people
chasing after you in the streets.
They made a cruel remark
about the Empress.
I got angry
and said a few more retorts.
The Empress has been
promoting new policies.
Especially the tax policy,
it's been reformed from time to time.
No wonder these people...
Di Renjie,
He Dajing,
come out.
Someone wants to see you.
Grand Secretariat Wei,
they are here.
Mr. Wei,
I'm sorry for the trouble.
Mr. Wei.
[Wei Wuji]
Huaiying?
Okay.
Go in and get them.
Don't yell.
Let's insist that we know no one.
Okay.
So you've been traveling
in Western Regions all these years.
Yes.
Shule and Kucha were both interesting.
But the moon in Kunlun was incomparable.
You have also been to Kunlun?
I haven't.
I'm not there yet,
but I yearn for it.
That's why I wanted to hear your story.
I am flattered.
Grand Secretariat Wei.
Grand Secretariat Wei,
I came as soon as I saw your name card.
He Dajing is my close assistant.
Mr. Di was once a student of mine.
It's my fault for not knowing
they've been misbehaving.
It is nothing.
It is just
a street fight.
The two misters
were involved by accident.
No need for the Grand Secretariat
to be here as the guarantor.
I'll release them now.
Thank you.
You are very welcome.
Then we shall continue our talk
about the Western Regions of Tang
will be after your examination
for classicists.
That is settled then.
Mr. Wei, mind your step.
Luckily, we met Grand Secretariat Wei,
or we'd have to
spend a lot of money today.
What about those two?
They're not residents of Chang'an.
It'll be hard for them to get released.
This will be enough, right?
I told you
we can't keep them.
They're trouble.
So what should we do?
Should I
go?
I already took care of it.
A wise man must remember
not to join the wrong side.
Mr. Di.
He's gone.
He really doesn't want us anymore.
[Daning Ward]
Take it out.
This is Chang'an,
not your countryside.
There are laws and regulations.
You have to be careful and obey the law.
Above all,
refrain from discussing happenings
in the palace.
Do you hear me?
I'm full.
The last time I ate this much
was when I killed
a bully's sheep.
Back then,
we robbed the rich to aid the poor.
We never killed an innocent person.
You just admitted
you've committed murder and robbery.
If I were an official,
I'd punish you now.
How much do you owe for your passport
to Western Regions?
I didn't tell her anything.
If you don't want people to know,
keep your voice down at night.
This shabby place.
I don't want your money.
If the city gates are on fire,
the fish in the moat won't survive.
Isn't this what you taught me?
I also taught you
that a noble-minded person
makes his fortune in a proper way.
Only this time and no more.
Excuse me, another naan, please.
Okay.
Don't commit an act of kindness
just because it is petty.
Don't fail to commit an evil act
just because it is trivial.
I remember it, too.
I'll keep an eye on her from now on.
I'll keep an eye on her.
If everyone thinks so like him,
this world will never get better.
[Di's Residence]
Di?
You scared me.
Why did you talk
to the neighborhood official?
Did you know Di Renjie's father used
to be a prominent official in Chang'an?
Did you know his family
owns a big house?
That's weird.
Then why does he stay
in that shabby inn?
I don't know either.
He has so many secrets.
Do you think the name Di Renjie
is also a fake?
A name is just a code.
What's real or fake?
Even if he's using a fake name,
maybe he's got a good reason.
Huaiying,
have you heard?
The categories
of this year's imperial examination
offer many choices.
Regardless of your status
and family background,
you can choose any of them.
There are Confucianism and classic texts.
There are also Astronomy and calculations.
An individualized examination.
Everyone can show their talents.
Mr. Wei told you that?
Didn't you promise
to do well in the exam?
Will you...
I promised him I would go to the exam.
I didn't promise him
I'd do well in the exam.
This thing is interesting.
Huaiying,
why don't you and I make a bet?
If I win,
you'll go to the exam.
If I lose,
you don't have to take the exam.
Two blacks and three whites
are called ''Ta''.
Three blacks and two whites
are called ''Xiao''.
If it's all black,
that's ''Lu''.
If it's all white,
that's ''Kai''.
I choose all whites.
Quick.
If you don't choose,
then it's a win for me.
It's such a big deal,
not a joke.
My fate
must be in my own hands.
Huaiying,
I don't know
what your fate is.
But your fate
has something to do with it.
All candidates,
tidy up your clothes
and enter the examination room.
Leave your belongings here.
Your admission ticket.
Leave your wineskin, too.
This year's examination system
is even stricter.
You're not allowed to bring
any drinking or eating utensils in.
Leave your wine flask here.
If it's found in the exam room,
you'll be disqualified.
Alright...
Don't put it upside down.
It won't spill.
Let's get in.
Next.
Huaiying,
don't tell Mr. Wei
that I carry a wineskin with me.
If he finds out,
the consequences will be unthinkable.
Look.
His Majesty and Her Majesty.
His Majesty.
Her Majesty.
It's truly His Majesty.
The examination is over.
All candidates leave.
Huaiying.
Let's go to drink.
You did well in the exam?
Will you go?
If you don't go,
you're looking down on me.
Let's go... Go...
Study hard for decades,
put pen to paper to serve the court
and gain higher status.
It's been three years.
I can finally go out and about again.
Huaiying,
come.
Look.
This is the Great Tang.
Even though it's nighttime,
it's fully illuminated
and crowded with people.
It's like
a festive feast every moment.
Let's go.
I heard that the Poetry Contest
two days ago
was very exciting.
The singers, dancers, and best poets
from all over the country
came to Chang'an.
There was my favorite,
the top dancer of the Tang,
Ms. Yulan.
And Cao An.
I like her, too.
Her singing
is better than that of all
of the 108 wards in Chang'an.
In the end,
it was Teng Kan
from Penglai
who won first place
in the Poetry Contest.
Teng Kan?
I know him.
Isn't he a military officer?
- He's a general,
- Two gentlemen!
but he's a very good poet now.
Even the Empress and His Majesty
are impressed by his poems.
This place is good.
Are you two guests
of Grand Commandant Zhangsun?
We just want to have a drink.
A private event is held here.
We can't serve you today.
We just want to have a drink.
Then we...
Let's go. Let's drink somewhere else.
Don't pull me.
I'm telling you.
You're nothing.
Huaiying, let me tell you something.
When I become a powerful official,
let's book this place, too.
Then
I'll ride the best horses
and drink the best wine.
We'll order the best dancers.
I must pass the examination
and receive a Jinshi degree.
Huaiying,
what are you looking at?
♪The land nurtures sweet osmanthus♪
♪Distant woods stand tall and strong♪
Huaiying.
Huaiying,
slow down. What are you looking for?
Gentlemen, do you two
want to listen to some music?
Great...
Do you have singers and dancers here?
We have both.
Huaiying, what are you looking for?
May I ask what brings
you two gentlemen here?
I'd like
to see the lady who was singing.
No one was singing.
I clearly heard
someone singing a Bingzhou ditty.
We're closed today.
We can't serve you.
Are you looking down on us?
Why are you all like this?
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Tao,
please invite the two gentlemen in.
Yes.
Well,
please come in.
Huaiying,
let's go.
Let's go.
[Jushui Entertainment House]
[Best singer in Chang'an]
Best singer in Chang'an.
A singer liked by the Empress.
Huaiying,
you've got good taste.
Gentlemen,
we're closed today.
The guards and servants are out.
We're not open for business.
It's all right.
I just want to see
the one who was singing just now.
We're the only ones
in Jushui Entertainment House.
You must have misheard.
But I did
hear someone singing
a Bingzhou ditty.
No one was singing.
No one was singing and that's it.
We're here to drink.
Just serve us wine.
Serve us wine.
Sit, Huaiying. Sit.
Someone,
serve wine.
Why is the wine in this color?
Dajing,
this wine...
Can we afford it?
Just drink it.
Here, Huaiying.
A toast to you.
Come on.
Let's get drunk today.
Slow down.
Wine has strong after-effects.
What? You're afraid I'll get drunk?
Isn't that why we drink?
I like to have a sip every day,
but I don't dare
in front of Mr. Wei.
So don't tell Mr. Wei
about our drinking today.
Is Mr. Wei still so lecturing?
Now, Mr. Wei
has been granted more responsibility.
By order of His Majesty and the Empress,
he's compiling Great Families
based on the Record of Eminent Families
from the Zhenguan Period.
Great Families?
It contains 245 surnames
and 287 families,
divided into nine classes.
All officials above the fifth rank
are included.
The Empress's four families
are listed in the first class.
And soldiers.
Soldiers are only included
if they're promoted
to the fifth rank or above
based on their military merits.
The other clans with no merits
are all at the back.
With this,
the order of the world
is about to change.
Of course, it will.
For those old nobles,
like Grand Commandant Zhangsun,
he'll have a hard time in the future.
Maybe one day,
something will go wrong.
This wine is really good.
I'll drink more today.
What's the smell?
I lift my drink and sing a song,
for who knows if life is short or long.
Man's life is but the morning dew.
Past days many, future ones few.
The melancholy my heart begets
comes from cares I cannot forget.
To alleviate worries,
only drinking will do.
He Dajing.
[Honor the Teacher, Respect the Teaching]
What is the matter, Mr. Wei?
Do well on your exam.
I will
always remember
your teachings.
When can we pick the shining moon
hanging in the sky?
Huaiying,
taste my wine.
Usually,
I'd have drunk it all by now.
But I couldn't bring it
to the examination room today,
so there's still some wine left.
Why is it so light?
It leaked?
It's impossible.
What?
When did it leak?
At the Imperial Academy.
It must have been the servants.
Pity about my good wine.
It's bitter.
Why is it so bitter?
Huanglian.
[*A traditional Chinese herb]
A few days ago,
while preparing for the exam,
I had a toothache,
so I took some Huanglian.
What a bad luck.
We're looking for the suspect.
Search the premises.
Hurry...
Quick.
Open the door.
Open the door now.
Open it.
What's wrong?
Officer.
Open the door.
Quick.
Quick. Search.
Make way...
Let's go.
[Yaxin]
Yaxin, it's me.
Sister,
when can I get out of here?
Just a little longer.
There are Jinwu Guards out there
searching for you.
Someone,
bring me wine.
I'll go out to take a look.
Lock the door.
Today, we must
drink to our hearts' content.
Where are you going?
Don't go.
Sir, where are you going?
I just came to apologize.
We agreed
to leave after a pot of wine.
My friend,
he's drunk.
Don't blame him.
It's fine, Sir.
It's not a problem.
There's a secret door, right?
Where does it lead?
You must be mistaken, Sir.
There's no such a door.
Here's the wine.
Sir, please keep drinking.
I think you've had too much to drink.
Your wine is not good enough.
I'll make you some hangover soup later.
[Jushui Entertainment House]
There's a fire.
Fire...
Huaiying...
Put out the fire.
Huaiying.
Huaiying...
Put out the fire.
[Jushui Entertainment House]