[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 31] [This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
Come, Huaiying.
Come.
Ying.
How is he?
Mr. Li, please
give me a basin of water
and a handkerchief.
I want to lower
the Magistrate's temperature.
Well,
I'll mix him
a stronger dose.
Thank you.
Zhou Li was indeed quite weird lately.
He told me
he had a Heavenly Eye.
He said he could see
unexpected calamities, wronged souls,
anxiety-ridden people,
and spirits behind people's backs.
Can you believe what he said?
Come.
You go over there.
Search that place.
Eaglewood from Yunshui Lodge.
Please give this
to Mr. Cui.
This way, please.
Almost there.
The roads in the library are intricate.
Don't walk around on your own.
It is snowing more and more heavily.
Where can he hide?
Did he find something?
I think so.
Otherwise, how could...?
Who?
Who is there?
Did you see someone?
Yes. Chase after him!
Stop.
Go over there to take a look.
Okay.
Come on, come here.
There is no one over there.
No.
There is no one here, either.
I did saw a pair of eyes.
Go over there to search.
Where is he?
The roads in the library are intricate.
Don't walk around on your own.
Miss Cao,
I've told you
you can't walk around casually.
What's this place?
What is this place for?
As you can see,
this is an altar.
I'm here to redeem Zhou Li's soul.
Isn't this place a library?
How can there be such a place in it?
We don't worship gods or Buddhas here.
Instead, we pay homage to the dead.
The dead in Zhao Yun Temple.
The dead?
Yes.
Two hundred years ago,
this place was a Taoist temple.
Its name was also Zhao Yun.
It was a tumultuous period at that time.
Besides Taoists,
there were a lot of commoners
and scholars here.
One night,
a group of roving bandits
attacked the temple.
In order to get a treasure
that might not exist,
they killed all the Taoists,
commoners,
and scholars here.
That was really a bloody massacre.
Later on,
this place became
a dilapidated and haunted abode.
It had been deserted for a hundred years.
Later,
about 40 years ago,
the world became peaceful.
Our teacher came here by chance.
He renovated this place
and kept the bones
of the dead
in this altar
that had already existed.
[Mr. Zhou Li's Memorial Tablet]
Our teacher also asked us
to bring some offerings here
when there was a climate change
or when it was a festival.
Although we don't perform
a religious rite,
we believe
these offerings
can soothe the souls of the dead.
I see.
Miss Cao,
why are you here?
Does Mr. Cui
know
the death of Zhou Li?
When our teacher's retreat
is over,
I'll report to him about it.
I didn't mean to offend this place.
I saw
the students in the library
were all very busy.
I didn't know what had happened.
So I came out to take a look.
However, I got lost.
They were looking for
the child in white
the Magistrate mentioned.
Have they found him?
Following the direction
the Magistrate told us,
they searched the entire yard.
But they didn't find the child.
Well,
the Magistrate was hurt
by poisonous thorns.
Was it possible
that he was hallucinating?
I don't think
the Magistrate was hallucinating.
Instead, he saw a ghost.
Or the Magistrate
saw something
that did not exist
because of the foul aura of the dead.
Do you know there will be
a solar eclipse this month?
On such dismal days,
the dead here
are always restless.
I don't believe in such things.
At first, I didn't believe
in these things, either.
But our teacher believes in them.
He showed me
that our understanding of the world
may be only
one ten-thousandth
of the truth of the world.
One day, there will be an explanation
for those unknown things
like ghosts, gods, and Buddhas.
Now we can only
understand it simply as a magnetic field.
As the weather has changed,
Yin Qi in this place is very heavy.
Plus the Magistrate
was very weak.
So his magnetic field might
have been disturbed,
causing the instability of his mind.
The old wishes
in his heart
were projected
into the air.
We can also call them
obsessions.
An obsession
may concern
something happened long ago
or
a deceased person.
Miss Cao.
Do you also have obsessions
in your heart like the Magistrate?
The Yin Qi here is too heavy.
We'd better leave quickly.
Hurry up.
Stop.
Stop!
Put it down.
What happened?
Magistrate,
last night,
Zhou Li
jumped down from the rooftop and died.
Everybody witnessed it.
Miss Cao was also here.
Why did he jump down from the rooftop?
Last night,
we gave Miss Cao an account.
Huaiying,
you are awake.
Mr. Li.
How are you now?
I'm feeling better.
Great.
It seems that the prescription
is working.
What happened in the library?
Why did he
jump down from the rooftop?
Miss Cao already
knows something about it.
It's too cold outside.
Let's go back to the room and talk.
Magistrate, please.
Let's go.
Don't catch a cold.
Please.
I saw him writing it on his palm
before he jumped down.
[Ghost]
Maybe he wanted to tell you something.
I don't know.
It seemed he wanted to say something,
but he didn't say anything.
Before he jumped down, he looked back.
His eyes were filled with horror
as if he had seen a ghost.
Are you sure those footprints
led from this room to the yard last night?
That's right.
Each footprint was about this big.
Each one was very deep.
The man seemed to be very heavy.
The incense that was given to Mr. Cui
appeared at the door
for no apparent reason.
And what I saw in the underground hall.
We don't worship gods or Buddhas here.
Instead, we pay homage to the dead
in Zhao Yun Temple.
Everything was so weird.
When it stops snowing,
let's leave here quickly.
When will the snow stop?
We can't leave now.
Yeah.
What I want to say is
that there are too many mysteries
we haven't solved.
Possessed by the dead,
Zhou Li jumped down and died.
They pay homage to the dead
200 years ago in the underground hall.
The package of incense
was back here for no apparent reason.
I saw
that child in white again.
Where did you see him?
Do you know there will be
a solar eclipse this month?
On such dismal days,
the dead here
are always restless.
As the weather has changed,
Yin Qi in this place is very heavy.
Plus the Magistrate is weak.
So his magnetic field might
have been disturbed,
causing the instability of his mind.
Ever since I came here,
I've been having a strange feeling.
It seems a pair of eyes are watching me.
The solar eclipse is coming.
Let's not offend the dead.
No, that's not the dead.
I know what I saw.
Maybe
it was really because you were too weak.
Or maybe you just saw
your own obsession.
The dead won't disturb the living.
Maybe you haven't forgotten him.
But I won't let him
disturb me.
Miss Cao, here is the medicine.
Mr. Li.
Miss Cao,
this is the Magistrate's medicine.
After he takes it today,
he should
get better tomorrow.
Thank you.
We also want
to leave the library as soon as possible.
Okay.
Well,
when it stops snowing,
I'll ask someone to send you
down the mountain at once.
Thank you.
Give it to the Magistrate now.
Goodbye.
The medicine Mr. Li has sent here.
Take it when it's hot.
When it stops snowing,
you can go back first.
It is written
in "Records of the Supernatural"
that there is a rare spring
south of Lanfang County.
Scoop a goblet of spring water
and the heart will be reborn.
One can realize
one's wish.
Scoop a goblet of spring water
and there is nothing to worry about?
When you come back,
if you still keep calling me Miss Cao,
I won't respond.
Our library does not teach children.
A year ago, when our teacher
started to retreat,
he left only his close disciples
in the library.
Moreover,
they are all adults.
He was acting weird lately.
He always said
he was agitated.
He also said someone was watching him.
[Nightmare, Soul, Spirit]
[Ghost]
Are you sure those footprints
led from this room to the yard last night?
Each footprint was about this big.
Each one was very deep.
The man seemed to be very heavy.
Before he jumped down, he looked back.
His eyes were filled with horror
as if he had seen a ghost.
This way, please.
Mr. Cui.
In order to write smoothly
and understand the historical facts,
every time after reading
historical materials,
our teacher will be in retreat.
Not to disturb him during his retreat.
Otherwise, his previous efforts
would be wasted.
So he should be burning the sandalwood
to calm his mind.
Hurry up.
If we sent it too late,
we will get scolded again.
Okay.
Hurry up.
It's snowing so heavily.
Don't know when it will stop.
Who knows?
Possessed by the dead,
Zhou Li jumped down and died.
I saw
that child in white again.
The package of incense
was back here for no apparent reason.
They pay homage to the dead
200 years ago in the underground hall.
There are too many mysteries
we haven't solved.
[Loving Father Pei Shinian's Tomb]
The dead won't disturb the living.
I won't let him
disturb me.
Who?
Stop.
Kid.
Where is my sword?
It's time to give it back to me.
The sword is with me.
He has given it back to me.
My brother.
Maybe
it was really because you were too weak.
Or maybe you just saw
your own obsession.
Who?
Lighter.
Huaiying.
Slowly.
Miss Cao.
What happened?
The Magistrate passed out
in the underground hall.
I guess
after he heard you describe that place,
he wanted to explore it himself.
But with his health condition,
it's too dangerous for him to go there.
You can leave.
Yes.
But his fever has gone down.
Why
is he still in a coma?
Did he take the medicine
I decocted for him?
I accidentally knocked it over.
It doesn't matter.
I'll prepare
another dose for him.
Thank you.
Don't go.
The wooden sword.
Huaiying,
what did you see?
The wooden sword.
[Wei]