[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 14]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
You slept so soundly.
Take this
to your new friend.
Ask him
whether there is news
about these child soldiers
in the streets.
Okay. Leave it to me.
Lead the way.
[Phoenix Inn]
Please.
You've finally arrived.
The Esteemed Head has been
talking about you.
Come.
- Big.
- Small.
Small.
Drink...
Hey?
You are here.
I thought you had forgotten about me!
What do you think?
Someone, bring a bowl.
Wait.
There's serious business.
These children in the pictures
are soldiers in the military camp
in the north of the city.
Three nights ago,
they were supposed to patrol the area
around the military camp.
But they left without permission.
No one knew where they had gone.
How do you want me to help you?
I want to know
where they went that night.
You
are overestimating my abilities.
I only know
in Penglai,
if even you can't find the information,
no one can.
Right?
Well,
you wait in the Magistrate's Office.
Tomorrow, I will send someone
to your place before sunset.
If you see no one,
you don't need to wait any longer.
Okay. I'll wait for you.
Huaiying,
the official clerk came back
early this morning.
About the procurement documents
in the military camp,
I've investigated them as you told me.
Most procurement applications
have been approved.
[Procurement Application]
After we arrived,
the military camp
was fairly well-supplied.
But it is clearly
a dilapidated military camp.
If I hadn't seen it with my own eyes,
I wouldn't dare to believe it.
But it is right in Penglai.
The garrison in Penglai
has always had great problems.
Corruption
is now a tumor for Tang.
I think
with these procurement approvals alone,
you can make a punitive expedition
against them.
I have to wait some time.
I need to confirm another thing.
[Mingyue House]
Miss Cao,
I have a busy day today.
After I come back from the watchtower,
I will come to you immediately.
I have something important to tell you.
Wait for me.
You wait for me here.
Ying'er.
Go away!
Rain Master, heed my command!
I know where he is.
I can take you to see him.
Yes.
I do want to see him.
I've been looking for him.
Tell me.
What did you see that night?
I know
he will come and take me with him.
The Rain Master
won't die.
He will come back to life.
Ying'er!
His fatal wound was in the back.
The stab in the chest
was completely different
from the one in the back
in terms of force and angle.
Zhong Fang
never let Ying'er see his real face.
That night,
Zhong Fang's corpse appeared
in the watchtower.
He was not wearing a mask.
It was the first time
Ying'er had seen Zhong Fang's face.
She found
the Rain Master she had been with
was just an ordinary man.
She was in a rage.
She made another stab in his body.
Actually, that knife
was left by the real murderer.
Magistrate Di.
Please save my fellows.
Officer Li wants them dead.
Tell your fellows
to go to see Mr. Hong
in the Magistrate's Office
and tell him to come
to take care of the body.
Go quickly.
Yes.
[Penglai County Magistrate's Office]
Mr. Hong.
Wait a minute.
Miss Cao, how come you are here?
Mr. Hong,
where is Magistrate Di?
Has he come back?
He is still out on a case.
As long as he is fine.
I'll take my leave.
Miss Cao,
Magistrate
will leave Penglai very soon
and go to work in Lanfang County.
He wants to invite you to go with him.
Nobody knows
when he will invite you himself.
So I spoke out of turn.
I have an important case to handle.
I'm leaving.
Miss Cao, take care.
Go.
Why did you do this?
They deserted their posts
and secretly went out of the camp.
This is the punishment they deserve.
I've come here today
to ask you clearly
where they were that night
and why their knives
appeared in the watchtower.
You killed them tonight.
What are you trying to hide?
You mean I was shielding them
from their crimes?
Why did you kill them then?
Answer me!
The dignity of the army is above all.
They made mistakes
and should be punished.
As for how heavy the punishment
should be,
this is my military camp.
I have the final say.
Besides, Magistrate Di,
isn't this the outcome you want?
You suspect them of wrongdoing,
so you came to catch them.
Name them murderers
or even worse
and then sentence them to death.
I solve cases based on evidence.
As long as they didn't do it,
they wouldn't die.
Look at him.
I brought him back from Fang Town.
And him, from Red Valley.
Him, from Liulin.
Him, Qi County.
They had no names.
They were all beggars.
I gave them names.
I taught them the rules.
Their bad habits disappeared
little by little
under my whip.
I've managed to turn them
from scavengers
into dignified soldiers.
Those charges
would've destroyed
their hard-earned
self-esteem.
This matter has not been cleared up yet.
I'd rather they are bodies with dignity.
Magistrate,
leave here
with your men.
This is my military camp.
I have the final say.
It's not a big deal.
Don't be anxious.
I'll get someone to restring it.
No need.
Shall I
invite Magistrate Di to come?
No need.
I don't quite understand.
You are clearly
worried about him.
You know his heart from someone else.
Why are you unwilling to see him?
Recklessly following someone
to a strange place
and unfamiliar surroundings
does not necessarily
lead to a good ending.
That's not necessarily true.
Life is
unpredictable.
You may encounter
anything.
Maybe every disaster
you've ever experienced
can teach you something.
You are either sad
or joyful.
A distant place
actually has nothing.
may not necessarily have nothing.
Magistrate
will leave Penglai very soon
and go to work in Lanfang County.
He wants to invite you to go with him.
Nobody knows
when he will invite you himself.
Do you know it will take a tree
at least three to four years
to bear fruits?
But it will bear fruits in the end, right?
I'm here.
I didn't break my word.
I'm back.
When I was little, I caught a cricket.
It was during the Dragon Boat Festival.
It was right in the grass
in the backyard of my house.
The little creature
kept chirping.
It seemed
it had endless energy.
It was very pleasant to hear.
It seemed the chirping
would never stop.
But just after the seventh month
of the year,
it died.
I cried very hard.
Later on, every year,
I would catch a cricket.
It was as if
they made a deal.
As soon as summer was over,
all of them were dead.
I can't remember
what year
I haven't cried since.
Later on,
no matter what kind of creature died,
I never shed
a single drop of tear.
I can't save anyone!
I can't save anyone.
Magistrate, you are awake.
Miss Cao prepared tea for you
as well as water from the well.
She...
She is gone.
She asked me to take good care of you.
She asked me to tell you
to go back after having tea.
She will come back quite late.
[Penglai County Magistrate's Office]
Magistrate,
The Esteemed Head has found out
where the four soldiers went
that night.
How could it be this tavern?
This is the tavern
where some people caused
a disturbance that night.
This...
Can you still recognize us?
Gentlemen, it was a misunderstanding
last time.
The Esteemed Head
has given me instructions.
He asked me to serve you well.
If you have any questions,
feel free to ask.
Everyone, please.
Please.
Please, be careful.
Magistrate,
it was these brats
who nearly smashed my tavern.
When did they come?
At dusk.
Did they take knives with them?
No.
If they had brought knives,
I would definitely remember it clearly.
What else
has left you a deep impression?
At dusk,
besides those brats,
in the private room on the second floor,
there were another two guests drinking.
I know one of them.
Mr. Xie from the salt shop.
The other one
was unfamiliar.
He has a mustache.
Previously...
Talk about these children.
Those brats were drunk.
They started to create
a disturbance here.
First, they overturned the table.
Then they caught me
and were about to beat me
without a reason.
At this time,
Mr. Xie and the man with a mustache
finished drinking on the second floor.
They were walking downstairs.
They directly encountered those brats.
When those brats
saw the man with a mustache,
they looked as if they saw a ghost.
In the end, they were taken away
directly by the man with a mustache.
Did the man with a mustache
behave like a soldier?
If you say so,
he indeed looked like a soldier.
[Xie's Salt Shop]
It turns out that those child soldiers
went out to drink secretly.
They bumped into Officer Li.
That's not right.
When we were in the military camp,
Officer Li said he had been
interrogating those child soldiers
about their whereabouts.
And nothing
came out of the interrogation.
But according to the owner
of the tavern,
it was he who had caught them back.
Officer Li was lying.
Why did he lie about this?
Why didn't he tell us directly?
Because he can't let others know
whom he met
or what they talked about that night.
Magistrate.
Magistrate, they came out.
No wonder the military camp
is so dilapidated.
It turns out the things are hidden here.
They are truly insatiable.
Stop.
Di Renjie, Magistrate of Penglai.
I have important issues
to announce in the military camp.
Let us go in.
You can go in.
Magistrate Di,
you've come again.
Magistrate has some announcements to make.
You're just in time.
If you didn't come,
I would go to see you.
Deserter Guo Kui,
disguised as Qiao Tai,
violated the law and discipline.
The court has ordered
that he should be dealt with
under military law promptly.
Di Renjie, the Magistrate,
you shelter the deserter.
According to the law of Tang,
you'll be escorted to the state government
for accountability.
Ma Rong.
Let go of me!
Magistrate.
Don't move.
Tai.
Let go of me!
Creating a disturbance
in the military camp.
Take her to the dungeon!
Yes.
Go!
Let go of me!
Tai!
Magistrate!
Go!
If you hadn't revealed yourself
during the registration,
I couldn't have remembered
I saw you at Assault-resisting Garrison
in Youzhou, Hebei Circuit.
[Qiao Tai]
As a deserter,
you dared
to frequent the military camp
swaggeringly?
You are so bold.
Do you remember Vice Commandant Luan?
He was my friend.
Magistrate,
I'll have a good talk with you later.
Take Magistrate Di to have a rest.
Tai.
Tai...
Is he dead?
Did you kill him?
Tai!
Is he dead?
Tai,
are you dead?
Tai!
Don't touch me.
Tai?
It hurts.
You scared me to death.
Tai.
I got Magistrate into trouble.
He is not afraid of trouble.
All these years,
I had few chances to write my name.
I came to this military camp
and saw these soldiers.
How could I unconsciously...?
I was...
What are you capable of?
If you were really capable,
how could you have been beaten so badly?
Stop talking.
Let me speak.
Tell my words to Magistrate.
You go out and tell him yourself.
It's too late.
If they convict me of desertion,
I still think it's worth it.
My true name
is Guo Kui.
I was a decurion
under General Meng
in Assault-resisting Garrison
in Youzhou, Hebei Circuit.
At that time,
the war between the Tang
and the vassals were raging.
Everyone knew
that going to the battlefield
meant death.
It was just a matter of time.
One day, after training,
I heard a woman's laughter.
The laughter suddenly gave me
something to look forward to
while I was waiting to die.
She smiled at me.
She was our Vice Commandant's concubine.
She said she liked me.
She asked me to take her away.
Then I became a deserter.
What happened after that?
On the third day we were away
from the camp, she couldn't bear it.
Quick.
- What's wrong?
- I'm...
I'm done.
It's been three days.
I can't stand
this constant worrying and fear anymore.
I couldn't watch her suffer.
So I sent her back.
You say it's worth it?
She was
in a relationship with me.
Go to hell.
It hurts.
Tell Magistrate
he was the best thing
that ever happened to me.
Kill him!
Kill the deserter!
Deserter!
Let me go out!
Kill him!
Deserter!
Qiao Tai!
Kill him!
Kill the deserter!
Deserter!
Any last words from the sinner?
See?
This is what happens to deserters.
Got cold feet and escaped.
The one should be sentenced to death.
Now let's
send him to hell.
Kill him!
Deserter!
Because he can't let others know
whom he met
or what they talked about
that night.
No. 301A
Procurement Application.
600 jin of mutton.
No. 302A
Procurement Application.
300 jin of cast iron
for casting armor and shields.
No. 303A
Procurement Application.
1,000 ropes
used for...
Why are you looking at me?
...used for climbing.
He is lying.
He is as much a worm
as any official sent before.
He just wants to save his subordinate.
Guards,
go kill him!
Wait a minute.
Let him finish.
Want to rebel?
But where are these materials?
At this moment,
they are
in the warehouse of Xie's Salt Shop
in the east of the city.
If such a worm is not removed,
Tang soldiers will lose their dignity.
Nonsense!
It's all lies from these stupid officials.
Go kill him quickly!
Put away the saber.
- Go kill him!
- Put away!
Who is it?
Listen, everyone.
Officer Li colluded
with the salt merchant,
took bribes and perverted the law,
and lined his own pockets.
He embezzled most of the supplies.
Mr. Xie,
tell everyone
where the supplies are.
Indeed.
Indeed, they are in my place.
Nonsense!
Totally nonsense!
Our country's security
is in our hands,
and yet we serve it on an empty stomach.
The soldiers died
because they were unarmed.
What are you doing?
This is rebellion!
Hand them over!
Beat him to death!
Tai.
Tai, wake up. Don't scare me.
It's okay.
Given his size,
two days of sleep will be enough.
Thank you, Magistrate Di.
With these materials,
you can update your weapons and armor.
Not just the materials.
You helped us get our dignity back.
There is one more thing.
Those child soldiers
were wronged and driven to death.
They were 14 years old or so.
Harsh military discipline
stifled their instincts,
achieving the opposite effect.
They got caught up in a storm
and died for nothing.
It's a pity.
It's lamentable.
Leaving.
[Penglai County Magistrate's Office]
Mr. Hong,
yesterday I was sorting
through the fellows' belongings.
I discovered this.
I was in a hurry to bring it here.
[Pawn Ticket]
I don't know if it is useful to you.
Pawn ticket?
This is the client's stub.
They must have recently pawned something
at Zhong's Pawn Shop.
Thank you.
Magistrate,
I've been hiding something from you.
I knew you as Qiao Tai
from way back.
You are my assistant.
Don't mention
the past again.
Magistrate, Mr. Hong wants to see you.
Don't mention it.
Tai, don't worry.
I didn't tell Magistrate
about your embarrassing things.
I told him
you went into battle
and killed the enemies bravely.
However,
you met a treacherous person
and were harmed by him.
But
you still put up a strong fight.
Did Magistrate believe it?
Ma Rong.
[Pawn Ticket]
Fortunately, I arrived in time.
Otherwise,
it would be too late.
That's right.
My heart was in my throat at that time.
Fortunately, Magistrate bought us time.
There are so many documents.
How did you recite them all?
I can't recite them all.
So you...
So I made it up.
Speaking of solving the case,
now Ying'er and the eighth camp
are cleared now.
This case
might have to return
to the starting point
and be re-investigated.
Perhaps
the child soldiers from the eighth camp
showed me a new direction.
I won't believe you from now on.
There's not a word of truth
in your mouth.
Miss Cao.
Why are you so flustered?
What happened?
I went past the market just now.
I heard the discussions
among the merchants.
They said
Magistrate Di encountered a big trouble
in the military camp.
We are not sure about his safety now.
They also saw Mr. Hong
escorting the owner of Xie's Salt Shop
to the military camp aggressively.
It is said he was going
to save Magistrate Di.
Okay.
I got it.
According to your instructions,
I told Miss Cao about this.
But
she didn't seem to be responding.
Really?
She wasn't like this just now.
One's feelings
can deceive others
but not oneself.
Xiang,
write up some new recruits
on the music house's behalf
and put them up.
We need to recruit new people.
[Penglai County Magistrate's Office]
How is it?
My skills haven't
deteriorated too much, have they?
Not at all.
I can't remember
the last time
I heard you play.
You are about to leave.
My Mingyue House will lose
the leading musician.
I can't find a better one
in a short time.
So I have to practice myself.
Did I say I would leave?
Then write me a guarantee.
Promise me that you won't leave.
Well...
Look,
you just won't admit your feelings.
You can't hide
your feelings for a man.
As for your concerns,
they are not actually concerns.
You know it again?
I've known it long ago.
Don't worry
about what you can't keep.
Can't rely on others.
I have to
rely on myself.
I might as well go
and practice my instrument.