[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 8]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
Di Renjie,
there's someone out there looking for you.
A woman.
- Magistrate.
[Magistral Office of Penglai County]
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Magistrate.
That day, before I could finish the song,
you fell asleep.
I'm presenting you with the collection
of Mr. Teng's poems.
Later,
I'll sing them for you one by one.
Sing what?
What "later"?
When did you two meet?
Thank you very much.
Di Renjie,
who is she?
I've never heard you mention her.
Prepare the horse.
Yes.
To invite Mr. Teng.
Don't go.
I go.
Mr. Teng,
do you think
that Mrs. Teng looks
a little strange?
The hair on her forehead
was cut short.
What...
Who did this?
It's not me.
I know.
Magistrate.
[Magistral Office of Penglai County]
Mr. Teng.
Tomorrow in the morning,
I'll visit you and see you off.
Ma Rong.
Don't let anything go wrong.
What did Huaiying say to you?
Huaiying.
- I'm your brother.
- Huaiying.
Hide from me?
What are you hiding from me?
[Teng's Residence]
Huaiying.
Huaiying,
if you don't show up,
you'll never see me again.
I won't.
Today,
you'll definitely see me.
How about the screen?
Will you take it with you?
It's ominous.
Why do I take it with me?
Before I leave,
I'll just burn it in a fire.
That screen
is a reenactment of your love
with Mrs. Yinlian.
If you burn it,
won't you also burn your love
with Mrs. Yinlian?
Your words are a bit harsh.
The love between me and my late wife
is so true.
It can't be burned away by a fire.
Take it easy.
Let me restore the screen
to its original picture
as a parting gift
to you, Mr. Teng.
What's this?
The lacquer has fallen off.
Can it be scratched off?
There's another layer inside.
The picture of murdering the wife
was painted with special pigment.
When it's exposed to hot water,
it will show up.
I scraped off the special pigment
so the original picture
was revealed.
That day,
you threw a bowl of hot medicine on it
and created
a shocking picture
of murdering the wife.
That day, I had an attack of madness.
I lost my mind and don't remember.
Did you really
have an attack of madness?
What else?
Are you saying
I deliberately threw the medicine
on the screen?
That's what I meant.
You first made the screen change
and spread the rumor
about the evil spirits.
Then,
you let the madness take over,
lost your mind,
and killed Yinlian.
Mr. Teng,
this is your plan.
To kill Mrs. Yinlian
and get what you desire.
If you kill someone due to madness,
the Tang Code,
people's hearts,
and public sentiment
will all
be on your side.
Yinlian was killed by Li Han.
That's your verdict, Magistrate.
I said
the truth would come out
when we find Li Han,
but I didn't ask you to silence him.
If it's true that Li Han
killed her for revenge,
why did he go through all the trouble
to let the screen change?
Why did I need to kill Yinlian?
I asked you
who made this screen.
Just an unknown artist.
Why ask again?
It's not because the painter is unknown,
but you don't want to tell me
the painter's name, right?
Is that Mrs. Yinlian
in the picture?
Xu Kai.
Why are you here?
Come...
It's a little messy here.
It's fine.
Pretty good.
Are you done with the screen?
Almost done.
This is...
a success in the imperial examination.
What is portrayed
is like a story.
This is
our story.
Does this screen
have a name?
Let's call it
the Four-panel Screen.
The woman in the lacquer screen
is also her.
However, the man
is not you
but the painter Xu Kai.
So you're saying
the one who should've been
with her for years
is this Xu Kai.
Where is he?
You killed him.
Seven stabs.
Mrs. Yinlian
was also
stabbed seven times.
A coincidence?
I don't think so.
But I didn't figure it out
until I found seven scratches
on the wall outside the private room
of the brothel.
You stalked Mrs. Yinlian's
secret rendezvous with Xu Kai.
Seven times in total.
One time,
one stab.
Take a good look at my nails.
What scratches are there?
Nothing!
The nails have grown back.
But that day,
when I examined your pulse,
I did see the wear and tear of your nails.
Unfortunately, at that time,
I didn't doubt what you were saying.
Shut up!
Don't say anything without evidence.
Di Renjie,
it doesn't matter if you accuse me.
If you accuse Yinlian
of adultery,
I won't spare you.
I've never been able to figure this out.
I didn't understand
how a man could endure such humiliation
until I found your poem
in Mrs. Yinlian's room.
The old mountains stand,
yet my bonds no longer cling.
Embarking on a journey to Chang'an
to enjoy the late spring.
A tree draped in pear blossoms,
a stream beneath moonlight.
I wonder who owns this sight tonight.
You said you were revising
Mrs. Yinlian's poem for her.
The old mountains exist,
yet my bonds no longer cling.
Embarking on a journey to Chang'an
to see the late spring.
You put your mark
on Mrs. Yinlian's poem and tried
to take it as your own.
But unfortunately,
after all your efforts,
it's not
as good as the original.
Di Renjie,
you're just a poor scholar
with a classicist degree.
You have no right to judge my poetry.
I indeed have no talent for poetry,
but I'm not one
who fish for fame either.
Someone told me
that love and romance
are simple.
It's strong while being together.
It's intense while missing.
Separation creates sorrow.
Infatuation creates suspicion.
Passionate incurs jealousy and hatred.
These feelings
are depicted to the fullest
in your poetry.
Your poetry is soft and sentimental,
more vivid
than a woman's thoughts.
Now that I think about it,
it's not that you're more delicate
than women,
but these poems
were written by a woman.
If not,
why did you know
that Mrs. Yinlian was having an affair
with her old lover
but still put up with it?
It's just because you need
Mrs. Yinlian's poems more
than anyone else.
Xu Kai.
Let's call it
the Four-panel Screen.
What is portrayed
is like a story.
This is our story.
Di Renjie,
get out of here.
I remember you said
you never used
that horsewhip
since your army days.
This horsewhip
is what I used back then.
Ever since I left office,
I've kept it with me.
It commemorates
my years of military service.
What about the fresh blood
on the end of the whip?
Dare to show your backside
for everyone to see?
Fingernails can grow,
but whip marks
can't disappear once left.
You whipped yourself
with the horsewhip every day,
trying to subdue your inner demons.
But in the end,
you couldn't bear it anymore.
You first killed Xu Kai.
Then,
you pretended to be mad
and killed Yinlian.
You said I was faking my madness?
In your study,
we found Bimanzi.
Bimanzi,
a small amount of it
can make one show the symptoms of madness.
To kill Yinlian,
you took it for more than ten days,
which confirmed your madness.
If I really wanted to kill my wife,
why did I do that?
In the beginning,
you didn't want to get blood
on your hands,
so you bribed the director
to release Li Han.
[Li Han]
Your words are getting
even more ridiculous.
I'm Teng Kan.
Everyone knows me in Penglai.
If I go to the quarry for one's release,
the director will surely recognize me.
Call the director here.
I'll confront him.
When did I mention the quarry?
That's right.
He didn't say it.
How do you know that Li Han
was serving in the quarry?
It's not hard to deduce.
Call the director here.
I'll confront him face-to-face.
No need for a confrontation.
The one who went to the quarry
was indeed not you
but
Ms. Lai Er,
Yinlian's sister.
Why did she do this?
You should ask her,
not me.
You know exactly why.
Mrs. Yinlian
always went out
in the name of visiting Ms. Lai Er.
The butler
can testify to this.
Had Mr.s Yinlian and Ms. Lai Er always
been seeing each other?
Not really.
I've heard they used to have a deep grudge
against each other.
It was only recently
that they began to see each other again.
If you knew they were at odds,
then
you'd realize Mrs. Yinlian
must've been lying.
You knew Ms. Lai Er loved Xu Kai deeply.
And after recovering from leprosy,
Xu Kai rekindled his relationship
with Yinlian.
You used her jealousy to get her
to pay for Li Han's release.
If it weren't for Li Han to thwart you,
you'd have succeeded.
He knew that after you killed Xu Kai,
- you'd kill your wife.
- Evil spirit...
Evil spirit...
So he could only sneak
into your residence repeatedly
to protect Yinlian.
You knew he didn't dare to report it,
so you took advantage of him
and successfully diverted my attention.
You're a heartless man,
so you wouldn't have thought
that Li Han was framed
and imprisoned due to Yinlian,
but he loved Yinlian
till his death.
This broken hair
is proof.
Such a person
can never want to kill someone.
What a story
of love and hate.
It's so touching.
Di Renjie,
you're saying with certainty.
So
you have evidence to convict me?
I have no evidence.
Li Han and Xu Kai
are both dead.
Just
the Bimanzi found in your residence
is not enough to convict you.
Magistrate Di,
my reputation in the realm of poetry
can't be shaken
by your ravings at all.
You've framed me like this.
Now,
you should consider the consequences.
I thought you once dominated
the realm of poetry
with your genuine talent.
How could you end up like this?
Three people have died because of you.
How can you be at peace?
What nonsense!
Someone!
Keep moving.
Lift!
How come it's turned into a stone?
Where are the manuscripts?
Where are my manuscripts?
It's here.
Where are the other manuscripts?
Where are my other manuscripts?
They're on the way to Chang'an.
I asked Ma Rong
to enter your residence
and replace all of them.
These manuscripts
are in Mrs. Yinlian's handwriting.
They're something
you haven't had a chance to copy yet.
You pretended to mourn her
and locked yourself in her room.
But actually,
you were searching for her last works.
I can't punish you for murder.
But you used Yinlian's poems
to win the first place in the capital.
You deceived the Emperor.
You still can't escape death
for this crime.
Mr. Teng,
I won't arrest you today.
You can go.
But remember,
after today,
all your fame
is a joke.
[Grave of Li Han. Grave of Mrs. Teng,
maiden name Yinlian. Grave of Xu Kai.]
[Grave of Yinlian]
I've been in charge of Penglai for a long
and have violated many codes and laws.
What is Di Renjie going to do with me?
He said
you've lost.
From now on, in Penglai County,
whatever is in your charge,
he'll take charge of it.
Whatever is not in your charge,
he'll also take charge of it.
[Mingyue House]
The rain has finally stopped.
Yes, it has.
It's made of red cedar wood.
When I was a kid in Chang'an,
a family
brought one red cedar tree
from the remote Jiannan Circuit
and planted it in their yard.
It was so tall and green
that you could see it from afar.
The heavens and the earth fall
into the dark night.
Dead and living dim and draw apart.
It's my first time.
If it's not good for you,
I'll change it.
It's very good.
No need to change it.
Magistrate, thank you.
Wang,
why did you drop anchor here?
It's too stormy.
This is nothing.
Back then,
I battled in Liaodong.
I've seen waves taller than a mountain.
Are you tricking me?
Don't worry.
I, Wang Lide, have been on this route
a dozen times.
Better safe than sorry.
Where are the others?
I told them to have a rest.
Okay, I'll go take a look.
[Wang Lide]
Brother.
Didn't I tell you not to come out?
I have a stomach ache.
Shh.
I told you this ship is dangerous.
The sailors hold swords.
They're all bandits.
I know that.
If they find out
I brought you on board secretly,
they'll kill you.
Wait a minute.
Use this.
I have diarrhea.
Hey.
Hey, wake up.
Wang Lide.
Gathered in delight,
a homecoming feast unfolds.
The joy is as great as
in the Song of the Great Wind.
[Ten days later.]
[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Golden Mystery Case]
[Penglai Harbor]
[Bai Kai]
Director Yi.
[Director Yi]
I forgot.
It's for Commissioner Liu.
Bai Kai,
your shipmaster, Mr. Gu,
has prepared a lot of goodies.
Commissioner Liu has come all the way
from the capital
to buy for His Majesty.
I heard
he's also trusted by the Empress.
We must take good care of him.
Right.
You're right.
But with me, you're usually
so stingy.
Just gave me the runaround
with some furs and Renshen.
[*Renshen: ginseng.]
Director Yi, you're so funny.
You're the director of maritime trade
who manages the harbor.
Which Mr. Gu's cargo ship dare not
to bring you gifts
while entering the harbor?
Besides,
I also heard
Commissioner Liu's intentions
for this trip are not good.
Only if we serve him well this time
can we make money later,
right?
That's true.
Huaiying.
Guanshi.
[Hou Yu, courtesy name Guan Shi]
Since you left the capital,
it's been over a year.
I still remember
seeing you off
outside the Beihuan Pavilion.
The fallen flowers outside the pavilion
were melancholy.
At that time, I wondered
when
and where
I'd meet you again.
Aren't I doing fine here
in this remote seaside city?
You've lost weight.
Why have you lost so much weight?
With the Empress in power,
many officials
are either demoted or deposed.
I was no exception.
Let's not talk about it.
When I heard one
from the Ministry of Justice
would accompany Commissioner Liu
to Penglai,
I was thinking
how nice it'd be you.
To my surprise...
It's me.
I was going
to meet you after the banquet
with Commissioner Liu.
Why
did I run into you here?
I'm here
to find a shipowner named Gu Mengbin.
For a small case,
I've been summoning him for three days,
but he's been evading me.
Gu Mengbin.
What a coincidence.
He's holding the banquet tonight.
Mr. Gu is here.
[Gu Mengbin]
Tai,
look over there.
The Gu family made a really big scene.
He's the biggest shipowner in Penglai.
The hundreds of ships
in and out of the harbor are all his.
His ships can sail to Japan
and Baekje.
You guys,
go in and clean up.
Hurry up.
Master.
Director Yi.
Such goodies.
Why are you taking them away?
Director Yi,
tonight, in front of Commissioner Liu,
don't mention gold,
Especially not the words "Baekje gold".
What are they moving into the tent?
I can't see it.
It must be some kind of treasure
[Penglai Harbor]
Quick...
Let's set the lanterns.
[Commissioner Liu]
I've been told
that you grew up by the sea
before you joined the palace
to serve His Majesty and Empress,
so I've taken the liberty
of setting this banquet here.
I hope you enjoy your drink.
Mr. Gu, I've heard
you're very thoughtful.
It seems that you've already
found out everything about me.
I wouldn't dare.
Commissioner,
I am in charge of goods
coming in from overseas
in the Commission of Maritime Trade.
I was wondering what you want
to purchase this time.
That depends on what Penglai has.
It's just a few meager items.
I'm afraid they won't meet the eyes
of His Majesty and the Empress.
Commissioner Liu,
please take a look.
I'm of little education.
I only like two things in life.
First,
enjoy songs.
Second,
gold.
Commissioner,
you're joking.
Penglai doesn't produce it.
However,
Mr. Gu
has prepared performers for you.
It's right outside.
Gu...
Mr. Gu
has also prepared you some little gifts.
I hope you'll accept them.
Wait.
Who is it?
You don't have eyes?
You don't know Magistrate Di?
I'm ignorant.
Magistrate, please forgive me.
Magistrate,
it was this agent named Bai Kai.
He's been trying
to stop me from finding Mr. Gu.
It must be a misunderstanding.
I wouldn't dare.
Stand still.
You stand up.
You. Stand up.
Ms. Cao.
Magistrate Di.
Commissioner Liu,
the magistrate of Penglai, Di Renjie,
is here to see you.
This is a reception for Commissioner Liu
by the director of maritime trade.
Why is he here?
I've heard that Di Renjie
and Deputy Secretary Hou are old friends.
Commissioner Liu,
I
do know Di Renjie from school.
I also heard
that even the Empress
appreciates him a lot.
Yes.
But in my opinion,
he's active by nature.
Back in the captain,
he hated paperwork.
So by order of the Empress,
He is applying his talents in Penglai.
Invite Magistrate Di to come in.
Yes.
Magistrate Di, please come in.
I am Di Renjie.
Greetings, Commissioner Liu,
Deputy Secretary Hou,
and Director Yi.
The director of maritime trade
is a fifth-ranked official,
higher than a seventh-ranked magistrate.
Have a seat.
I heard
Magistrate Di is active by nature.
You didn't come here
in the dark
to get a drink, right?
You came here from the capital.
I am sorry to have missed the welcome.
Don't say such polite things.
I'm of little education.
I guess Magistrate Di must
be here on official business.
Deputy Secretary Hou holds you
in high regard.
So I'm curious.
I've never seen
a magistrate judge a case.
If you're on official business,
do it here.
Let me take a look.
I'll do as I'm told.
Commissioner Liu,
let's enjoy songs first.
Performers come in.
Thank you, Ms. Cao.
The man in this painting is Wang Lide.
It's said
he's an agent working for Mr. Gu,
who is in charge
of the transshipment of overseas goods.
Magistrate Di,
I've told the man you sent.
This agent is not my man.
Ms. Cao,
play a song for Commissioner Liu.
This drum in your arms
looks very special.
I've never seen it before.
I'm Qiao Tai.
May I have your name?
[Yusu]
My name is Yusu.
Your accent...
I'm from Baekje.
Officer, mind your own business.
I'm talking to Ms. Yusu.
What's it to you?
Unfortunately,
all the performers here
are booked by us tonight.
It's not a big deal to be rich.
Get out.
It's not a big deal to a sidekick.
Wait for me.
A few days ago,
the magistral office received a report
that a store
was overdue for rent.
After investigation,
it's the man in the painting.
He's gone to sea a few months ago
and was scheduled to return last month,
but hasn't returned yet.
So
I sent someone to check with Mr. Gu.
Rent arrears
are just a small amount of money.
Why should Mr. Gu be disturbed?
That's very true, Commissioner.
It's just
that the cargo we found
is not a small deal.
It's the Modao.