[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 26]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
[Loong's Butchery]
It is Loong who killed that couple.
Look at these words on the tags.
What are these words?
They are even worse than my handwriting.
Worse than your handwriting.
Then, how could he teach that couple
to play Xiangqi?
[*Chinese chess]
The heart and the knife are here,
and they are physical evidence.
The physical evidence
may be put here
by someone intentionally.
Where are you?
It's the person who coerced him
into self-castration.
The person who coerced him
[Lanfang County Magistrate's Office]
From the butcher's appearance,
I feel he couldn't make the paper effigy.
No need to investigate further, Hong.
The paper effigy and Loong
have nothing to do with each other.
All over the paper effigy,
not a single speck of grease can be found.
Loong was a butcher
who had been selling pork.
He was unrelated to the paper effigy.
The murderer
behind the three cases
obviously wants me to notice him.
So, I think
the three seemingly unrelated cases
were committed by the same person.
You suspect
that Heiyan did these?
I don't know.
What I know is
I am deeply disappointed.
Disappointed in myself
and the people of Lanfang County.
We've spent several years
popularizing laws
in Lanfang County.
The aim
is to create a peaceful place
where all the people
can live in harmony
in the world of justice.
All because of a mere paper effigy,
chaos has ensued.
To protect themselves,
the residents keep silent
about what they know
and fail to report crimes they witness.
The funeral shop on the street
has been closed for two days.
They fear getting involved,
so they keep silent about what they know
and don't report crimes they witness.
In the grocery stores,
the sellers even fear selling kites.
What are we doing?
We spare no effort popularizing laws,
but is the current situation different
from the authoritarian rule in the past?
Investigate it.
Hong,
please investigate all the information
about Loong
before and after his death.
Okay.
Mister,
I heard that that couple's hearts
were gouged out.
Yeah.
There are fewer people on the streets.
Have you finished?
Shall I clean the dishes?
Okay.
I'm leaving.
Okay!
[Notice]
What's written on it?
What is the notice about?
Yeah.
What's written on it?
Requesting all local artisans
to assist in case solving
at the Magistrate's Office.
There's also a reward.
Artisans can assist in case-solving?
I've never heard about that.
What kind of Magistrate is he?
He relies on artisans to solve cases.
The workmanship!
Mr. Sun,
the workmanship
is truly ingenious.
Who has such techniques
in Lanfang County?
Sir,
may I have a word with you?
Everyone,
get your reward in the front hall.
Thank you, Magistrate Di.
Do you know
who made this paper effigy?
Magistrate,
I don't know
who made this thing.
I just feel the paper effigy is familiar.
But the paper effigy is not a portrait.
It couldn't be made to resemble someone.
It should be a coincidence.
Who does it resemble?
It looks like
the daughter of the shopkeeper
of Xiao's Dyeing House,
Chunyu.
Do you know
where she is now?
She has been missing for many years.
You were not in Lanfang County
at that time.
Thank you.
Get your reward in the front hall.
Thank you, Magistrate.
Chunyu.
Mr. Hong, all the documents are here.
Mr. Hong,
you just said
you wanted to find Loong's case file.
Please check if it's this person.
Exactly.
Chu Lei raided Xiao's Dyeing House
and abducted Shopkeeper Xiao's daughter,
Xiao Chunyu.
The witness
was Loong,
a butcher.
Is the Magistrate here?
No.
[Xiao's Dyeing House]
Miss,
we are about to close.
Mister,
where did you
get the paper effigy?
Did you buy it?
It was made by my daughter.
Your daughter?
Mister…
[Shopkeeper Xiao]
do you know this?
This is my daughter's room.
No one has lived here
for many years.
But
it's still exactly the same as before.
This pair of earrings
is very valuable.
I am old,
and I have only one daughter.
If I hadn't given the earrings to her,
who should I give them to?
When and where
did you last see the earrings?
It was a night when my daughter
came back home
to visit me before she passed away.
[Xiao Chunyu]
Passed away?
I remember
your daughter is missing.
It's said that she is missing.
We just haven't found her corpse.
In fact,
she was murdered by Chu Lei long ago.
During those years,
[Xiao's Dyeing House]
the business was doing well.
So, I wanted
to open another shop
to incorporate the sale
of ready-made clothes.
Chunyu came up with the idea
of making some paper effigies.
She said
that we could put those clothes
on the paper effigies.
So, the size
and style
would be clear to people at a glance.
In this way,
the business would be better.
She had been skillful
since she was little.
No one in the city
could make those paper effigies.
But before the business got better,
she was gone.
Shopkeeper Xiao,
please tell us more about what happened
to Chunyu back then.
[Loong's Butchery]
All of this
conforms to Loong's testimony.
Even now,
I can still remember it very clearly.
If Chu Lei
knew Loong could see it clearly,
why did he
choose to commit the crime at that time?
Such a ruthless criminal
wouldn't care about it at all.
[Chu Lei]
Did you witness
all these with your own eyes?
No.
Then how would you know so clearly?
After my daughter was abducted,
the room was in a mess.
It was the magistrate at that time
who made this inference.
Where were you
when the crime occurred?
I was in the house next door.
How come you didn't hear the commotion
in your daughter's room?
I was in a very deep sleep.
From the case file,
Chu Lei was arrested
based on Loong's testimony,
right?
Yes.
Chu Lei
committed the crime late at night,
yet Loong recognized him immediately.
They must have known
each other before.
Chu Lei had been coveting
my daughter for a long time.
Before he enlisted,
he often came to harass her.
Loong lives across from our house,
[Loong's Butchery]
so he surely had met Chu Lei.
Chu Lei
used to be in the military?
Yeah.
What did he do for a living
before getting enlisted?
He was just a useless poor scholar.
Why would a scholar
suddenly join the military?
I had told him
if he could make something of himself,
I would consider
marrying my daughter to him.
Let go of my daughter!
Get lost!
If you don't have any accomplishments,
you'll never see my daughter again.
Leave!
Chunyu...
Just leave!
Hurry up!
Wait for me.
So, he joined the military
and declared
that he would return to marry her
after achieving success.
But as soon as he left,
you married your daughter
to someone else?
I can't marry my daughter to him
and condemn her to a life of poverty.
But what I heard is
Chu Lei died in prison
soon after being arrested.
He never
admitted to killing Chunyu,
even until his death.
I didn't kill Chunyu!
I was set up!
No murderer
would admit their guilt easily.
Indeed.
That makes sense.
Chunyu's body
is still missing now,
and Chu Lei had died for years.
A life for a life.
I'll regard it
as water under the bridge.
Do you know Mr. Chen the Sixth
and his wife?
Who?
The newlywed farmers,
Mr. Chen
and his wife.
I run a dyeing house.
I don't know farmers.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Magistrate,
I think there are many suspicious points
in Chunyu's case.
Of course.
Currently, only Chunyu
can link all the cases together.
Loong
was a witness in Chunyu's case.
The earrings
worn by the farmer's wife
belonged to Chunyu.
The paper effigy could be made
by Chunyu.
As for the skull...
You think it's Chunyu's skull?
If so,
the murderer
came for revenge for the old case.
Then it all makes sense.
Where was Chu Lei buried
after his death?
The mass grave in the west of the city.
Stop looking for it.
Even if we find his tombstone,
we wouldn't know
if the person buried there
is Chu Lei or not.
It's been 10 years.
I should have thought of it.
Who arranged his burial
when he died?
The file recorded a person named
Lin Fan.
Why didn't you tell us earlier?
We should have gone to Lin Fan directly.
What's the point of coming to this place?
Whammy!
You didn't ask.
Let's go. Stop playing with dead bones.
Digging out the heart and lungs.
Castration.
These must have been done
by evil spirits.
Exactly. So poor of the victims.
It was said
that the victims did it themselves.
Loong castrated himself
with his
own hands.
He harassed those girls.
He asked for it.
Have you heard about that couple?
They killed each other,
digging out each other's hearts.
How miserable!
Think carefully
about the mistakes we made
and just pray.
We should
do more good deeds.
Miss Cao,
is Magistrate Di stressed out lately?
Why?
I've heard
about the cases lately.
Everyone is jittery.
Miss Cao,
you cherish the instrument.
But
the damage
must have been caused by a fall.
I guess
Magistrate Di accidentally
let this musical instrument fall.
Miss Cao,
that's a mason I hired.
I'm planning
to erect a new tombstone
for my deceased father.
Miss Cao.
Darling,
why aren't you staying in the backyard?
What are you doing here?
He has finished his work.
He heard Miss Cao had arrived,
so he came to pay his respects.
I appreciate your politeness.
Say something.
Feel free to speak.
Let me help him.
The thing is,
he heard the Magistrate
has closed Loong's Butchery.
He had ordered sausages from there
but hadn't picked them up.
Although Loong is dead,
his death should have nothing to do
with those sausages.
He usually enjoys a drink with sausages,
and the sausages cost him a lot.
He cherishes his hard-earned money.
So, he wants to ask you a favor,
which is to speak to Magistrate Di
and give him the sausages.
I heard there were wooden signs
with names and addresses written
on them.
May I have your name?
I'll tell the Magistrate once I return.
[Lin Fan]
Lin Fan.
My name is Lin Fan.
Thank you, Miss Cao.
I'll take my leave first.
Father.
Father,
help me save it.
[Young Di Renjie]
Father.
Father,
help me save it.
Father...
You've read the letter.
Please consider it.
Don't tell me such things.
Get out of here!
Get out!
I'll come back again.
Hong,
who is that man?
Someone your father doesn't like.
Father,
I just saved a bird,
but it seems to be injured.
Here,
let me check on it.
Its wings are injured.
Go get some medicinal wine.
Okay.
The bird will be able to fly home
if we cure it.
It's a skylark that you saved.
Skylarks miss their home
the most.
No matter where they are taken,
they will do whatever it takes
to fly back home.
Only then can they feel at ease.
Huaiying,
what's the matter?
I had a dream.
Why aren't you sleeping yet?
I have something
to tell you.
You've been busy these days.
I'm afraid I won't see you tomorrow.
I met
a mason today
when I had my instrument repaired.
He wanted to ask you for a favor.
Tell me.
He said
he wanted to pick up
the sausages he ordered from Loong.
They cost him
a lot of money.
He doesn't want
to waste the money.
But that mason...
What happened to him?
Huaiying,
look.
This is the annual name list
of enlistment in Yonghui County.
These are the reasons
why Lin Fan collected Chu Lei's body.
[Name List]
They joined the army
in the same year.
Lin Fan?
The mason I talked about just now
is also called Lin Fan.
He is Lin Fan...
[Loong's Butchery]
[Huang]
[Chun]
[Lin]
Magistrate,
do you really think Lin Fan
is the murderer?
Not sure.
Do you think
Lin Fan might have killed
the three people
out of comradeship?
Find a package
to wrap the sausages in.
[Chunyu]
[Lin]
Lin Fan.
I have said before
that I would take these
by myself once informed.
How dare I trouble you
to deliver these personally?
You know me?
When you held court trials,
I went to see them.
So I remember your look.
Are these
made by you?
Yes, that's right.
It seems
you have been a mason for years.
For five years.
Who was your mentor?
I didn't have a mentor.
I learned these by myself.
You are talented.
That's too much praise.
Carry on with your business.
Before you became a mason,
how did you make a living?
I worked in gambling houses and inns.
I had been an ironsmith and farmer.
I tried many kinds of jobs.
And before that?
What do you mean by "before that"?
The first year of the Yonghui Reign.
These are the reasons
why Lin Fan collected Chu Lei's body.
Beat him!
Lin Fan.
As a soldier stationed at the border,
what haven't you seen?
Stop acting.
I'm a deserter.
As you have seen through me,
please spare my life, Magistrate.
Raise your head.
Whether you are a deserter or not,
I don't care.
I came here
not to catch you
but to investigate a case.
Sit down.
Let's continue with the topic.
You are a deserter.
You've already fled,
so why not go into hiding
and move to another place?
Magistrate, you may not know it.
Before you came here,
outlaws were rampant in Lanfang County.
Even the previous Magistrate's Office
was burnt by them.
Among these outlaws,
some are also deserters.
My real name
cannot be hidden.
But it is also because of this
that they protected me
and I have survived.
Comradeship.
Sort of.
For comradeship,
you collected someone's corpse.
I thought you came
to catch me
because I am a deserter.
I didn't know
you came for Chu Lei and Chunyu's case.
I didn't mention this,
and you know
I came for Chunyu's case.
Isn't it being talked about everywhere?
Well,
about Chu Lei,
what do you know?
Though we were comrade-in-arms,
we were not that familiar to each other.
I collected his corpse
out of morality.
The Magistrate's Office was burnt down,
but the case files are still intact.
The file says clearly
that you and Chu Lei
were in the same troop
and had faced life and death together.
You said
you were not familiar with him.
Are you kidding me?
That was more than a decade ago.
Even if you know everything about him,
can you
dig him out of his grave
and investigate the case?
How to investigate a case
is my business.
All you need to do
is answer my question.
During that year,
Heiyan brought chaos to society.
Even the Magistrate's Office
was burnt down.
An unimportant prisoner
died.
Who would care about this?
But when did he die?
How did he die?
Moreover,
was
the dead man really Chu Lei?
Who knows about it?
Magistrate,
you have doubts
about what happened before.
I really can't explain it.
Tell me.
Let's start with why Chu Lei
enlisted in the army.
Chu Lei
told me in person
[Chunyu]
that he enlisted in the army
because he wanted to be successful.
That way,
he could go back to marry Chunyu.
Give it back to me!
Actually,
every soldier knew well
that we were two weak scholars.
We weren't fit to be soldiers at all.
Every day in the military
felt like an eternity.
I was insulted every day.
So was he.
Kill me.
I can't do it myself.
Look,
I used a piece of tile to cut myself.
It hurts.
I can't bear it.
One day,
I thought of fleeing.
I knew
if we got caught,
it would be beyond redemption.
But I didn't care at all.
I could only remember
all the humiliations.
According to the rule
of the border army,
if a soldier runs away and gets caught,
he'll be left hanging
under the blazing sun for seven days.
If he survived,
he could be forgiven.
But no one could survive for five days.
However, the heaven lets us survive.
On the fifth day,
it rained.
From that day on,
everything changed.
- He stopped showing mercy to anyone.
- Come on!
He seemed to have lost his heart.
He was like an empty shell.
But I heard
Chu Lei
was a useless poor scholar.
A villain?
Once,
we were dispatched to a village
to suppress the rebellion.
Chu Lei served as the leader
for the first time,
commanding the battle.
It was more of a massacre
than suppressing the rebellion.
Kill him!
Please don't.
I'm begging you.
Don't kill me.
Don't care about who they are.
They are worthless things,
not humans.
Chu Lei went on a killing spree
and became a man of no scruples.
Before he enlisted,
he was kind, indeed.
But after that,
he became extremely ruthless.
Magistrate,
do you know
what kind of person Chu Lei was now?
No one stopped him
from slaughtering innocents?
People in the military
cover for each other.
This is the rule.
It's been more than a decade.
If you don't believe me,
just treat it
as if you've heard a story.
Heiyan.
Lin Fan,
what do you think of Heiyan?
Do you know
villains in Lanfang County
are all afraid of Heiyan?
When I returned from the military,
I had to survive the chaos.
Indeed,
I thought about joining Heiyan.
But you showed up and defeated Heiyan.
Thanks to you,
I didn't make the mistake.
Defeated Heiyan.
You said I defeated Heiyan
instead
of wiping them out.
It indicates
that in your heart,
you know Heiyan still exists.
Let's end our conversation.
I'll come to see you again.
Zhao, the blacksmith.
Here, here.
Thanks a lot.
What's written here?
You are here to get the sausages, too?
Wang, the tailor.
Here, here.
Thanks!
It's really delicious!
You only care about eating.
You dare to eat something
made by a dead person?
Haven't you heard the discussions?
You'll get your turn sooner or later.
Go back now.
Go back!
Go!
Trying to beat a woman?
Is he really a man?
What a waste!
Mr. Zhao (the Sixth).
It's me.
They say the meat is delicious.
Let's take it back to the Magistrate.
Miss Cao,
why don't you leave the sewing
to the servants?
I have nothing to do.
I can handle it without bothering others.
Alright.
The instrument repairer is waiting
for you outside.
I'll go take a look.
[Rong]
[Lanfang County Magistrate's Office]
Miss Cao,
I fixed it.
Here you are.
Thank you.
By the way,
I have some tasks to do in my shop,
so I'll take my leave first.
Thank you again.
Take my instrument back to the house.
Okay.
Miss Cao,
it's getting dark. Where are you going?
Just walking around. I'll be back soon.
[Lanfang County]
Lin Fan?