[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 12]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
Huaiying.
You're still alive.
Gold.
You see.
Quite a lot.
I found them all.
Come on, do me a favor.
This case
is solved.
We solved it.
Do me a favor.
Come on.
You threw the box into the sea.
How is that possible?
Stop lying.
This is not a gold smuggling case.
This is an arms trafficking case.
Gold is only for trading.
When did you start to suspect me?
Since Yusu left that word in my hand.
All the clues
are connected.
With one word,
and you conclude that I'm the murderer.
Plus this box of gold,
isn't that enough?
In Penglai,
Wang Lide helped Baekje people
with arms trafficking.
The sellers of the weapons
are officials who oppose Her Majesty.
And you
are the middleman they chose.
For a long time,
your smuggling channels
are unobstructed.
You even taught him
the score notation in the capital,
which aids your communication
when smuggling gold.
But this time,
Wang Lide is in trouble.
Heiyan's men found him.
They asked him
to rob this gold.
He knows
exchanging gold for weapons
will involve the privileged.
He can't offend them.
But Heiyan's men are cruel.
He dared not say no, either.
He thought about it.
Then he decided to confess to you.
He asked you for help.
What happened?
Brother Yu.
Two days ago, Heiyan's men found me.
They said they would
rob our gold on the ship.
And promised to give me a share.
If I don't say yes,
I'm afraid...
I
will die.
He wants to ask you
to use the power of the privileged
to kick Heiyan's men out of Penglai.
In this way,
he can continue to smuggle gold.
But after you heard it,
you got another evil idea.
You and Wang Lide
made an appointment
at a place in the sea.
That place
is your secret with him.
There're three copies
of the nautical chart.
One for you and one for Wang Lide.
Heiyan also got one.
It's just that there is no such place
on Heiyan's nautical chart.
That's where you were going
to take all the gold by yourself.
Wang Lide followed your plan.
He stunned Heiyan's sailors.
Wang Lide stopped
at the island on his way,
waiting for the time agreed with you.
But when you got on board,
he discovered that
you didn't bring a single soldier.
He became suspicious of you.
Why do you come alone?
Where are your men?
They are all on the big ship behind.
They will be here shortly.
Everything in the cabin is taken care of.
Where's the gold?
This way.
Why did you put it here?
More noticeable, less suspicious.
How come your men haven't come yet?
If Heiyan finds out,
we are done.
Wang Lide.
Wang Lide's fall
into the sea was an accident.
But you were not worried.
In fact,
Wang Lide drifted to the island at sea
and lived a few more days.
It was really not a threat to you.
What you were waiting for
is a big tide.
You were waiting for the ebb tide,
when you could come
to the trench to get back the gold.
What I didn't expect is
that you are so proficient in tides.
In fact, about tides and stars,
I also know a thing or two.
You were planning
to take the largest sum of gold
smuggled from Baekje by yourself.
On one hand,
the weapons were not lost.
You have something to
explain to the officials.
On the other hand,
you made it look
like it's Heiyan who robbed the gold.
So you won't be chased after
by the Baekje people.
For such a big business,
you only need to get rid of Wang Lide.
Still, it's a pity.
What you didn't expect is
the chain of accidents that followed.
You didn't expect
there was also a stowaway
from Baekje hiding on the ship.
This skinny man
said he saw Heiyan's men.
On a sailor,
I've seen a weird tattoo.
Heiyan didn't get the gold
and lost ten of his sailors.
He was infuriated already.
What's worse,
their whereabouts were exposed.
They were wanted by the court.
So,
they sent Jin Sang
pretending to be a survivor.
His confession involved
all dignitaries of Penglai.
One of them
is the shipmaster surnamed Gu.
- The ship is his.
- Nonsense!
This is a false charge.
There is also an official surnamed Yi.
You are talking nonsense!
Then Heiyan deliberately
offered a nautical chart
to lead us
to the sea.
In fact, at that time,
I haven't thought it could be you.
When people are trapped at sea,
some of the original secrets
can't be hidden any longer.
That's strange.
As we just set sail,
someone sabotaged the sail.
Out of the way!
I've been thinking about it.
I think he is afraid
of gold being found.
In another word,
he is also afraid of being found by me
who
is smuggling gold.
The first one
to show his trail is Yi Pan.
He can't explain
why that night
he would leave the port with the
Director of Maritime Trade's ship.
I don't know how you manipulated Yi Pan
so he'd serve you.
I guess
there are only two reasons.
First, in the name of handling cases
by the Ministry of Punishments.
Second,
he didn't check the gold ships before
and took advantage of it.
And this
helps you to blackmail him.
Someone tried to kill Director Yi and me.
On the night of the gold ship's accident,
Director Yi accompanied
a mysterious man out of the sea.
He refused to say who the man was.
He said he would be dead
if he let out the secret.
Mr. Gu.
Is that you?
On the ship,
the secret was hard to keep unknown.
So,
you strangled Yi Pan.
You made his death look like a suicide.
Gu Mengbin might not know your secret.
But Yi Pan's death frightened him.
You were afraid
that Gu Mengbin knew something.
So,
you shot an arrow in the back
and killed him.
To cover up the secrets of gold,
you've become so frenzied.
Di Renjie
collaborated with the enemies.
Get your arrows ready.
Go.
It never occurred to me
the last person you wanted to kill
is me.
Why?
Why this case of gold
turned my friend into a demon?
This box of gold
can get me back what I want.
Do you understand?
Hong Liang.
Thank you for timely sending a ship
to rescue me.
This means as you just said,
Hou Yu calculated
when the tide would recede,
then he sank the gold
into the trench ahead of time.
Di Renjie's way of handling cases
is interesting.
I was mistaken to blame Magistrate Di.
Commissioner.
The tide will soon rise.
Time is running out.
Go.
Send someone to meet him quickly.
You go.
Yes, sir.
Give up the official behind you.
Come back with me and turn yourself in.
You shut up.
My family worked
for Tang for three generations.
My grandfather
taught me astronomy
and maritime affairs since I was a child.
He wanted me to be a prodigious talent.
But now that Her Majesty is in power,
I see no hope.
Those senior officials
who oppose Her Majesty
are all evil-minded.
They asked me to smuggle gold.
They let me associate
with people like Wang Lide.
What the heck os Wang Lide?
He's small time.
And I...
I have something greater to achieve.
Do you really think I value this gold?
It was Her Majesty who relieved me
of my official duties.
None of those senior officials
spoke for me.
They're all cowards.
You have no other choice
but to turn yourself in.
Huaiying,
we have another choice.
For this gold,
I won't keep any of it.
I will give it all away.
All those who died
are major criminals for gold smuggling.
We took them out.
They deserved to die.
They deserve the punishment.
This case was solved by you.
You can take this gold
and report to Her Majesty.
Huaiying, do you remember the time
when we were in the capital?
We were drinking and singing.
We were high-spirited.
We have great plans for the country.
Do you remember?
Help me out this time, will you?
Let me go.
Di Renjie.
Magistrate.
The tide is rising.
Magistrate, hurry up.
Magistrate.
The tide is rising. Magistrate.
Hou Yu.
Di Renjie.
- Let's go, Magistrate.
- Di Renjie.
Magistrate, hurry up.
Magistrate.
Hou Yu.
Now I got this gold.
I can get my career back.
At that time
I am still elite of
the Ministry of Punishments.
Huaiying.
I'll be
the pillar of Tang.
Here comes the tide.
The case of gold was solved.
Your Majesty,
from now on,
there will be no more smuggled gold
in the capital.
Hong.
You are in a hurry.
Where are you doing?
I have an appointment with Ms. Cao.
We will go to the temple to pray.
Go, go.
What's the matter?
Magistrate, got something on your mind?
Not at all.
Then why don't you say anything?
Today...
It's a good day.
It's rare.
Right?
Across the bridge,
it's just a short walk away
from the Buddhist temple.
Magistrate, do you believe in Buddhism?
No.
And you?
I believe in destiny in Buddhism.
Everything has its cause.
All joys and sorrows are
external circumstances.
Honor, disgrace, calamity, and fortune are
all karmas from past lives.
Even though they exist now,
they will return to nothingness
when the destiny ends.
So, not to be delighted, come what may.
Leave everything to destiny.
Magistrate, you said
you don't believe in Buddhism.
But what you just said
are all Buddhist teachings.
It's just hearsay.
You see.
There is a cherry tree there.
It's really a cherry tree.
It is growing on this cliff.
It's not easy.
The world enters eternal night.
Life and death are vast and boundless.
When I was a child,
my father is in distress.
My mother and I
were exiled to a remote and dry place.
We were hungry and thirsty.
Fortunately,
I met a cherry tree.
That's how we survived.
Speaking of which,
me and the cherry tree
are really destined.
Magistrate.
That man.
That year,
a little girl's family
suffered a catastrophe.
That man
saved you.
That's why you came to Penglai.
You are here for him.
You want to find him.
Then today, why do you...
Faraway,
in fact, there is nothing.
Faraway
there could have something.
Huaiying.
Please sit down.
Have some fruit.
I'll prepare dinner.
Stay for dinner.
Will you?
No need for that.
It's time for me to leave.
Please stay.
Have a meal and enjoy your time.
I heard you would stay for dinner.
We have nothing at home.
Stop pulling me.
What are you talking about?
Ms. Cao.
Hong wonders if there is
anything you don't like.
You...
Do you eat coriander?
They are strange today.
I don't know what happened to them.
They just
want to know what happened to us.
Then what happened to us?
For today,
thank you.
I didn't expect that
you'd really plant a cherry tree.
In this way,
when you want to eat cherries,
you can get it right here.
Do you know
it will take at least
three to four years
before a tree can bear fruit?
But it'll eventually bear fruit, won't it?
[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Rain Master Legend]
Here's my pawn ticket.
Why don't you give it back?
You must return my bracelet today.
It must be returned to us.
What's happening?
It's loud in the morning.
What are you yelling about?
This is Yamen.
How dare you?
Yamen is exactly the place.
I want to see Magistrate.
Zhong's pawnshop is cheating.
[Penglai Yamen]
I want justice.
He won't give my bracelet back.
Shut up.
That's him.
Behave yourself.
Come on, stop it.
What's going on here?
Magistrate.
Magistrate, you are just in time.
I want justice.
Six months ago, in Zhong's pawnshop,
I pawned a gold bracelet.
We agreed
on a period of six months.
Now the ticket is here.
It is in black and white.
[Pawn ticket]
Today is the last day of the period.
I've got enough money.
I want my bracelet back.
But they told me
the bracelet is missing.
Magistrate.
[Shopkeeper Lin]
The ticket is genuine.
The handwriting on it
is indeed the handwriting
of shopkeeper Zhong.
But we really
couldn't find the bracelet.
Now, the shopkeeper is not in the store.
As for how to pay up,
I'm really sorry
but we still have to wait
for the shopkeeper to come back.
When will he come back?
It's hard to say.
This is personal for the shopkeeper.
We're not really sure.
Personal?
I heard that you shopkeeper
has been playing tricks recently.
In my opinion,
he plotted to run away with our stuff.
Is he running away?
Don't worry about that.
Zhong's pawnshop
has been established
for more than 20 years.
Our reputation is well-known.
If you can't return my bracelet today,
you have to pay me money.
I have told you.
Compensate us.
Since the shopkeeper is away,
the period
is invalid
and will be postponed.
Until their shopkeeper comes back,
if they can't give your bracelet back,
or
he'll not have come back for a long time,
at that time,
you can come here again.
I will handle it impartially.
Well...
Now that Magistrate has said so,
what else can I say?
In three days,
if you can't find the bracelet,
I'll see you in court.
See you in court.
Thank you, Magistrate.
Come on now, mind your own business.
Walk away.
It is early in the morning,
but we have so many troubles.
Where did you two go?
A tavern in the east of the city.
Someone said there was trouble.
The shopkeeper came to report.
We both went to check that out.
Something serious?
It's no big deal.
They were drunk,
torn several tavern signs,
and smashed some chairs.
That shopkeeper is also unreasonable.
Some chairs were knocked over.
He insisted we two should compensate
saying that we were
incompetent in our duties.
Lucky for him, I am on duty.
Otherwise, I would beat him to death.
Magistrate.
Magistrate, someone came to report.
It's a homicide.
Poor child.
Last night,
after I found him,
he was too scared to say a word.
It took him all night
to speak.
When you found him,
was he in the watchtower
in the north of the city?
Yes.
Near the swamp.
Yesterday,
we were playing hide and seek
near the watchtower swamp.
After a long time,
I came out from behind the reeds.
But I couldn't find them.
They couldn't find me either.
I just kept walking.
I wanted to find my way out.
I kept walking
until I approached the swamp.
And then I saw someone lying there.
I saw a zombie.
This place is like hell.
Magistrate.
There is a pool of blood here.
More here.
The man must have been killed here.
And then began to crawl.
Crawl.
To where?
The watchtower.
You guys
check around.
[Ying'er]
Human.
I am Di Renjie, Penglai's magistrate.
Lady.
I meant no harm.
I just came by for a routine inquiry.
Last evening,
where were you?
What were you doing?
You are not allowed to be here.
Go away.
Lady.
Go.
I've seen it all around.
Didn't see a body.
Who are you guys?
I am Di Renjie, Penglai's magistrate.
We are ordered to patrol here.
There are often
Baekje's spy in this area
as well as smugglers.
Have you ever
found a body here?
Why should I tell you?
How dare you?
I am Penglai's magistrate.
All the cases that happen here
are under my jurisdiction.
We carried it away.
To where?
Barracks.
Where did you find the body?
Right here.
Why didn't you report it to me?
Why did you move the body?
Captain Li asked us
to carry it back.
Who gives him the right to do so?
Magistrate.
As for this,
you'll have to ask Captain Li himself.
Take me to him.
Magistrate.
What did you just find in the watchtower?
Why did he go to the watchtower?
Who?
The victim.
The murderer.
And these men.
This is the barracks.
You are allowed in without permission.
This is Penglai's magistrate.
You need to register your name
in the book.
[Di]
[Di Renjie, Ma Rong]
[Qiao Tai]
Thirteen.
Fourteen.
Fifteen.
Sixteen.
Seventeen.
Eighteen.
Nineteen.
Magistrate.
You don't have to do it personally.
It's my duty.
Here is my advice.
Don't come to such
a dangerous place alone.
Your men kept my men
outside the door.
In the barracks,
we don't welcome too many outsiders.
What about the woman on the watchtower?
[Captain Li]
As far as I know,
for a place
under the jurisdiction of barracks,
common people are forbidden.
Her name is Ying'er.
You've met her?
Ying'er is a mad.
She hasn't got into any trouble.
So I let her stay there.
I want to know
why you moved the body without permission?
What I want to know more is
why
the barracks meddle in this matter?
Thewatchtower area is
under the jurisdiction of the barracks.
I am the Penglai's magistrate.
In Penglai, I'm responsible
for any case, big or small.
If there is a murder involved,
you should report to me in time.
When I have disposed of the body,
I will ask someone
to send you a message.
You disposed of the body?
In such weather,
I can't leave a body here.
I don't want my soldiers
to die of plague.
It's probably burned out by now.
Where is the body?
Take me there.
It's OK.
Let him go.
Magistrate.
Be careful.
Don't get yourself burnt.
So many rules.
Why aren't we allowed
to go in with Magistrate?
You don't understand this.
Inside the barracks,
there are countless rules.
When I was a soldier,
I suffered a lot from rules.
So sometimes if you don't understand,
just remain silent.
What are you doing?
Now that I have nothing to do,
I want to have some practice.
Aren't you curious about it?
This shabby chest is locked up.
What's in it?
[Erotic pictures]
Look at how stressful
these young soldiers are.
No wonder it's locked.
Have you done the same thing?
Am I that kind of guy?
OK.
Let them go back.
Easy, easy.
Slowly.
Awesome.
Are you all right, brothers?
Fine.
It's worth it.
Last night was awesome.
Is it worth
getting beaten up?
Hell yes.
OK.