[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 11]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
Tai, it's foggy again,
be careful.
OK.
Hurry up.
Tonight, you two
must follow me closely and protect me.
- Yes.
Where is the observation post?
It's up there.
Let's go.
Sentry.
Master.
Come on, buck up.
If something unexpected happens,
just blow the wooden whistle.
Yes, Master, don't worry.
Time for a meal.
Shh.
Where is the girl named Yusu
being held?
Say it.
In the aft cabin.
Deputy Secretary Hou.
Bring the girl named Yusu here
to replace Deputy Secretary Hou,
or I will kill him.
Get away.
Don't tell Commissioner Liu.
Sister.
What are you doing?
Get up.
Go.
Where are you taking her?
Sister.
Let me go.
Yusu.
Go.
- Yusu.
- Sister.
Who sent you here?
Was it someone from Heiyan?
Stop talking nonsense,
you'll find out soon.
Guanshi.
Don't come over.
Jin Sang?
They come from Heiyan,
and they brought us over here.
Shut up.
A ship is coming.
Chief, we received Jin Sang's signal.
Nock the arrow.
Watch out.
It's an enemy ship.
Shoot the arrow.
Shoot.
Alert!
Everyone, take cover.
Hide quickly.
Don't be panic.
Don't run around.
Don't come over.
You're done.
Go to defend the enemy
and command the Yulin Guards,
otherwise
we will all die here.
Go.
Come up.
Come here.
What's the sound outside?
Commissioner,
I don't know.
Go and guard the door.
Don't let anyone in.
Yes.
Don't run.
Magistrate.
Don't be panic, everyone.
Archers.
Where are the archers?
Quick.
Magistrate.
Mr. Gu,
Heiyan is on the attack.
Let's go back to the cabin.
They're not Heiyan.
I've been set up.
Who did it?
Jin Sang?
Someone wants to kill Director Yi and me
and silence us.
We shouldn't have coveted
the benefits of smuggling gold.
Who are the buyers of gold?
Only Wang Lide knows.
I only provide the ships.
Magistrate.
The Yulin Guards,
assemble on the port side!
Nock the arrow.
Forty zhang.
Shoot.
Prepare to board
when we're nearly twenty zhang.
Qiao Tai,
go find Ms. Cao.
Tell them
not to act rashly.
Don't move.
Let her come alone.
Let me go.
Go.
Stop.
- Go back.
Go back.
Come here.
Now she is worth more than you.
Help me.
Ms. Cao,
Ms. Cao.
Within ten zhang.
Magistrate,
there is no one in Ms. Cao's room.
Jin Sang captured Yusu.
Hold the deck.
Chief, we've lost quite a few brothers.
Do we still proceed closer to the ship?
Continue as planned.
Yes.
Help me.
Tell me what on earth did he say to you?
Nock the arrow.
Hou Yu.
Yusu.
Qiao.
He is from Heiyan.
Help me.
Magistrate Di.
Commissioner Liu.
What happened?
Jin Sang captured Yusu.
Magistrate Di went to negotiate.
Yusu.
The secret lies in Yusu.
That's why on the ship,
as soon as Yusu was taken into custody,
Di Renjie and his fellows became anxious
and sent Qiao Tai to visit.
If the situation is critical,
Di Renjie will definitely reveal his flaws
and then cover up Yusu.
Di Renjie.
Magistrate Di,
help me.
Help me.
If you remain silent,
I will surely kill you.
Magistrate Di,
help...
help me.
Say.
Say it.
Commissioner.
What do you want?
Gold.
I'm going to use it to seek justice for
my ten brothers who died.
Who killed them?
Wang Lide.
Where is he?
Wang Lide embezzled the gold
and ran away.
This is his woman,
the only clue to the gold.
Tell me,
where is Wang Lide?
I really don't know.
- You are so stupid.
- I really don't know.
She is just a songstress
and has nothing to do with gold.
If I weren't here now,
you would die immediately.
Let her go.
Who is stupid?
Look around this ship.
They're all from Heiyan.
In less than an hour,
Heiyan can kill everyone
on this ship.
There is no need to hide the truth now.
Heiyan originally wanted to rob the gold.
We have long heard about
Wang Lide smuggling gold from Baekje.
I told him
that when the next large shipment of gold
is escorted,
Heiyan will take over.
We'll rob the gold on the way
and give him one-tenth of it.
The two big shots at the port,
Gu Mengbin and Yi Pan,
were both involved.
They both got a share of the benefits.
According to our request,
Wang Lide replaced the crew members
with Heiyan's brothers,
and ten of them went to Baekje with him.
But that night,
we sent a ship
to pick up the gold as agreed.
Both gold and Wang Lide disappeared,
and our members were poisoned.
There were strong winds and waves
that night.
We've checked
that none of the merchant ships in Penglai
went to sea.
We concluded
that the news of the gold hijacking
must have been leaked.
So I pretended to
be a survivor
and intentionally diverted your attention
in order to find out the truth
through you.
The chart you got
was deliberately released by us.
After setting sail, I quietly
went on the deck and destroyed the mast,
leaving your ship alone.
We must take back the gold.
The person who knows the truth
is on this ship.
I really don't know.
Shoot arrows.
Stop.
Go.
Heiyan has boarded the ship.
Kill them.
Heiyan.
Go outside and take a walk.
Stuck in this cage,
you could only be a plaything in the end.
Chief,
I am here.
Di Renjie,
thank you for telling us
the secret of gold
and bringing us here.
Chief,
this woman has a clue to gold.
I... I don't know anything.
Jump down.
There's a boat waiting to pick us up.
Let's go.
- Go
- Don't kill me.
- Go.
Guanshi.
Don't let anyone go.
Chief.
Kill them all.
Retreat.
Magistrate.
Wang Lide
left three words that I didn't recognize.
Yusu.
Di Renjie
is colluding with the enemy.
Everyone, nock the arrows.
- Commissioner.
- Don't shoot arrows.
Hou Yu.
- Commissioner, don't shoot arrows.
- Magistrate.
Don't shoot arrows.
Shoot.
Di Renjie.
Magistrate.
If a lark wants to fly higher,
it must go farther.
Go outside and take a walk.
Stuck in this cage,
you could only be a plaything in the end.
Who are you going to see?
What?
Who do you want to see
after taking such a big risk
to get on the ship?
That person
is important, right?
Have you seen that person?
Yes.
What should we do next?
Hong should have received my signal.
Let's wait for him.
I notice that you're very skilled at
making fires and setting up camps.
You must have been to many places,
haven't you?
I went to the north of the Great Wall.
You are really well-informed.
I guess
you must've gained many life insights.
Insights on life.
Insights on life
cannot be gained until the end of life.
When that time comes,
speaking of the past,
I might feel that
everything was just a fleeting moment.
Yes.
Everything was just a fleeting moment.
Someone once told me
that a lark stuck in a cage
could only be a plaything
in the end.
Only by traveling
can one understand the rule of nature.
At that time,
I was young and naive,
believing that this was the essence
of the world.
Now looking back,
it's nothing but an empty illusion.
Not exactly.
The journey of life
is unpredictable.
One may come across
a variety of experiences.
Every challenge you've encountered
might offer you some inspiration,
sadness,
or joy.
I'm going to collect some firewood.
♪Today under the flower tree♪
♪It seems like ages♪
♪In the early summer♪
♪Your youthful face is rouged♪
♪Lies in the lips♪
♪Revealed between eyebrows♪
♪The old love appears in a dream♪
When I was passing by,
I heard you play a Bingzhou ditty.
I wonder
if you could play it again for me.
♪Fate brings us together and apart,
yet my heart remains undisturbed♪
One's missing.
Maybe someone escaped with it.
Do you recognize him?
I do. It's him.
Wang Lide.
Magistrate.
It's Wang Lide.
Magistrate,
look.
Huaiying,
according to the letter you gave me,
I found the island.
This is the Huang Dao Yi
you asked me to find.
Fortunately, a few years ago,
there was a magistrate
who liked to observe the stars at night.
So I found one in the library.
It's all rusted now,
I hurriedly asked a craftsman
to repair it.
I wonder if it can still be used?
It's OK.
Where are the calendar books?
They're all here.
All the old almanacs that
can be found are here.
Wang Lide left three words
that I didn't recognize.
This is what Yusu left for me
before she died.
It is the words on the score.
Yusu said
that Wang Lide played the guqin.
Wang Lide was a gold smuggler.
He must have had contacts
with people in the capital.
Then he learned
this popular score in the capital.
The words on the score
not only suggest the fingering
[fourteen]
but also imply two numbers
(ten and four).
The "ten" represents the Hui
of the guqin.
A guqin has 13 Huis.
A star leading board
consists of 12 square boards.
These 13 Huis
are enough to include
the star leading board.
The "ten" represents...
The tenth board
of the star leading board.
Yes.
It's called the ten zhi.
What about this "four"?
The "four" represents the string.
A guqin has seven strings.
This season,
if the sailors are to set sail,
they'll need to observe
six or seven constellations.
Counting from left to right,
the fourth is
Zhinv Star.
This means
that we need to align
the tenth star leading board
with Zhinv Star in the sky, right?
As long as we measure three stars
and compare them with the chart,
we can deduce the location
where Wang Lide left the gold.
What about the other two words
left by Yusu?
She didn't have a chance to say it.
Then how can we measure the stars?
Wang Lide seems to be an uneducated guy,
but he must have studied
the tides in Penglai
or
the people behind him have studied.
That person
is the killer.
As for the Maritime Trade Administration,
I went there to check.
The soldiers who sailed
with Director Yi that night said
that Director Yi's order
was for night patrol.
But there was a mysterious guy
on the ship,
who was said to be a guest of Director Yi.
This man covered his face
since he got on the ship.
The soldiers couldn't see
his face clearly,
so they called him the mysterious guy.
I've got it figured out.
I've got it all figured out.
That night,
Director Yi took him on a voyage with him.
There are three copies of the route map,
one for Wang Lide
and one for Heiyan.
The third copy is
in the hands of this mysterious man.
I checked the weather that night.
The sky was clear
in the first half of the night,
but it was windy and rainy
in the second half of the night.
Therefore, the ship must have arrived
at the designated sea area
before the middle of the night.
But neither Director Yi nor the soldiers
had seen gold.
Therefore,
the mysterious man
must have boarded Wang Lide's boat alone
and killed him.
And the mysterious man
finally threw the boxes filled with gold
to the sea.
Threw gold to the sea?
I think I'm right.
But this man has spent so much effort.
Why did he sink the gold
to the bottom of the sea?
What's wrong with the man?
He can't stand gold,
and he has a grudge against gold?
There is no such person.
Of course, he wanted
to keep the gold for himself.
He couldn't get rid of greed
even though he tried his best.
The place where gold was sunk that night
was actually not far from the coast.
[Record of Haitao]
"Record of Haitao" records
that a strange large tide occurs here
every hundred years.
When a tide occurs,
the water level at low tide
can retreat more than ten lis
to reveal a large trench.
The cycle of hundreds of years has passed,
and the great tide
is happening today.
Guanshi.
Huaiying.