[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 3]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
[Day five]
[Department of State Affairs]
Stop.
Go.
Open it up.
Is there anything in it?
You guys
look new to me.
We're new.
Go now.
What's wrong?
Clean up now.
[Archive]
So many.
What are we looking for?
We're looking for the list of those
who left the capital nine days ago,
on the tenth day of the fifth month.
There are so many. How can we find it?
Split up and search for it.
Qiao Tai,
you go over there.
How about me?
Wherever you choose.
What...
What does he mean
by "wherever I choose"?
You don't know how to read. You...
Shut up.
I don't know how to read, so what?
So what?
Fine.
Whatever you want. Okay?
[The tenth day of the fifth month]
[List of Personnel Who Left the Capital
on the Tenth Day of the Fifth Month]
Here it is.
On the day you mentioned,
ten people left the capital.
Yangzhou, Shannan Circuit.
Four of them went there.
General Kang,
we found something suspicious here.
This place is not planned
for remodeling.
General Kang,
we have checked everywhere.
Nobody is here.
Check the armory again.
Don't leave anything to chance.
Yes.
Mr. Di,
why must we check the Yulin Guards'
records of leaving the capital?
On the second day
of these Yulin Guards' departure
from the palace,
the Governor of Yangzhou, Chen Zhuliang,
was forcibly poisoned and killed.
The ones who delivered the decree
were the Yulin Guards.
From Chang'an to Yangzhou,
it takes half a day at top speed.
So those four were the ones
who delivered the forged imperial decree.
They were silenced?
The forged imperial decree
is the cause of the violent criticism.
From Jushui Entertainment House,
all the deaths
are related to the Phoenix Seal.
The Yulin Guards are the royal army.
Who has the guts
to kill the Yulin Guards?
Let's investigate.
On sale. It's fresh.
Make way, please.
Come and take a look.
Sea animal and grape pattern.
Remember what it looks like.
Let's split up and look around
to see if we can find anything similar.
I'll go over there.
I'll go that way.
Small bowls.
Beautiful plates.
A wine glass that ran across the sea.
Excuse me,
is that a picture of a sea animal?
Yes.
It's an animal.
Where did it come from?
Can you tell me where it came from?
It's a wine glass brought from far away.
Well,
well.
Stop. You don't have to say anymore.
Forget I asked.
Welcome.
Sir,
you're from the Xuanjia Army, right?
Me?
This is the unique decoration
on the Xuanjia Army's sword.
The Xuanjia Army greatly contributed
to Emperor Taizong's defeat
of Xueyantuo Khaganate.
It's made
of pure copper.
It's a rare item nowadays.
I'm afraid
only General Kang Huai'en's soldiers
would have it.
Kang Huai'en.
I've heard that name before.
He's a rebel, right?
Yes.
He had no vision.
Even we Kucha people know
that Emperor Taizong would win,
but he defected to Xueyantuo.
Are you selling this?
I can offer you this much for it.
[Wei's Residence]
Stop drinking.
Have some water.
You see.
All the cases related to the Heavenly Fire
are linked to the Empress.
Everyone out there is saying
that anyone who supports the Empress
will be punished by Heaven
and burned by the Heavenly Fire.
Do you think it's true?
It's all due to the political rivals.
This case
seems simple,
but it's full of suspicions.
For example, what does this
have to do
with Kang Huai'en's
soldiers of the Xuanjia Army
who battled
against Xueyantuo Khaganate?
Why don't we write the character "Niu"?
Don't write "Ma" anymore.
"Yang" is fine, too.
Why is it so hard
to write the character "Ma"?
Why do you have to do this?
Why don't you just tell Mr. Di
that you don't know how to read?
I can tell anyone but him.
I'm warning you.
Don't you tell him.
Preferring to save face
even at the cost of suffering.
You've been writing all morning.
You...
[Ma]
This one is not bad.
[Official Records of Personal Identity]
Where did you get this paper?
Why?
I took it from the Archive.
[Kang]
You don't know how to read, right?
Why did you take this?
It's so pretty.
It can be a souvenir.
Mr. Di,
we've found something important.
An unexpected find.
It's Kang Zhiyi's profile.
Where did you get this?
Rong...
I knew you'd need it,
so I found it for you.
Kang Huai'en is Kang Zhiyi's father?
Kang Zhiyi killed the people
in the silkworm house?
How about Jushui Entertainment House?
That night,
I did see his horse
in Pingkang Ward.
That's not right.
Kang Zhiyi works for the Empress.
Why would he do anything against her?
Maybe he was told to do it.
Back then,
his father was sentenced
to death for rebellion,
but his family survived
because
of a guarantor.
Afterward,
he was recommended
to serve in the palace
as the commander of the Yulin Guards
for Zhangsun Qing.
Kang Zhiyi.
Zhangsun Qing.
What did you find?
Nothing.
This case
still has doubts.
[Imperial Academy]
Mr. Wei.
Huaiying,
how can I help you?
I have found out the truth.
So, who was it?
The Empress's guard,
Kang Zhiyi.
He stole the Phoenix Seal,
forged the imperial decree,
and ordered the Yulin Guards to poison
and kill Chen Zhuliang.
Then,
he set fire to kill the palace maid Yaxin,
who was responsible for the Seal,
as well as the four Yulin Guards,
who delivered the forged imperial decree.
This is not the place to talk.
Kang Zhiyi
has been guarding the Empress
since she entered the palace
and is trusted by the Empress.
Even with the Phoenix Seal missing,
there's no reason to suspect him.
But I found out
that Kang Huai'en is Kang Zhiyi's father.
Back then, the one
who saved the Kang family
from being executed
was Zhangsun Qing.
In the first year of the Yonghui Reign,
the late Emperor passed away.
Kang Zhiyi returned to Chang'an.
The person who guaranteed his entry
into the Jinwu Guards
was also Zhangsun Qing.
So you suspect that Zhangsun
ordered him to commit the crime?
Zhangsun Qing
is the Empress' biggest political rival.
He had reason to frame the Empress.
On the night of the incident
at Jushui Entertainment House,
Kang Zhiyi was meeting Zhangsun Qing
in Pingkang Ward.
Are you two guests
of Grand Commandant Zhangsun?
A private event is held here.
We can't serve you today.
So,
time,
place,
and motive,
Kang Zhiyi has all.
It must be him.
What are you going to do?
Report to the Ministry of Justice
and the Court of Judicial Review.
Ask for a state trial
to justify the Empress.
Just with your testimony,
the Court of Judicial Review
wouldn't care.
Let me tell you something else.
Zhangsun Qing has worked
with Minister Xu Yuan
and Left Vice Director Sun Zhining
and written to His Majesty together.
Deposing the Empress
is only a matter of time.
However, the Empress
is protected by Xu Jingzong
and other ministers.
They can fight, though.
However,
Zhangsun Qing served
under three emperors.
He's a minister of honor,
a relative of the Emperor,
and the highest leader
of Tang's noble forces.
The head of most of the people
who oppose the Empress.
He's like a big tree
with strong and deep roots.
You can't cut it down.
It's a massive tree.
But if it fails from the inside,
we can cut it down
as long as we find the right moment.
You remind me of Di Zhixun.
Your father and I studied
under the same teacher.
We were quite close.
Huaiying,
this case is over.
Don't investigate any further.
The magistrate of Wannian County
and the Ministry of Justice,
I'll do my best to negotiate with them.
If you keep investigating,
not only you,
Hong Liang
and the siblings following you
will all be implicated.
The fight in the palace
is much more intense than we think.
Huaiying,
it's all fate.
You can't fight it.
Greetings, Grand Commandant Zhangsun.
There are too many people
who oppose the Empress.
And are all in high positions.
Chang'an
is not yours or mine.
It's theirs.
♪The land nurtures sweet osmanthus♪
♪Distant woods stand tall and strong♪
♪Leaves open, unfolding brilliance
in the wind♪
♪Flowers bloom, radiating moonlight♪
[Di Zhixun]
Father.
[Wei's Residence]
Mr. Di,
why are you in such a good mood
and even drinking with me today?
Is the case about to be solved?
What do you mean by "solved"?
Mr. Di,
I've searched for a long time
and found nothing.
But in a burnt tree branch,
I found this.
What do you think it is?
Is it related to the tree
that caught on fire?
No, it's nothing.
Ma Rong,
you've been in Chang'an for so long.
How do you like it?
Do you like Chang'an?
Why are you asking me this
all of a sudden?
Chang'an
is just as I thought it'd be.
No, not really.
Let me explain.
As long as you have money,
you can eat, drink, and have fun here.
But if you don't have money,
you're nothing.
People here dress nicely
and talk nicely.
But the things they do
don't seem so nice.
Think about the three of us
in the desert.
Three people, three horses,
nothing in sight,
but I was so happy.
In Chang'an,
there are so many people on the street.
But I always feel empty inside.
This is Chang'an.
It's just
like that ridiculous case.
It's all about power struggles.
There are no supernatural beings.
It's all excuses.
The truth?
There is no truth.
There is no emotion.
It's just
the perception
of a blinded heart.
There's no truth,
only...
Hong.
You're drunk.
Look at you now.
It's been five days.
You only have half the time.
Do you still have time
to be sentimental here
and talk about strange things
that nobody understands?
From the very beginning,
I shouldn't have let you
investigate the incident
at Jushui Entertainment House.
Now,
you got to Zhangsun Qing.
Tell me.
If the person
recruited by the Grand Secretariat
can't protect you,
what should you do?
Have you thought about that?
If he can't help me,
then that's it.
This case
is over.
If you two
don't like Chang'an,
you can leave.
Anytime.
Just say the word
and we'll go and kidnap
that Zhangsun fellow.
If you want to leave,
I'll pay for your passage.
What...
Mr. Di is in trouble.
We can't leave now.
Tai.
What is he taking us for?
He doesn't want to keep us.
We should leave.
What are you talking about?
You got drunk too?
Ma Rong.
Stop there.
Are you really leaving?
Di Renjie is in big trouble.
All the more reason not to leave.
I know him too well.
Even if we keep on bothering him,
he still won't say anything to us.
Anyway,
let's just keep an eye on him in secret.
We must appear timely
so that he'll know
we're precious to him.
Let's go.
It's under curfew.
We'll get caught if we go out.
I'll take you to a nice place.
[Wei's Residence]
I don't have any money.
Hong,
do you believe in fate?
If I hadn't brought
Ma Rong and Qiao Tai back,
I wouldn't have met He Dajing that day.
If I hadn't met He Dajing,
I wouldn't have
sat for the imperial examination.
That day,
after the examination,
we went to Pingkang Ward.
So many taverns and entertainment houses
were in Pingkang Ward,
but I chose Jushui Entertainment House.
[Jushui Entertainment House]
Now,
I can't help but think.
This may be my fate.
Do you remember
my father?
Except for the scene
on the Weishui River,
I can't remember
anything else.
Like you,
he loved to fight against fate.
There are still five days left.
Try your best.
Father.
Huaiying,
go.
You haven't finished your job yet.
Go and find it for me.
Find the truth.
[Day six]
This is Mr. Zhangsun.
Mr. Zhangsun.
[Pingtai Tavern]
Move aside.
Grand Commandant Zhangsun,
please take care of your health.
Please get on your horse.
Since the ceremony of worshiping
the Cypress of the Tang Empire,
you haven't said a word
and are just walking
with such a heavy burden.
We can't bear to see it.
Yes.
Grand Commandant Zhangsun,
please don't walk anymore.
Empress Wu's misdeeds
have brought Heaven's wrath
upon the people of Chang'an.
What does this have to do with you?
What does that have to do with me?
The Heavenly Fire
hurt many people in Chang'an.
I
am the grand commandant.
Tell me
what this has to do with me!
Heaven has established the order.
There is order and decency.
Seniors and juniors,
that is the order of seniority.
I thought
this is
the order of the world.
But when confronted
with decrees that disrupted the order,
I didn't try my best to stop it.
When confronted with those
who disrupted the order,
I didn't try my best to take them down.
This
angered Heaven
and incurred its wrath.
I, Zhangsun Qing,
should apologize to all the civilians.
I'm
guilty.
Grand Commandant.
Just now,
when I saw the Cypress of the Tang Empire
still flourishing,
I felt ashamed of the trust
of the two former emperors,
Gaozu and Taizong.
Today,
I'll give this branch
of the Cypress of the Tang Empire
to His Majesty
and urge him
to punish those who disobeyed the order.
Tomorrow,
I'll go to the Qinglong Temple
for a one-month retreat
to pray for
the Cypress of the Tang Empire.
I'll
donate incense and candles
that are worth 20,000 guan
and keep them burning day and night
to pray
for the people of Tang,
wishing that the Heavenly Fire disappears
and people can enjoy peace forever.
Thank you, Grand Commandant.
It is useless.
The Heavenly Fire
will come again.
Fire
is the hexagram "Radiance" in Bagua.
The upper and lower trigrams
of the hexagram
both have five lines.
That means
the Heavenly Fire
will come at least five times.
Five times?
When will the next fire come?
Right.
Fire is the utmost yang,
attracted by the sun.
It will change every three days.
Since the last Heavenly Fire
destroyed the silkworm house,
it has been 24 hours.
That means,
in two days,
the Heavenly Fire
will surely come again.
Where will it be this time?
Does it still have something
to do with the Empress?
Of course.
The Heavenly Fire
first burned down
the Empress's favorite Wutong tree.
For the second time,
it set fire
to the entertainment house
praised by the Empress.
For the third time,
it burned
the farmer who raised silkworms for her.
Then the next one...
By order of the Empress,
he's compiling Great Families
based on the Record of Eminent Families
from the Zhenguan Period.
The Empress's four families
are listed in the first class.
Grand Commandant Zhangsun
will have a hard time in the future.
Great Families.
This is the Empress's
biggest political move
in recent years.
The order of the world
will be reset.
If the Heavenly Fire
hates the new world,
then
it will come to it.
What if
the Heavenly Fire stops?
Then it means
there is no Heavenly Fire.
Everything
is man-made
to frame the Empress.
Who is
this man?
Di Zhixun's son,
Di Renjie.
When we get out of here,
you'll all listen to my command.
We'll move as one.
When we get out,
don't all go the same way.
Let's split up.
But our ultimate goal
is to go to Lanling Ward.
Understand?
Yes, sir.
Please forgive me, Mr. Wei.
Forgive you for what?
I deliberately enraged Zhangsun Qing
and put you and your students
in danger
so that he and Kang Zhiyi
would take the initiative
and reveal themselves.
Only then
will I be able
to catch them in the act
and expose their plot.
You're leaving an empty house as bait.
He will be able to tell
that you're egging him on.
They've already killed so many people.
If they don't bring down the Empress,
they'll lose everything.
I bet
they'll take the risk.
You want them to go to Lanling Ward?
Yes.
As far as I know,
Di's Residence is in Lanling Ward.
No one will remember
that guilty man.
A forgotten place
is the safest.
I'll escort you there myself.
I'm not going.
I'll stay.
Mr. Wei.
I'm over 50 years old.
Life and death
are no longer my concern.
I want to stay and see the Heavenly Fire
with my own eyes.
It's too risky.
Mr. Wei.
Huaiying,
stop trying to talk me out of it.
People
can't
escape their fate after all.
If I can have a chance
to see the real face
of the manipulator of fate,
it's worth it.
I will be sure to keep you safe.
[Wei's Residence]
Good.
Bravo.
Wonderful.