[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 30]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
Please come in.
[Tongfu Inn]
It's warm inside. Come.
Mind your step.
Come.
This way.
Please come in.
Sir,
two best rooms.
Okay, they'll be ready soon.
Please sit here for a while.
The weather changed without warning.
It's just the ninth month,
but the weather is so cold.
Please
have some hot tea first
to warm your bodies.
Is there anything to eat?
Yes. We have
hot goat soup that was just cooked.
You'll feel very warm
when you have a sip of it.
Did you see our Xiaobao?
Why are you here again?
What are you doing?
Did you see our Xiaobao?
Sir,
what's going on?
He is called Wei Xiaobao.
He is my grandson.
I lost him.
Did you see our Xiaobao?
He is this tall.
He has a mole
on the right side of his face.
He was wearing a white gown
and a pair of white shoes.
I was away for a while and you came again.
Your grandson is not here.
Don't look for him here.
He...
They are not from here.
They don't know it.
Go out quickly.
Who took away my Xiaobao?
Don't look for him here.
Your grandson is not here.
Don't come again.
Who is she looking for anyway?
Sorry, everybody.
Sorry.
What happened?
She is just a mad woman.
Mad as a hatter.
She comes every day
to look for her grandson.
We don't know whether it is true or not.
The goat soup
will be ready soon.
I'll cook it for you now.
Sir.
We don't want the goat soup anymore.
Take us directly to our rooms.
Okay.
This way, please.
Watch your step.
[Tongfu Inn]
It should be right ahead.
Unfortunately, the fog is too heavy.
We can't see anything.
The weather is not good.
Shall we go back?
Now that we've come,
we can make a wish.
Let's go there.
Harder.
Thank you, Sir.
Where are you from?
From the direction of Anxi Protectorate.
There was a snowstorm there.
I've never seen such a heavy snow.
The houses even collapsed
under the weight of the snow.
The snowstorm will come soon.
Go north
to Lanfang County.
Okay.
I am Di Renjie,
the Magistrate of Lanfang County.
If you need help,
go to the Magistrate's Office there.
Thank you, Magistrate Di.
Hurry up and go.
Thank you, Magistrate.
Let's go.
What's wrong with your hand?
Let me dress your wound.
It is snowing more and more heavily.
Let's not go any further.
Let's go back to Lanfang County.
Thickheaded.
Today,
I'll let you see Di Zhixun
in the netherworld!
Father!
Huaiying.
[Lanfang County Magistrate's Office]
Mr. Hong,
the wine has been heated.
Let's have a drink.
How can a girl
drink wine?
Give me the bowl.
Mr. Hong.
Mr. Hong,
a group of refugees came.
They said it was snowing heavily
in the south.
Will the Magistrate be in danger?
[Zhao Yun Library]
Huaiying,
there is a library ahead.
I'll go take a look.
Wait for me for a while.
Coming.
I'm sorry to disturb you.
Can I meet Mr. Cui?
[Zhou Li]
My teacher ordered
that no outsiders should be received.
Wait.
The person in the carriage
is Di Renjie,
the Magistrate of Lanfang County.
Please wait a minute.
I'll report to my teacher.
[Zhao Yun Library]
Are you Mr. Cui?
No.
[Li Miao]
I am Li Miao.
The Magistrate and you have come.
I should have welcomed you earlier.
Please pardon me.
The Magistrate was hurt
by poisonous thorns.
His wound swelled
and he has a fever.
Can we spend the night here?
I know a little about medicine.
I can dress the Magistrate's wound.
Thank you then.
However, Miss,
our teacher, Mr. Cui,
was assigned by the Minister of Rites
to compile the local history
of this place.
He has been writing in retreat.
Before his retreat, he repeatedly warned
that our library was not convenient
for receiving outsiders.
So after the wound is dressed,
you have to leave as soon as possible.
Follow me.
Look,
how serious his condition is.
So serious.
We can't go back to Lanfang County
due to the heavy snow.
If you don't take us in,
we have nowhere to go tonight.
If something really happens
to the Magistrate,
you are all responsible.
Hurry.
Carry the Magistrate
to the library.
Yes.
Miss Cao, this way.
Miss Cao, mind your step.
This way, please.
Slowly.
Miss Cao, here we are.
Our library has no spare rooms for guests.
This is where old papers
and books are kept.
You'll have to make do with it.
Come.
Carry him to the inner room.
Here, yours.
Thank you.
Please line up.
Here, yours.
Thank you.
[Lanfang County Magistrate's Office]
You see.
I said they shouldn't have gone there.
The north of the mountains
and the south of the water are Yin.
How else would they have encountered
such a once-in-a-century snowstorm?
Man proposes, but Heaven disposes.
Fine, Mr. Hong.
Stop nagging.
The Magistrate and Miss Cao will be fine.
Let's go.
Don't forget to take this.
Mount the horse.
Be careful on the road.
Okay!
How is he?
The Magistrate's pulse
is disordered.
He was not just poisoned.
He may also have
excessive internal heat
and has fallen ill from overwork.
It doesn't matter.
I'll get him some herbs.
Thank you.
Huaiying.
Magistrate,
you are awake.
This is...?
I am Li Miao.
This place is Zhao Yun Library.
Our teacher is Cui Haoran, Mr. Cui.
I've heard
Mr. Cui's song in Dingdu.
Mr. Cui
is kind to others
and makes no social distinctions
in teaching.
He is a great scholar.
Yes.
We came rashly...
Help me get up.
I'll go to greet Mr. Cui.
Well...
Mr. Cui is now in retreat.
Yes.
Besides,
Magistrate, your health...
I'm fine.
We came rashly.
Help me get up.
This way.
Magistrate,
the roads in the library are intricate.
On this snowy night,
the view is even more obstructed.
If you need anything,
Miss Cao can ask the students
in the library to do it.
Don't walk around on your own.
Come.
Be careful.
Why is he burning sandalwood
with such a strong smell?
In order to write smoothly
and understand the historical facts,
every time after reading
historical materials,
our teacher will be in retreat
and focus on meditation.
So he should be burning the sandalwood
to calm his mind.
Our teacher
repeatedly told us
not to disturb him during his retreat.
Otherwise, his previous efforts
would be wasted.
This is...?
Eaglewood from Yunshui Lodge.
Please give this
to Mr. Cui.
I won't disturb him.
Magistrate.
Well,
now that you are here,
just go in.
I thank you for my teacher.
I'll take this inside for him.
Are you okay?
Magistrate, be careful.
Who is it?
Mr. Li.
Zhou Li?
Where are you going?
The firewood in Mr. Cui's room
is not burning well.
I
will fetch some firewood.
Fetch some firewood.
I've told you so many times
that the woodshed is over there.
It's not in this direction.
I see.
Over there.
Not in this direction.
Please don't take it ill.
He is called Zhou Li.
He is a new student here.
Although the roads in the library
are intricate,
after such a long time,
he just can't remember
where the woodshed is.
I also feel...
Come on, hurry.
Hurry back to the room.
Miss Cao,
please let the Magistrate have a rest now.
I'll decoct the medicine for him.
I'll go with you.
Please wait for me
at the door for a while.
Have a rest.
I'll go get you some medicine.
Huaiying.
Magistrate.
What's wrong with the Magistrate?
Huaiying.
I saw...
I saw a child in white
going that way.
Well...
Come on. Go inside the room first.
Come.
Slowly.
Let me take the medicine.
The Magistrate said
he had seen a child in white in the yard.
No way.
Our library does not teach children.
A year ago, when our teacher
started to retreat,
he left only his close disciples
in the library.
Moreover,
they are all adults.
You have a fever.
So you could be hallucinating.
No.
I wasn't hallucinating.
I saw the child.
Okay.
Such being the case,
I'll ask them
to look around the yard
and see if any neighboring rascals
have strayed into this place.
If you need,
I can look around the place with you.
Miss Cao,
all the people in the library are men.
Please don't
walk around casually.
You don't believe me, either?
I do.
Don't think too much.
If there is really a child,
they will find them.
Mr. Li said
this medicine could work wonders.
If tomorrow,
the weather is better,
we will set off immediately.
Tai,
there isn't even a soul around here.
How can we find them?
Just go all the way south.
Can you still tell the directions?
I couldn't be a soldier for nothing.
Let's go.
[Zhao Yun Library]
[Gate to True Learning]
Zhou Li.
Come down.
Come here.
You evil spirits.
Come here. I'm not afraid of you!
Come down, Zhou Li.
Zhou Li.
It's too dangerous.
Come down.
Come down. It's too dangerous up there.
Come.
It's too dangerous up there.
Come down.
Zhou Li, did you hear us?
Yama.
Evil spirits.
Come down.
You all come!
Zhou Li, come down.
It's dangerous.
Zhou Li.
It's too dangerous up there.
Zhou Li, it's dangerous up there.
It's too dangerous.
It's too dangerous up there. Come down.
Come down, Zhou Li.
Did you hear us?
Come down.
Zhou Li.
Zhou Li, come down.
It's too dangerous.
Come down.
Zhou Li.
Come!
This...
Come, Huaiying.
[Ghost]
Mr. Li.
Lin Shu.
[Lin Shu]
Why
did Zhou Li do this?
When I woke up,
Zhou Li was not in bed.
I went out to see
and found him on the rooftop.
He was dancing wildly.
I don't know why he was like that.
Mr. Li.
Miss Cao.
Look at his palm.
[Ghost]
It seems to be the word "ghost".
I saw him writing it on his palm
before he jumped down.
Could you
take me to Zhou Li's room?
Okay.
Lin Shu,
lead the way.
Miss, please.
Such a tragedy.
[Gate to True Learning]
This way, please.
Here is his room.
Miss Cao,
our teacher
repeatedly gave us
the following instructions.
Lead a simple life
and enjoy living in a shabby house.
Miss Cao,
this is Zhou Li's desk.
Where was Zhou Li from?
When did he come to the library?
His family lives in a nearby village.
His mother is his only parent left.
His elder sister is looking after her.
He had been in the library
for over ten months.
After Mr. Cui retreated?
Yes.
I actually have no right to take him in.
But I thought he was sincere in his study.
Besides, he kept begging me,
so I could only bend the rules
and let him join the library.
He could pay his tuition by doing chores.
This is...
Lin Shu,
Zhou Li's condition was so serious.
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
Zhou Li had been out of his mind
for a long time?
He...
He had been
acting weird lately.
He always said
he was agitated.
He also said someone was watching him.
He often rambled at night.
Miss Cao, I don't want to say
anything improper
to cause concern,
but Zhou Li
was indeed quite weird lately.
During the morning reading,
he was often absent-minded.
I scolded him.
He told me
he had a Heavenly Eye.
He said he could see
unexpected calamities, wronged souls,
anxiety-ridden people,
and spirits behind people's backs.
I thought
he had read too much light reading.
I didn't expect him...
Miss Cao,
can you believe what he said?
After the Magistrate wakes up,
I'll tell him everything.
He will examine the body.
At that time,
there will be a definitive conclusion.
Okay.
Miss Cao,
I'll walk you back to your room.
Lin Shu,
put Zhou Li's body
in the woodshed for now.
Yes.
Miss Cao, please.
Tai,
I think it's weird.
It's like we're going around in circles.
Impossible.
With my sense of direction,
it should be...
Tai!
We are really going around in circles.
Mr. Hong is right.
The north of the mountains
and the south of the water are Yin.
We've encountered a ghost.
Don't talk nonsense.
How can there be a ghost?
That way. Follow me.