[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
[Episode 17]
Mr. Di, the new magistrate of Lan Ward,
is now holding court for cases.
Anyone has anything to say
is welcome to step forward.
Wait a minute.
What do you do?
Sorry.
Magistrate,
how long do we have to wait?
We wait until the work time is over.
If no one comes to report,
we still keep waiting all the time?
Until the work time is over.
Miss Cao,
please take a rest.
There are so many case files.
You can't finish them
within one or two days.
Case files in the Zhenguan era
remain just two volumes.
In the files,
the recorded Shangshu Zuocheng
is Magistrate Di's father?
[File]
Master is
not a traitor.
The bandit leader of Heiyan
was Master's schoolmate.
He wanted to use Huaiying
to compel Master to cooperate with him
and send weapons to Chang'an
so as to stage an armed rebellion.
But Master wouldn't agree.
Master
feared that Huaiying would face danger,
so he committed suicide.
It was because of Minister Di
that the Court
found out what Heiyan aimed to do
and finally annihilated them.
Right.
But what was the good of that?
Though the previous emperor
rehabilitated the Master,
he had already died.
He could not be restored to life.
Huaiying now buries himself in cases.
He tries to popularize the Tang Code
and it has something to do
with the misfortunes happened that year.
Today, he
chose to hold court
on the rubbles.
I know
bad things would happen.
I want to report to Magistrate.
Come back.
This kid.
I want to report to Magistrate.
You little kid!
Go away!
Magistrate,
some one broke my father's leg.
Come back with me.
Come with me, now!
Wait.
Who broke your leg?
I fell down.
So my leg was broken.
It has nothing to do with others.
Let's move!
Did you
break your leg yourself,
or was it broken by someone else?
Magistrate.
If you don't tell Magistrate,
they won't stop.
Don't be afraid.
Speak up boldly.
The magistral office will capture them.
What can the magistral office do?
Even if the office was burnt down,
the code still exists.
Magistrate,
the magistral office wasn't burnt down
by someone.
The fire was caused by the lightning,
and it burnt for two days and nights.
But no one came to put it off.
No one!
Because people didn't know
what the meaning was
to save the magistral office.
Go.
What is this about?
Father!
It is a fact.
Maybe you would feel better
when you think
it was caused by people.
Lan Ward
is divided into various parts,
and every part has a leader.
To announce sovereignty on the rubbles
seemed like an unimportant act,
but it was quite necessary for him
to popularize the Tang Code
that he believed in so much.
I think Magistrate Di
has preparations.
Miss Cao,
you are really Huaiying's confidante.
[Bupo Medicine Shop]
Fool!
He did it by himself.
This foot is large.
It is really big.
Why is he measuring the feet?
Can he really perform autopsy?
Though Mr. Hu looks crazy,
in Lan Ward,
he might be the only physician
who has never made a mistake.
These could be a man's feet.
He is indeed a man.
You,
come here.
There is a red spot on the neck.
Did you see that?
Where is the red spot?
Was it caused by a poisonous needle?
No. He is...
He cut himself.
Look at this cut.
Let me show you. Here.
He is...
in this way,
this way,
and this way.
Does he show any symptoms of poisoning?
He must have bled a lot.
You see this cut.
You...
Does he show any symptoms of poisoning?
Why do you shout at me?
Who are you?
- Wait.
- I perform the autopsy or you do it?
- You stand aside.
- Mr. Hu.
Mr. Hu,
please don't say that.
Didn't I introduce him to you?
He is Magistrate Di,
the new officer of Lan Ward.
Is the red... spot
poisonous?
Open the door!
Coming.
You don't touch anything here.
Open the door.
Anyone answering?
Coming.
Don't rush me.
Open the door. What are you doing inside?
Coming.
Don't rush me.
Open the door.
Coming...
Are you dead? Hurry up.
Open the door.
Wait...
Coming.
You are slow.
We called you so many times.
What were you doing?
Where is the medicine?
Don't speak to Mr. Hu like this.
Sorry.
This man is insensible.
Mr. Hu.
You are sensible.
What are you looking at?
Go!
You brat.
Since the 20th year of the Zhenguan era,
there were records one after another
depicting the stories of Heiyan
in the local documents
of Lan Ward.
But this group of Heiyan bandits
was totally different from the one
the Imperial Court had annihilated.
They didn't do anything
against the court,
but they controlled all businesses.
Gambling places,
pubs,
and entertainment houses.
Sometimes, they also committed murders.
Although their businesses
covered all the Lan Ward,
they were restricted
within this place.
They were just some survivors of Heiyan.
They weren't reconciled to failure
and gathered together
to do some disgraceful business.
Mr. Hong,
please look at this.
The last time Heiyan showed up in Lan Ward
was at the beginning of the fifth year
of the Gengshen cycle.
[*Gengshen means a specific year]
The fifth year of the Gengshen cycle
[within a 60-year cycle.]
is the year when the Penglai war occurred.
All of them went to Penglai
to loot gold and weapons.
That war
was lethal to Heiyan.
They took risks,
but their leaders were killed.
Heiyan thus suffered a great loss.
Heiyan has disappeared.
God helps Huaiying.
I am really afraid that he would tumble
over the same thing as his father did.
Huaiying
should be the literary name
of Magistrate Di after his enlightenment.
Why is it carved on the toy
of his childhood?
It was a long time ago.
I have already forgot
these old things.
I should put it aside.
[Ying]
By order of Magistrate Di,
we will count the heads in Red Pavilion.
Madam, I haven't slept all night.
Are you new here?
Fine.
Qiu Yue,
that night,
in this room,
what did you actually do?
I did nothing.
That night, I...
Do you know?
The blood on his wrist
was almost dry.
But the ink on the table
was still wet.
You said that when you came in,
he was already dead.
Then, you called for help.
Yes.
You are lying.
I'm not.
You tampered with the crime scene.
What were you looking for?
Did you
imitate Biyu
and kill Li Tao?
Speak!
Magistrate Di,
let me tell you a story.
As a kid, I traveled with my father
on business trips.
But one time,
we encountered a sandstorm.
Run!
Hurry up...
Sandstorm!
Run!
I thought
it was a normal sandstorm.
But unexpectedly,
the violence of the sandstorm
was far beyond everyone's imagination.
Father,
where are you?
Among the whole trade caravan,
only I survived.
Help.
That day,
five trade caravans passed by,
but no one intended to save me.
Wait.
She is dying.
If you give her water,
all of us could die.
Let's go.
Actually,
no one would really care
about a dying girl.
But then,
I met Biyu, who was passing by.
She saved my life.
After that, I came with her
to the Red Pavilion.
Miss Qiu Yue...
Magistrate Di,
I haven't finished yet.
You don't have to pity me.
I told you these
not for your sympathy.
This is Lan Ward.
This is the desert.
Maybe,
this is my fate.
Lan Ward
is a place for insincere,
predatory,
and adaptable people.
Green Dragon Gang and Black Tiger Gang
are just like this.
So,
I came with Biyu
to the Red Pavilion
just to...
To live.
That's not shameful.
Until one day,
I met Mr. Li.
He was nice,
gentle,
and kind.
He was so elegant
and was like a lotus under the sunshine.
He was gentle to everyone.
He would give beggars money.
He would dissuade bullies when he saw
them picking on the weak.
He would go to the well
and stop the fights every day.
He was so elegant
that he was not like an earthly man.
So,
you fell in love with him.
No.
He loved me.
He once proposed to you,
but you refused him.
Why would you do that?
Didn't you want to leave
the Red Pavilion?
I'm living a good life here.
I don't want to marry a rich man
and be his concubine.
You doubted that
Mr. Li had true feelings
for you.
No need for that.
After I objected to his proposal,
he took a different attitude
toward me.
Mister.
Get out!
Mister!
You get out!
Without my permission, you can't come in.
What's the matter?
Mister!
Although he became indifferent to me
and estranged me,
I always remember
the first time we met.
You are like a lady from a painting.
As Li Tao
took a different attitude toward you,
you became unhappy
and gave up your feelings for him.
Until...
I know what you are thinking about.
Mr. Li
died.
I am a prostitute
and want to take advantage of this
to live a better life.
Is that wrong?
I must admit
that up to now,
what you said
is true.
However...
You want to say
that I lied that night.
Yeah.
I lied.
What is it?
You killed Li Tao
and you searched for something
in the room.
Right?
When I entered Mr. Li's room that night,
he was indeed dead.
I have told you
that Mr. Li said
he was writing a will.
If I have this will,
I can prove that I am innocent.
Then, where is the will?
I haven't found it.
Perhaps,
there is no will at all.
I know
you suspect that I killed him.
I know all of you suspect me.
You believe
that I wanted to imitate
Biyu's legendary story.
But the only good man in Lan Ward died.
If you think I am the murderer,
you can arrest me.
I am a humble girl anyway.
It doesn't matter.
Remember.
What I said just now
was all truth.
You...
Believe it or not.
Magistrate.
A guard is missing.
Just missing
a dishonest and untrustworthy guard.
It's quite normal.
Nobody would notice.
When did he disappear?
It seems like
two days ago.
That day, Mr. Qiao
wanted to eat fruits from Yonglin Shop.
So I asked him to buy some.
He never returned
after leaving.
You can say that Mr. Qiao wants it.
Business as usual.
Magistrate,
I've seen him.
It was not the first time
Wei Cheng ran away after losing money.
Before that,
he would leave for some days.
When he got enough money,
he would come back again.
He is good at fighting.
I'm willing to hire him.
As far as I know,
he won't kill a man in the Red Pavilion
and burn his own bridge.
Magistrate,
Wei Cheng is a gambler.
I know that.
So do I.
What Mr. Po said is true.
I have also heard
of this person.
If he really killed Li for money,
he wouldn't come back
this time.
Find him.
Yes.
Magistrate,
you've finally come.
this is Wei Cheng's house.
It seems that
it hasn't been inhabited for a long time.
He must have come back.
Where can he be?
Come out.
Cross cut.
Qian Hao.
Why did Qian Hao want to kill you?
Like...
Like you.
But I'm not the murderer.
Do you know Li Tao?
Mr. Li?
I do.
He is dead.
You killed him?
No.
I didn't.
Mr. Li was my benefactor.
I once stole his property
but got caught on the spot.
Mr. Li didn't accuse me.
Instead, he lent me money
to pay off debts
at a northern gambling den.
You were afraid
that you couldn't pay back his money,
so you harbored a murderous intent.
Where did you get
those drugs that numb people?
How did you kill him
and stage it to look like a suicide?
I didn't kill him.
You didn't?
Though I am addicted to gambling,
I am not a bad guy.
I would rather be killed by people
from the gambling den
than harm Mr. Li.
I am a scoundrel.
My death is not to be regretted.
Wei Cheng!
What did he mean by saying that?
What is "like us"?
Qian Hao
is also looking for the murderer.
Why?
[*Anhua: A undisclosed and illegal reward]
Someone offered Anhua.
Hire someone to commit murder
and to seek revenge for Mr. Li.
Your son Li Tao...
I am...
Governor Li…
When the tulip withers,
the spring
is about to end.
He is my only son.
Let's go.
Magistrate, where are we going?
To see Governor Li's father.
Magistrate,
all gangs in the city
are looking for the murderer
and they killed many innocent people.
The one who faces the greatest danger
is Qiu Yue.
How much is the Anhua?
It even makes Qian Hao tempted.
Then we should ask
the person who offered the Anhua.
[Li Mansion]
You can't get in.
Get out of the way!
Magistrate.
Governor Li!
The master suffers the loss of a son.
Di Renjie
is here to offer condolences.
Take it easy.
The magistrate is investigating a case.
- The magistrate is investigating a case.
- Magistrate, you can't do this.
Please make no fuss.
Magistrate, you can't get inside.
You can't get in there.
Governor Li!
The pain of losing a son
is very profound.
I have also suffered the loss
of loved ones.
I can relate to you.
But you were an official for many years.
How can you know the law and yet break it,
and hire someone to commit murder?
Get out.
Governor Li,
you were an official.
You brought welfare to the local people.
The populace there loved you.
Your son Li Tao
treated people kindly
in Lan Ward.
He lost his life,
and all the people in the city
are mourning for him spontaneously.
But what about you?
What you did
is an insult to all of this.
Someone killed my son
and staged it like a suicide.
I want the murderer
to pay with his own life.
Governor Li,
we cannot confirm
if Qiu Yue is the real culprit.
Please trust me.
I will definitely bring the murderer
to justice.
Di Renjie,
I have contracted tuberculosis.
I don't have time
to wait for your justice.
So,
you offered Anhua
and let Qian Hao kill
the murderer for you.
Not just Qian Hao.
Whoever
kills the murderer doesn't matter
as long as my son
is avenged.
This is my only way.
Governor Li,
innocent people
should not have been killed for no reason.
I will definitely
seek for justice
for your son.
[Li Mansion]
It's on fire!
There is fire!
Someone come and put out the fire!
The house is on fire.
Come and put out the fire!
Someone come here!
Mr. Hu.
There is fire.
He is still alive.
Corpse.
Li Tao's corpse.
Water...
Magistrate, the fire inside
is pretty much out.
Mind your steps.
[Promissory note]
They are all promissory notes.
Mr. Hu's promissory notes
for borrowing money from others.
Black Tiger Gang.
Magistrate.
Mr. Li and the others have come.
Let me see.
Qian Hao.
It must be Qian Hao who set the fire.
Qian Hao?
Why did he intend to kill Mr. Hu?
Let me tell you, Miss Ma.
Since Governor Li offered his Anhua,
all the gangs in the city
want to claim the Anhua.
Black Tiger Gang
is the largest gang in the city.
So, they won't tolerate others
finding the murderer before them.
I was asking
why Qian Hao intended to kill Mr. Hu.
Is Mr. Hu the murderer?
Mr. Hu must have discovered some clues
and he refused to give them to Qian Hao.
So...
Mr. Hu discovered some clues?
Even I, as the magistrate, was unaware,
but Qian Hao knew this before me?
What's the matter?
There's a traitor among us.
That explains why.
Magistrate,
in this place,
almost everyone is involved
with those gangs.
What should we do?
Qiao Tai!
Come down here if you are available.
Okay!
Magistrate.
Arrange some men
to clean up the backyard.
The magistral office was destroyed.
If Mr. Hu is not seriously injured,
let him rest in the backyard.
Understood.
You guys come with me!
Coming.
Come over and give a hand.
Okay.
You come, too.
Yes.
Magistrate,
did Qian Hao really do this?
Not sure yet.
Magistrate.
How is Mr. Hu?
I think
he is fine.
He was probably just overcome by smoke.
Go to the backyard.
Understood.
Let's go.
Okay.
This place has so many gangs.
Mr. Li,
why are you sure
this
was done by Qian Hao?
I think
the Black Tiger Gang
is the leading one in the Lan Ward.
So the speculation arose from my mind.
But I think
Qian Hao would not be so reckless.
Why?
These gangs
always fight each other.
They often get sick or injured.
As is known,
Mr. Hu is not only a coroner
but also one of best physicians
in Lan Ward.
Harming him
could provoke anger of the populace.
Magistrate,
could it be that
Mr. Hu actually has found out some clues?
Magistrate,
Mr. Hu woke up.
He woke up?
He woke up.
Everyone,
please wait here for a minute.
Okay.
Alright then.
Rong!
Something has gone wrong.
Things are about to get serious.
Magistrate,
is Mr. Hu awake?
He woke up for seconds
but fainted again.
Did he say anything?
He told me
some very important clues.
Mr. Li,
please take care of things here.
Arrange more men
to protect Mr. Hu.
When he wakes up,
you should record his words carefully.
I have a more important thing to do now.
I'll leave
this place to you.
Okay.
Mr. Li,
my mother is at home alone, I should go.
Please take care of this place.
Goodbye.
Bye!
Mr. Li,
I should go, too.
Thanks for your efforts.
Goodbye.
How are those two persons?
Mr. Li has been staying
in Mr. Hu's pharmacy.
Secretary Bai didn't come out
after he got home.
Then it's him.
He has been here for a long time.
He must be waiting for someone.
Someone is coming.
Only you come here?
Only me.
I'm here to tell you...
Qian Hao?
Okay. I know.
He left.
You ungrateful traitor!
Please allow me to explain.
Shut up.
With people like you,
the Lan Ward is corrupted to the core.
Magistrate, I...
I...
You take him back first.
Yes.
Where are you going?
Qian Hao!
You can't take
Governor Li's Anhua.
Why would I listen to you?
Show me what you got
if you want me to listen to you.
Come on!