[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 7]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
You want me to be an official
or a villain?
I...
I'll tell you.
I'll tell you...
Li Han has escaped.
He's a prisoner with shackles.
How could he escape
from your heavily guarded quarry?
Kill him.
No...
I released him...
Why did you do this?
Someone paid to release him.
Who?
I really don't know.
The person wore a long robe,
a bamboo hat
with a black veil.
The person didn't say a word,
just paid me
[Li Han]
and pointed at Li Han's name on the list.
I'm engaging in an offense punishable
by beheading.
Not asking for details also benefits me,
so I won't look into it.
So you're a repeat offender.
No...
It's a momentary lapse of judgment.
When did he leave?
Ten days ago.
But he's indeed
been suffering from leprosy.
That's not a lie.
Even if I don't let him go,
in a few days,
he'll be dead.
Qiao Tai.
You better watch out.
Someone will come to handle you later.
Magistrate,
you said before
that Li Han was sentenced
because of Yinlian's grudge.
And Li Han was released
before the unidentified body was found.
If the unidentified body is really Xu Kai
and there are similarities
between the two cases,
Li Han's motive to kill
because of his grudge will be confirmed.
Then the person who paid for his release
is probably his accomplice.
You've improved a lot lately.
Based on the powder left
at the painting and calligraphy store,
the one who told us the body's identity
is also Li Han.
Now that I think about it,
Yinlian was out of fear at that time
because she recognized
that man was Li Han.
After returning to the city,
go to find a beggar.
Long hair and rags cover his face.
He's disabled because of leprosy
with an unique appearance.
Since his appearance is unique,
finding him shouldn't be hard.
It's time for me
to see Mrs. Yinlian's real face.
Real face?
This Mr. Bazong Ma Rong just met
is so powerful.
[Mingyue House]
Ms. Cao, Magistrate Di is here.
Okay.
Magistrate,
sorry to keep you waiting.
That's all right.
Magistrate, I guess
you haven't rested for long.
I'm so confused,
so I can't fall asleep.
Is this about the murder of Mrs. Yinlian?
Yes.
This case
is very complicated.
It involves romantic entanglements.
And I still can't make sense of them.
I don't know how to start.
So you're not here to hear me sing.
Are you
asking for my help?
I think
you've experienced a lot of romance
and seen a lot.
A chat with you
may clear up my doubts.
Love and romance are simple.
It's strong while being together
and intense while missing.
Separation creates sorrow.
Infatuation creates suspicion.
Passionate creates jealousy and hatred.
In fact, these feelings
are depicted to the fullest
in Mr. Teng's poetry.
His poetry is soft and sentimental.
The feelings portrayed are more vivid
than an ordinary woman's thoughts.
I really don't get it.
Why don't
I play something for you?
Good.
Thank you.
What are you doing here?
Waiting for Di Renjie.
Why do you always call him ''Di Renjie''?
Call him ''Magistrate''.
We're different now.
You have to know the rules.
Tai,
you're becoming
more and more like Mr. Hong.
You're getting old.
You're so wild.
I'll see who dares to marry you.
Fine...
Magistrate Di.
I'm waiting for Magistrate Di.
Okay?
Then don't wait.
He left early in the morning.
Left?
Where did you go?
I don't know.
Then why are you talking to me?
Where are you going?
Mr. Hong.
Stop minding me.
How could I stop minding you?
Come here.
Mr. Teng is too self-critical.
It's so worrying.
How is Mr. Teng?
Let us see him.
Magistrate is here.
[Teng's Residence]
Isn't this Mr. Di?
Magistrate.
Come with me.
Magistrate Di.
Magistrate.
Everyone, Mr. Teng can't meet you today.
Please go back.
Magistrate, you're just in time.
Actually,
Master has been locked himself
in Madam's room for a whole day
without food or water.
- We're worried.
- Madam's room?
Yes.
Mr. Teng and Mrs. Teng share
different rooms?
You don't know.
In fact,
when composing poems,
Master tends to work day and night.
Fearing that it would affect
Madam's normal rest,
they always lived in separate rooms.
It is here.
Master,
Magistrate is here.
I can wait.
Well...
I'm here
to think of my late wife.
I don't want to be disturbed.
Sorry for keeping you waiting.
I beg your pardon for the inconvenience.
There are no outsiders here.
Just call me Huaiying.
Is this Mrs. Teng's work?
It's thick and delicate, just like her.
The old mountains stand,
yet my bonds no longer cling.
Embarking on a journey to Chang'an
to enjoy the late spring.
A tree draped in pear blossoms,
a stream beneath moonlight.
I wonder who
owns this sight tonight.
What a nice poem.
These
are all left by Yinlian.
Under my influence,
she also liked
poems and literature.
She occasionally wrote under my guidance.
Just a hobby.
Not good enough to be remembered.
Being close to orchids
will let one get a special fragrance.
If the poem is passed on to the world,
it's also a fine piece.
Seeing the things remind me of her.
It's hard to calm my heart.
Huaiying,
Let's talk somewhere else.
Magistrate.
This poem,
Yinlian asked me to revise it,
but I couldn't finish it.
Now,
I've finished it,
but it's too late
for her to see it.
Magistrate.
Have a seat.
Back in the court,
I was the Secretary General
of the Right Guards.
This horsewhip
is what I used back then.
Ever since I left office,
I've kept it with me.
It commemorates
my years of military service.
Magistrate,
when are you going
to sentence me to death?
Mr. Teng,
have you ever heard of Li Han?
Li Han?
It's an unfamiliar name.
I've never heard of it.
Where did Mrs. Teng like to go
when she went out?
Usually,
I only write behind closed doors.
I don't know
where Yinlian went.
Before
Mrs. Teng married,
she was courted by Li Han.
Because he was a nuisance,
Mrs. Teng framed him
for robbery
and sent him to jail.
But a few days ago,
someone paid for Li Han's release.
Because Mrs. Teng framed him,
he suffered for nothing.
His hatred for her
is obvious.
On the day
Mrs. Teng was killed,
you
lost your mind in an attack
of madness.
In the study, someone
found
an evil spirit there.
Li Han
was just
in the residence.
The evil spirit rumored to have appeared
was probably him.
So
in this case,
he's the prime suspect.
If so,
this Li Han is the one who killed Yinlian.
The person who paid to release him
was equally guilty.
Who is that person?
If we find Li Han,
the truth will come out.
Thank you, Magistrate.
In fact,
here's the thing.
Whenever Master wrote a poem,
he stayed behind closed doors.
So
no one
dared to disturb him.
When Madam had nothing to do,
she'd return
to the Lai family
to visit her sister.
The two families...
I wonder
when was the last time
you met Mrs. Yinlian?
I don't like Yinlian,
so we had no contact.
Does ''her sister'' here refer
to Ms. Lai Er?
Yes.
She is an old girl
and has never married.
It's sad for her.
Had Mrs. Yinlian and Ms. Lai Er
always been seeing each other?
Not really.
I've heard they used to have a deep grudge
against each other.
It was only recently
they began to see each other again.
Ever since that day
when you were flirting
and behaved in a coquettish way,
I swore I'd never see you again.
After all, they're blood sisters.
How can there be any real grudges?
That's true.
[Teng's Residence]
Magistrate, mind your step.
Close the door.
Why are you here?
Bazong's dice
are very helpful, right?
Not bad.
Where are we going next?
Help me ask that friend of yours.
Where women in the city
usually go
to meet their lovers?
No need
to ask.
He already told me.
Why did he tell you that?
You don't have to care that.
Let's go, I'll take you there.
Welcome!
Waiter, two guests.
Come... Please come inside.
I don't want to drink or enjoy songs.
I want to ask you something.
This is a place
for drinking and enjoying songs.
For information,
you've come to the wrong place.
We're investigating a case.
I'm Di Renjie.
Magistrate Di.
I'm an ignorant woman.
I've heard
you have a room
exclusively for lovers to date.
Is that true?
This is a place for men to have fun.
We don't serve adulterers.
As long as you don't violate
the Tang Code,
I don't care
what you did.
Yes...
But
we really don't do this kind
of business here.
If you ask me again,
I can only answer truthfully.
To be frank...
I do
have a room....
Magistrate,
please also think for me.
Where is it?
It's been reserved by one for long.
By whom?
The person was veiled in black.
I don't know who it is.
Show me.
I don't think that's appropriate.
It seems
Bazong's dice don't work here.
Officer...
I didn't say
I wouldn't take you to see it.
It's upstairs.
Please come with me.
Come. Please.
It seems a county magistrate's power
is no more than the person in charge.
This is it.
Don't blame me, Magistrate.
We're doing business.
We have no choice.
You really don't know
who the person is?
I really don't know.
She never let me clean this room.
Since it was rented out,
even I haven't come in.
How about the one she met?
I don't even know.
You can go down first.
Magistrate.
Magistrate,
there's writing here.
[Mountains]
The old mountains stand,
yet my bonds no longer cling.
This is...
Mrs. Yinlian's handwriting.
Why is a flower here?
You went to all this trouble
just to tell me
that it's all about Kai.
Xu Kai.
Magistrate.
That's called tampering with evidence.
They knew how to have fun.
It's all me.
In his whole life,
he's loved to draw me the most.
[Xu Kai]
There are four sisters in the painting.
Before Yinlian married,
she and her three sisters lived
in her family.
If this is not the story
of Yinlian and me,
what else could it be?
This is
our story.
Does this screen have a name?
The Four-panel Screen.
You are the one on it.
You and Xu Kai were having an affair
because you love each other.
I want to hear you
tell about Li Han.
I don't know him.
Back then,
it was here
that he was taken down by the servants.
You told me about it.
I forgot.
Can't I?
Well, look who's in this portrait.
Xu Kai.
It's Xu Kai.
He's dead?
How did he die?
Who killed him?
How do you know
he was killed?
Who killed him?
It's him.
It must be him.
Who?
It's me.
I got you into this.
It must be I who got you into this.
No.
It's Yinlian.
Shame on you.
You're so flirtatious.
You're already married.
Why do you still pester Mr. Xu?
That's between me and Mr. Xu.
I don't need you to judge us.
Besides,
Mr. Xu never liked you.
Nonsense!
Mr. Xu does like me.
He just doesn't want to say it.
He...
Sister,
how long will you lie to yourself?
What do you know?
No.
It's that bitch, Yinlian.
If it wasn't for her,
how could you have died?
What he likes is me.
It's me.
You knew
that Xu Kai was having an affair
with Yinlian.
No.
They were not.
Xu Kai was Yinlian's lover.
The one in the paintings is all Yinlian.
Why are you
deceiving yourself?
Get out.
You all get out of here.
No.
This is not Yinlian.
It's me.
Xu Kai only draws me.
This is not Yinlian.
It's me.
It's time to ask your friend
for a third favor.
Three dice, three favors,
all done?
The first one
was used in the quarry.
The second one
was at the entertainment house.
For the third one,
I need you to spread some news for me.
Spread some news?
What news?
Yinlian isn't dead.
Do you guys know?
What?
Mrs. Teng was saved.
Mrs. Teng is not dead?
Yes.
She was so badly injured,
but she was saved.
Who's the doctor? So amazing.
Did you hear that?
Mrs. Teng didn't die.
Right.
Li,
did you hear that?
Mrs. Teng.
Mrs. Teng is still alive.
Great.
It's so lucky.
Mrs. Teng is still alive.
Mrs. Teng was stabbed so many times,
but she was still saved.
Oh, my goodness.
You have no ideas.
The stabs even disfigured her body.
[Teng's Residence]
Yinlian,
I've come to see you.
Li Han.
Come with me to the magistral office.
I'm not going with you.
I'm not going.
Don't kill him.
I'm not going there with you.
I'll never go there with you.
I...
Help.
Yin...
Lian...
Why did you kill him?
Yinlian,
I've avenged you.
Wait a minute.
Stop.
Magistrate, what's wrong?
I heard
Mr. Teng killed that crazy man Li Han.
Right.
Mrs. Yinlian's revenge is finally avenged.
Unfortunately,
Mr. Teng doesn't plan to stay either.
I saw the family packing up
to leave Penglai.
[Mingyue House]
Magistrate, welcome.
Is Ms. Cao here?
She's taking a bath.
Magistrate,
Ms. Cao has told us.
Whenever you're here,
just come in.
Please.
Magistrate,
it's you?
It's me.
Still worried about the case?
The case is solved.
Congratulations, Magistrate.
The case's been solved.
Why don't you
see any joy on your face?
Magistrate?
Yin...
Lian...
A piece of her hair was cut off.
Di Renjie.
Mr. Hong.
Where's Di Renjie?
Stop calling him ''Di Renjie''.
Call him ''Magistrate''.
What's in your hand?
Wood from the woodwork store.
They said
Magistrate Di ordered it.
It took them a long time to find it.
Red cedar wood.
[Teng's Residence]
Magistrate.
- Magistrate.
Magistrate, welcome.
- One moment, please.
- Magistrate.
I'll ask Master to come out.
Wait a minute.
Stop.
Huaiying,
you're here.
I'm here.
It's you who helped me
get my revenge.
Thank you.
You should've heard about this.
I'm leaving Penglai soon.
Where will you go
after leaving?
It's just
remote countryside.
I'm not good at anything
except writing poems.
Since
Heaven has left me to live on,
I can't do anything but write poems
to remember Yinlian.
This screen,
who painted it?
An unknown painter.
I don't remember.
So
I won't bother you anymore.
You're on official business.
Sorry for not seeing you off.
Slow down.
Magistrate.
Human sandbags?
They lack training.
Your back...
When I was in the army,
I broke the rules
and was punished with flogging.
Magistrate,
if these paintings are not helpful,
tomorrow,
I'll return them to the shopkeeper.
Slow down.
Thank you.
Huaiying.
Come...
Let me show you something.
Look.
This is...
Do you remember the flower soil
at the crime scene?
This soil
was found on the soles of your feet.
I didn't think the rock powder
and the flower soil would blend into one,
so
I went to check it out.
What did you find?
Bimanzi.
[*A poison.]
You know what it's for, right?
Of course I do.
Qiao Tai,
prepare the horse.
I'm going to invite Mr. Teng.
Before he leaves Penglai,
I'd like to ask him
to meet Mrs. Yinlian
one last time.
Mrs. Yinlian is lying in the autopsy room.
I just want him to come
to the autopsy room.