[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 29]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
Where are we
going?
No rush.
You will see him soon.
I solved a case before.
The criminal was called Diao Xiaoguan.
He was from Heiyan.
He also had an eagle.
His Heiyan tattoo
was on his tongue.
Maybe he wanted to hide it.
If he really wanted to hide it,
wouldn't it be better
to hide it in his heart?
What can be
better hidden
than an invisible mark?
Take it slow.
Sand
is difficult to walk on.
Aren't you in a hurry?
No.
I'll meet him anyway.
A little earlier or a little later
makes no difference.
Well,
let me tell you a new story
about Chu Lei.
He has been rebellious since childhood.
Later on,
he got to know a group of people
as rebellious as him.
They were all criminals.
They had
no mercy.
They tempered their will and their hearts
with frenzied killing.
He hated this world
because the first one that discarded him
was his father.
From then on,
it took all his strength
just to survive.
Such things
happened again and again.
He was always the only one
that survived in the end.
Killing
had become a habit.
In his heart,
besides sneering and mocking,
there was nothing but cruelty.
In the end, there was one thing
that had replaced everything else.
That was rage.
Magistrate,
between what you said and what I deduced,
is there any difference?
Yes.
In my version,
those who beat Chu Lei
were not soldiers from the border army
but Heiyan.
The one
he aspired to
and joined.
When did you find out about it?
After Chunyu's case
was solved.
You asked me
why
the Chu Lei in Chunyu's case
is so much different
from the Chu Lei you described.
Because everything you said
was made up by you.
The Chu Lei you described
is not Chu Lei at all,
but you.
You guys
are not human
but dirt.
Lin Fan.
You don't like this name, do you?
Your name is Di Ying,
right?
My brother.
[Lin Fan]
[Di Ying]
You guessed it all right.
My brother.
Di Renjie, you really live up
to your reputation as a brilliant sleuth.
You must have a lot of questions for me.
Who is Lin Fan?
Lin Fan is not important.
He was merely a soldier I had killed.
What's your name?
Heiyan only kills those
whose names are known to it.
My name is Lin Fan.
I'm begging you.
I can't join Heiyan.
I have a family to support...
What about Chu Lei?
Chu Lei
was just like you surmised.
He was just a good-for-nothing.
A scholar
who joined the army for a woman.
When he came to Lanfang County,
he was imprisoned.
He died a sudden death in prison.
It was I
who took care of his remains.
Why?
Because I wanted to become Lin Fan.
If I took care of his remains,
I would be Lin Fan.
Whether these two people
were good or bad is no longer important.
It's been such a long time.
A mere verbal statement is no guarantee.
I talk about them,
and they just become that way.
No.
How do you explain my wound?
You stabbed yourself.
You are very clever.
You've succeeded in clearing
my suspicions about you.
What about the weapon?
You hid it away.
Later on,
you put it by Cao An's bed.
Cao An is my witness.
There are so many
human-shaped sculptures
in your mason's shop.
It was not difficult
to deceive Cao An.
Lin Fan?
You killed Lin Fan?
There's something
I've been meaning to ask you.
Was it fun
to hide by my side?
That was really fun.
Besides,
it was very safe.
I also want to tell you one thing.
You let all the people in the county
wear Heiyan's mark.
The idea was brilliant.
You forced me
to meet you.
Are you really forced out by me?
Where is Cao An?
Renjie,
if you didn't come to Lanfang County,
I might spend the rest of my life here
as Lin Fan.
I love the old Lanfang County.
The strong prevailed
and the weak kept their place.
That's what Lanfang County should be.
The strong abide by the law,
and the weak
live and work happily.
The Code
maintains the order here.
That's the way I like.
The Code?
What is the Code?
Can you protect them forever?
You saved Wei,
Qiuyue, and Wangdong.
As a local official, you bring benefit
to the people in this place.
You will get promoted and leave.
What about them?
What about the next magistrate?
Will he still uphold the Code?
I don't think the previous magistrates
did so.
When a man is in power,
power goes to his head.
The Code.
The Code is nonsense.
The law of the jungle
is the way of the world.
The water in Lanfang County
is very precious.
You are right.
Ying.
Before I came, Lanfang County
was Lanfang County.
After I leave,
Lanfang County
will still be Lanfang County.
I know
it's very difficult
to change Lanfang County.
I just
want to do
what I can.
Your choice
is to be the guardian
of the old order of Lanfang County.
As for my choice,
it's hope itself.
There is good and evil in the human heart.
Evil
makes people kill each other.
It is goodness
that allows people to coexist.
The Code
guards
the goodness in people's hearts.
Nonsense.
This is the nonsense
Di Zhixun taught you!
It doesn't matter who taught me.
Choose what is good and hold fast to it.
There is nothing wrong with it.
Shut up.
If these lowly people
have good in their hearts,
will I succeed?
I just told them something unreasonable.
What was the result?
You saw it all.
You changed Lanfang County
beyond recognition
just so I could see it.
You changed it into a living hell.
Was it me who changed Lanfang County
into a living hell?
It was their hearts
that had changed this place
into a living hell.
I want to tell you
that all this
is the way of Heaven.
I finally understand
why our father kicked you
out of the house back then.
What did you say?
I often remember
how you left home back then.
You're no longer
a member of our family.
Maybe this is the only way
to keep him alive.
Very pitiful.
Say it again.
Our father kicked you
out of the house back then.
He was right to do so.
Ying,
you are really pitiful.
Is this the Rain Dragon Sword
Di Zhixun gave you?
It is as useless
as you.
I will definitely
arrest you today.
I'm not guilty.
I have never killed anyone.
I have no Heiyan tattoo, either.
You spent your life
advocating the Tang Code,
but it cannot convict me.
Nor can you save Cao An.
How about this?
You kill me yourself
to prove the Code is useless.
Isn't it wonderful?
Kidnapping
is also against the Code.
How do you know she is unwilling?
Oh right.
Didn't she tell you anything
between us before?
Renjie,
is this the best you can do?
If you still don't go all out,
I'll cut Cao An's throat.
Thickheaded.
Today,
I'll let you see Di Zhixun
in the netherworld!
You
wanted to arrest me.
In the end,
you delivered this fatal blow.
Who is guilty,
you
or me?
The way of Heaven
is not wrong.
You
are not wrong.
Di Zhixun
was not wrong, either.
It is human nature
that is wrong.
Where is Cao An?
I thought
the Di family
was just where I came from.
I didn't expect
it was also
my destination.
[Young Di Renjie]
I also want a sword.
Just like you.
[Young Di Ying]
You can't be like me.
You should follow Father's words.
Study hard in the future
and be a person he considers useful.
Come.
Ying, slow down.
Come here.
Wait for me.
Is Bingzhou
your hometown?
There is a special custom in Bingzhou.
The corpses are left in the suburbs
for birds and beasts to eat.
No need to worry in this world.
Make light of life and death
as well as the corporeal body.
This is the mood of the music.
My hometown
is just a place
in my memory.
[Ying]
Skylarks miss their home
the most.
No matter where they are taken,
they will do whatever it takes
to fly back home.
The bird will be able to fly home
if we cure it.
[Ying]
Nonsense.
This is the nonsense Di Zhixun taught you.
I just told them something unreasonable.
Was it me who changed Lanfang County
into a living hell?
The water in Lanfang County
is very precious.
To meet you.
The Code is nonsense.
Why?
That all this
is the way of Heaven.
If you didn't come to Lanfang County,
I might spend the rest of my life here
as Lin Fan.
Huaiying.
Where is my sword?
That's weird.
Where is it?
Huaiying,
I'm asking you.
Where is my sword?
Is it here?
Why can't I find it?
[Lanfang County Magistrate's Office]
It is said that wearing Zhuyu
on the Double Ninth Festival
can drive away evil spirits
and pray for eternal life.
I don't know whether it is true.
Zhuyu is also called Wuyu.
[*plant Cornus officinalis]
It is spicy and can be used as medicine.
Just because
it is spicy and flavorful,
people think it is powerful.
So they pin their hopes on it.
Today is the Double Ninth Festival.
Will you climb the hill with us?
If you want to climb the hill,
go to the front office now
and take care of business.
There is a lot to do today.
Qiao Tai can't finish all of it.
Yes, Sir.
Miss Cao,
I've consulted a fortune-teller.
Both of your Ba-Zi
belong to the Yin category.
Easy to get into trouble.
The ninth month
is purely Yang in nature.
Perfect for weddings.
So,
please choose a date.
It's the ninth day today.
Should we be in such a hurry?
If you had been in a hurry before,
you wouldn't have to now.
Please choose a date.
Let Huaiying make a decision
for the matters concerning our wedding.
Please choose a date.
You choose.
You don't even ask me
what the date is for.
How can I choose a date for you?
The 20th day of this month.
The 20th day.
There will be a total solar eclipse
on the 20th day.
The extreme of Yin and darkness.
No way.
Let Miss Cao decide
on the date of the wedding.
I can't tell Miss Cao what to do,
but I can give you a piece of my mind.
Now that you and Miss Cao
have decided to get married.
You should hold the wedding
as soon as possible.
Why do you keep postponing it?
You are not sincere enough.
Fine.
I know you have a load on your mind.
But the dead is gone...
Enough.
You can't un-ring...
Let's not talk about this.
If you keep postponing it,
it can never happen.
I...
He taught you
that Bingzhou ditty?
He just taught me how to sing it,
nothing more.
So
I didn't mention it.
You should have told me.
It is written
in "Records of the Supernatural"
that there is a rare spring
south of Lanfang County.
It looks like the crescent moon
and is never dry.
Scoop a goblet of spring water
and the heart will be reborn.
One can realize
one's wish.
If there is nothing to worry about,
there will be nothing to be afraid of.
[Crescent Spring]
Scoop a goblet of spring water
and there is nothing to worry about?
We will know
if we give it a try.
The Crescent Spring
is not far away from us.
If we hurry,
it will take us five days to arrive there.
Let's go for a visit.
Just take it as a distraction.
Okay.
You are heading
towards Anxi this time.
The north of the mountains
and the south of the water are Yin.
You must be very careful on the road.
Don't offend
Buddhist or Taoist temples
or tombs.
Don't worry. We will be careful.
Mr. Hong,
don't worry.
They are going to the Crescent Spring
for sightseeing.
Why would they offend those things?
Take it slow.
Magistrate.
Be careful on the road.
Remember, don't go to Buddhist
or Taoist temples.
Mr. Hong,
when did you start to believe
in such things?
[Lanfang County Magistrate's Office]
Mr. Hong,
what's the matter?
The Magistrate forgot to take
the Rain Dragon Sword with him.
He forgot it deliberately.
If this is the case,
it is arranged by heaven.
It is to let them
overcome the tribulation.
[Loving Father,
Pei Shinian's Memorial Tablet]
[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Zhao Yun Library]