[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
Rent arrears
are just a small amount of money.
Why should Mr. Gu be disturbed?
That's very true, Commissioner.
It's just
that the cargo we found
is not a small deal.
It's the Modao.
Our Tang army's Modao
is well-hardened and extremely sharp.
By the Tang Code,
one can't keep them secretly
or sell them.
But the dockmaster confirms
that over the past six months,
there have been many shipments.
The shipment I found
included 100 Modao
and 80
Fuyuan Crossbows.
Mr. Gu,
I'd like to ask you,
where could an agent
sell such a large number
of weapons.
Since Wang Lide is at sea,
you should sail out to catch him.
Why come here to spoil
the Commissioner's fun?
I have already told you.
I've never hired such an agent.
Mr. Gu,
Magistrate Di said you hired that agent,
but where's the proof?
Miss Cao,
keep going.
Director Yi,
according to the Commission
of Maritime Trade's notice,
fifteen Gu's ships entered
and left the quay
last month.
There's a putty store at the quay.
According to their account book,
Gu's ships
that purchased putty last month
were more than 20.
Putty
is waterproof and seals leaks.
Exactly.
That means the Gu family
has both legal ships
and clandestine ships.
I'm afraid
there are also legal
and clandestine agents.
Magistrate Di,
the Commission of Maritime Trade
manages the quay.
Each ship is charged a 10% tax.
You said there are legal ones
and clandestine ones.
You're accusing me
of dereliction of duty?
Magistrate Di said
that Wang Lide works for me,
but the ship isn't on the Commission
of Maritime Trade's notice,
so it means it's a ghost ship.
Mr. Gu,
if your agents sell swords
and crossbows,
that's treason.
I'm innocent.
Please make a fair judgment.
Director Yi.
Magistrate Di alleges
that the Commission of Maritime Trade
is evading taxes.
This is no trivial matter.
I'll look into it when I get back.
I've just arrived in Penglai,
and I'm a little tired.
I think it would be best
to discuss this matter later.
Commissioner,
this is a very important case.
Can you ask Mr. Gu to stay here
so I can ask him thoroughly?
So do you mean
you're afraid that I'll protect them?
I wouldn't dare.
Tai, look.
Catch him!
Don't move.
Don't...
We're one of yours.
What are you doing?
- We're one of yours.
- We're on the same team.
- The same team.
- It's a misunderstanding.
It's a misunderstanding.
Magistrate!
Help! Magistrate!
Magi...
Magistrate! Help!
Stop!
Magistrate.
Don't push.
Move back.
Magistrate Di,
your men?
They are indeed officers
of the Magistrate's Office.
And these are...
These are Mr. Gu...
Di Renjie,
you've come out of the blue
to set me up.
You want to accuse me of taking a bribe?
Commissioner,
I have no such intention.
Step back.
Move back.
Di Renjie,
accept the imperial edict.
It's the Empress's
secret edict.
Di Renjie,
it's been found
that gold from Baekje has been flowing
into the capital
through Penglai recently.
Traitorous officials in the court
used it to buy people's support
and disrupt the market
with ill intention.
I order you to solve this case
within one month.
If you fail,
you'll be as guilty
as the gold smugglers.
Look. It's a ship.
Look over there.
- Look over there.
- A ship's coming.
There's no one on board.
Isn't this a ghost ship?
Let's go and take a look.
Ghost ship!
It's so strange.
This ship is going to crash into us.
Run!
Move aside.
Make way.
Hurry up.
Search carefully.
There's nothing here.
Search this crate.
Coming.
Search carefully.
Open these crates
and find out what's inside.
Commissioner Liu was on a mission.
Last night,
it was clear
that he wanted to blackmail Mr. Gu
and Director Yi
for personal gain.
But what did you do?
You've spoiled his plan.
Last night was really an accident.
It would never be my intention.
I told you
to be careful.
The Empress trusts no one now.
If an official in the court
is suspected,
he'll be demoted or even exiled.
You can't cause any more trouble.
This isn't the time for you to show off
with high spirits.
Yes.
Director Yi,
did you find anything?
Commissioner Liu,
I'm on my way!
this ship
is very strange.
It's indeed a ghost ship.
Really? That's weird.
Did you check the cabin?
Yes, I did.
There were sailors in the cabin.
All the living essentials are there.
The kitchen...
There's rice and flour in the kitchen.
If the pirates attacked
and killed the crew,
there must be signs of struggle,
but there are no marks
of sword or knife fights.
Could it be that they jumped
into the sea together
after being frightened?
What about the cargo?
It's just furs and herbs.
It's not worth much.
Do you know
where did the cargo come from?
That's hard to say.
Tell me.
Mohe,
Baekje, Silla,
Tamna, and Wakoku
all produce these things.
Judging from the style of that ship,
it's clearly a Tang's vessel.
I grew up by the sea.
I can't be fooled.
Commissioner Liu,
I don't have this ship
in my fleet.
That's weird.
An unclaimed Tang vessel.
The sailors on board
have also disappeared.
Is it
really a ghost ship?
Come here.
Let me show you something.
Take a look.
Can you recognize it?
These are
just two pieces of gold.
What's the difference?
Diff...
One is placer gold.
The other
is Baekje gold.
Magistrate Di,
you're truly discerning.
Placer gold comes from rivers
and has impurities.
It's this one.
The other
is fine in color.
If it hasn't been purified,
it must come from the mountains.
It's said
there's a vein in Baekje
that produces gold
in the shape of broad beans.
So it's the other one.
Commissioner Liu, if you suspect
this ship
is involved in smuggling Baekje gold,
please allow me
to get on board and inspect it.
It's the Commission
of Maritime Trade's job
to inspect ships arrived at the quay.
When did
the Magistrate's Office take charge?
Deputy Secretary Hou,
what do you think?
Why don't you let him try?
If he can't find out anything,
it can dampen
my classmate's spirits a bit.
Thank you, Commissioner Liu
and Deputy Secretary Hou.
The Empress asked you
to investigate smuggling.
Director Yi and Mr. Gu
know about the Baekje gold
but are playing dumb.
You're the only one
who's trying to be brave.
Commissioner Liu came
with a secret edict.
How can I run away from it?
One's missing.
Maybe someone escaped with it.
Magistrate,
what's this for?
Such wood rollers
are used to move heavy objects on ships.
Look,
the crate was probably hanging there.
After being chopped off,
it fell down
and rolled over there.
It was here before.
I'm jotting it down.
Magistrate,
they brought mushrooms on board.
No.
These mushrooms grew on their own.
To grow to this size,
it would take at least 30 days.
After deducting the ten days
of the incident,
the ship
came to Penglai about 20 days ago.
If this ship set out 20 days ago,
its country of departure
shouldn't be Mohe
or Wakoku.
It should be
Tamna
or Baekje.
I've asked the fishermen.
Baekje.
Baekje gold.
Why is the rice bucket
in a place where the ceiling is leaking?
It's already moldy.
Give me a hand.
Qiao Tai,
save him.
Magistrate,
Miss Yusu is here.
Greetings, sirs.
As you were.
Please begin the questioning.
Who are you? Where are you from?
I'm from Baekje.
There've been wars for years.
I know how to make rice cake,
so I wanted to stow away
on the ship to Tang to sell it.
Then, my brother
secretly took me on board.
Since the crew was armed with swords,
he hid me under the cabin.
The ship changed direction a few times
during the voyage.
It was strange.
We came across
a white island we'd never seen before.
The ship was stopped there for a few days,
waiting for something.
On the night of the incident,
the ship stopped in a vast whirlpool.
I didn't know what happened that night,
but my brother told me not to come out.
I waited until the next day
but couldn't move the boards.
The next day,
he couldn't move the boards.
No one answered,
no matter how he shouted.
If you hadn't saved him,
he would've starved to death.
Ask him if he recognizes this man.
Have you seen the man in the portrait?
Magistrate Di,
don't be fooled by this Baekje man.
On the route from Baekje to Penglai,
there's no island.
This alone
could prove
that this thin guy is talking nonsense.
Either he's mad due to hunger,
or he's lying on purpose.
Nothing he said is credible.
A crew member
has a weird tattoo on his body.
What's he talking about?
My brother said
all the crew members had it.
He said
he saw a weird tattoo
on one of the crew members.
His brother said all the crew had it.
Draw it.
Draw the tattoo you see.
Heiyan
is back?
Yes.
Back then, you were too young
to know.
This group of remnants
of the former era was arrogant
and was all over the state.
They were a major threat
to the late Emperor.
Then what year was it...
In the 14th year of the Zhenguan Reign,
they were eliminated successfully,
basically wiped out.
The remaining ones
went into hiding.
Who had the credit
for that annihilation?
Magistrate Di,
your father, Di Zhixun,
made a great contribution.
Commissioner Liu,
Di Zhixun's case
has long been reversed.
And
there's no direct evidence
proving that he colluded with Heiyan.
Di Zhixun was threatened at the time,
so he chose to commit suicide.
But
as you said,
Heiyan has been in hiding
for many years,
but it's making a comeback.
Magistrate Di,
do you think they're the ones
smuggling Baekje gold?
The evidence we've collected
is not enough to conclude that.
Then why don't you go and investigate?
Yes.
Commissioner Liu
is a government official,
so the way he speaks...
Don't take it personally.
I know little
about the past,
so I don't mind talking about it.
I just didn't expect
Heiyan to be involved
in this big case again.
We annihilated them in the 14th year
of the Zhenguan Reign.
Today,
we can do the same.
With our combined efforts this time,
we're sure to make it.
There seems to be someone over there.
Let's go.
How are you doing?
Thank you.
It's the fifth meal.
This silly guy may eat too much.
He doesn't understand our language.
Anyway, Director Yi told us to feed him,
so why do you care so much?
Are you sure he choked to death?
I went to check when I got the news.
No poison was found
in the food he vomited.
A starving man
can't overeat like that.
Who told him to eat like that?
Yi Pan.
Magistrate.
Mr. Hong.
Someone drifted onto the beach.
It looks like a crew member
from the ghost ship.
Dead or alive?
Alive.
Report to Commissioner Liu
and Deputy Secretary Hou.
Hold court trial.
Magistrate,
this man stinks to high heaven.
[Jin Sang]
We've poured some water on him.
You may go.
Yes.
Are you from Baekje?
Sir,
please redress my grievances.
Are you from Baekje
or the Tang?
I'm from Baekje.
My name is Jin Sang.
My ancestors have been trading
with the Tang for generations,
so I can speak the language of the Tang.
In that case,
tell me about your ship.
It's that agent
with the surname Wang
killed all the sailors.
Do you recognize him?
I do.
I do. It's him.
Wang Lide.
I saw him commit murder,
and I ran away.
He chased me to the deck.
I had no choice
but to jump overboard.
What were you carrying
when you jumped overboard?
A plank.
Wasn't it a gourd?
No,
it was a plank.
I was lying on the plank like this.
Luckily, I had a fishing hook with me.
I fished
every day
to survive.
It's truly unbelievable
that you drifted at sea for ten days.
You're saying Wang Lide killed others.
What would be his motive?
I dare not say.
Why don't you dare?
I'm afraid of being beheaded.
Don't be scared.
Commissioner Liu is here.
He'll redress your grievances.
Then I'll tell you.
One day,
on the aft deck,
I overheard Wang Lide
plotting with others
about a large shipment of gold
being smuggled aboard the ship
in a big crate.
Wang Lide also said
that this gold shipment
is related to many big shots in Penglai.
One of them is...
Tell me!
the shipmaster, Mr. Gu.
He owns the ship.
Nonsense!
- There is also an official surnamed Yi.
- This is a frame-up!
You're a vicious slander!
The magistrate also received favors
from them.
I think his last name
is Di.
I'm the magistrate
whose last name is Di.
Tell me,
is your crew from Heiyan?
What Heiyan?
We're just ordinary sailors
recruited by Wang Lide
to support our families.
That's not right.
Someone said
he saw the symbol of Heiyan on you.
Where is it?
If you don't believe me,
take off my clothes.
Come on, I'll show you.
How improper!
Adjourn.
I'll take over
this case.
Sir.
Search carefully.
Don't let him get away.
Shh.
Stop.
You...
Mr. Heiyan?
You know me?
Last time in the forest...
Wait for us.
Lady,
you just have to do it the hard way.
It's you.
Do you have wine?
Yes.
Can you play a Bingzhou ditty?
I haven't learned it.
Just play something.
Keep playing.
I shouldn't
have said those two words, right?
You should learn the Bingzhou ditty.
Don't talk to me like that.
Get out of here.
Stay out of my sight.
Get out.
I'll be back.
Mr. Hong,
who is that guy?
He's someone Master doesn't like.
Your father is in the Heiyan.
He is a traitor.
Don't you dare say that again!
What's wrong with it?
Isn't that true?
Don't you dare badmouth my father?
I fell asleep.
It's only been half an hour.
I'm so sorry.
Magistrate, it's my honor
to share your worries.
Your songs
can always
calm my heart
and
clear my mind.
That's good.
This case
is a tough one.
Lately, officials working for the court
have gathered here.
I can always hear the horses
carrying messages
passing through the marketplace.
Even if I don't go out,
I can still feel
the ceaseless turmoil seething.
You must be
worried about this.
Nice tea.
Rumor has it
that a gang
called Heiyan
is behind this.
Whenever you play the pipa,
I'm pleasant.
I have some business to attend to.
Farewell.
Please take care.
Why did you take me here?
Qiao Tai found out
that the guards said the ship
was haunted.
Haunted?
So I asked you here
to catch a ghost with me.
Huaiying, don't be ridiculous.
Commissioner Liu tortured Jin Sang,
but the ruffian insisted
that everyone from the Commission
of Maritime Trade
and the Magistrate's Office
is related to the gold.
He said I'm also...
Do you believe it?
Also,
Jin Sang's and the thin guy's statements
are consistent.
They both mentioned the island.
But Gu Mengbin said
there is
no such island
in the waters near Penglai.
Magistrate,
please go back.
This ship is haunted.
That's right, Magistrate.
It's really haunted.
After you.
Guanshi!
This is the Star-Orienting Board.
It's used to measure the stars
on long voyages.
I know that.
They need it
to determine the course.
Commissioner,
this is the chart they used
to smuggle gold across the sea,
starting from Baekje
and ending at Penglai.
Look,
there's a small island here.
It matches the thin guy's
and Jin Sang's statements.
This island may be the key.
You mean
the gold is hidden on this island?
The top priority
is to go there as soon as possible
to check it out.
There's no time to lose.
Although Jin Sang talks nonsense
and has slandered Magistrate Di,
someone in Penglai
must have something to do with the gold.
If word gets out,
I'm afraid
someone else will get there first.
Commissioner,
the Commission of Maritime Trade
has sent two warships to escort you.
I'll be by your side
and serve you.
Take him on board.
Yes.
Move it.
I'm leaving.
If a lark wants to fly higher,
it must go farther.
Go outside and take a walk.
Stuck in this cage,
you could only be a plaything.
Miss Cao An,
I'll see you again.
Are you looking for someone?
What are you doing here?
Commissioner Liu is going out to sea.
He wants you to sing on his ship.
It may be a risky trip.
Remember,
don't get on board.
Why do you say that?
Heiyan.
Find an excuse.
Don't get on board.
Thank you for reminding me.
How's it going?
It's red.
That's right.
Remember what the chart says?
When we're 50 li from Penglai
and sink ten zhang,
the sea mud will turn red.
So,
we're on the route
Wang Lide was once on.
We'll reach the island
in one day.
Attention, everybody!
A storm is coming.
Secure everything on board.
Tighten the ropes.
Lower the sails now.
Magistrate, it's dangerous out there.
Let's go inside.
Hurry up.
Miss Yusu,
what's wrong?
are you all right?
Miss Yusu.
Ma Rong, come and help.
Commissioner Liu invites you two ladies
to sing a song upstairs.