[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 23]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
Sir,
what's your name?
[Lang Liu]
I'm Lang Liu.
I'm passing through here on business.
May I ask
your name?
I'm a healer.
My surname is Lin.
I'm practicing medicine here.
Healer...
Healer Lin.
Fate has brought us together.
It's fate.
Please help yourself.
Excuse me
for my abrupt questions.
Where
are you from?
Where are you going?
What are you selling?
I'm
from
where I come from.
I'll go to the place where I will go.
I can't tell you
what I'm selling.
Healer Lin,
are you satisfied
with my answer?
In this world,
there are always secrets
to keep.
I can understand.
I often
have to
dig up secrets
from patients.
Sorry for asking you those questions.
It doesn't matter.
You are used to asking questions,
but I can't answer.
A merchant
does not always have everything.
A good healer
may not be a cure-all.
Well said.
There are some diseases
in this world
that even a good healer
can't cure.
But
I've always wanted
to cure
all incurable diseases.
You
aim for the highest.
But
the way things are these days...
Forget it.
I
wish you
all the best
in Qingchuan.
Well,
the noodles are too bland.
I'll add some salt for you later.
Add salt.
Add some ants for you.
What are you looking for?
Let me see
whether there are free ants in my bowl.
Your smile is so beautiful.
Your mother
must be beautiful.
Hurry up. What are you doing?
Coming.
Don't waste my time.
You are so slow.
Healer Lin.
Mr. Lang.
It's so late at night.
With everything
going on lately,
I'm a little upset.
I'll get some air.
The moon is clear tonight.
Healer Lin,
shall we...?
Forgive me for being rude.
Wei.
Do you also need salt?
Sit down.
Do you know
what Mr. Lang
sells?
He sells silks and satins.
He has booked
some of the best rooms in this inn.
The warehouses around the corner
also belong to him.
I don't think
he likes you very much.
Your stepfather...
No one likes me.
There are indeed
rumors in town
that something big is about to happen.
The mastermind
can't be Heiyan you mentioned, can it?
I'm
from where I come from.
I'll go to the place where I will go.
I can't tell you clearly
what I'm selling.
Are you satisfied
with my answer?
[Green Bird Inn]
Mr. Wei.
Magistrate Di,
do you really
enjoy the dark night?
Who are you?
You invited me to Qingchuan.
I'm not in the mood for that.
How did you know me?
You are the famous Magistrate Di
in Lanfang County.
Is there anything wrong
with me knowing you?
Are you
also staying in this inn?
I stay
wherever it stops.
Tonight,
we are here.
Tomorrow night,
I hope it can find a warmer place.
Healer Lin,
it's getting late.
Stalking people,
you could
get into an accident.
Mr. Hulu,
are you a native of Qingchuan?
So many years have passed.
I can't remember.
Do you know
something big
is about to happen in this place?
I've lived in Qingchuan
long enough.
But everybody ignores me.
They all think I'm a lunatic.
They just nodded
when they greeted me.
Only you
dare to speak to me.
Yes.
Perhaps
you think I'm one of your patients,
Healer Lin.
You are from Heiyan.
Have you
always been
so curious?
Magistrate Di.
Sometimes,
it's better
not to know.
I'm leaving.
He also owns a few warehouses
at the street corner.
The smell of blood.
Who are you?
I want to know who you are.
You are too nosy.
You are going
to die here today!
Don't fight.
It's not good to fight.
But nobody listens to me.
Kill him!
Look.
Sorry.
I'm exhausted.
I didn't know
you had such talent.
I have no talent.
I just used their own strength
against them.
Do you understand?
You don't?
Young man,
there are many things
you don't understand.
Learn them.
Don't throw things about.
You rely on this thing to make a living.
You better take good care of it.
[Green Bird Inn]
Mr. Wei,
what were you doing
driving the wagon
in the middle of the night?
Healer Lin?
What else can I do with my wagon?
Of course, I was delivering goods.
I run an inn.
I'm different from you healers.
You can make money
by moving your fingers
and saying a few words.
I can't do that.
This...
I
bought some sheep a few days ago.
They died.
Well,
there are just a few guests
in my inn these days.
The mutton has gone bad.
I could only send it back
and trade it for some money.
Oh, you don't know.
I have
a lot of worries.
People all say
I'm a miser.
Can I do without money?
I can't make a living.
Look,
I have enough on my plate with her.
What are you doing here?
Why are you in a daze?
Get some water.
Wash the wagon clean.
Do you know
what goods he was delivering?
Who would make deliveries
in the middle of the night?
Who knows what he was up to?
Mr. Wei,
who were you delivering the goods to?
What do you mean?
What were the goods
in the wagon?
Didn't I tell you?
Two dead sheep.
They weren't sheep.
Dead cows, dead horses,
or dead people.
Does it have anything to do with you?
Healer Lin,
look at you.
You also show up on various occasions.
Look at your clothes.
Your clothes
are inappropriate.
Let me take you to see something good.
Let's go.
Go.
Come.
Look,
the things in this room
were all left by the previous guests.
Take a look.
Look,
this piece of clothing was also left
by a guest.
This piece
is suitable for you.
You have good taste, Healer Lin.
This piece is great.
Look at the cloth. Look.
It's just a bit expensive.
This is my wife's dress.
It's not for sale.
You like
such things?
I can sell this.
I heard
she
had run away with someone.
Who told you this?
Who did she run away with?
Where did they go?
Have you reported it?
I report it?
Why should I look for her?
Whenever there was
someone rich
or good-looking in the inn,
she would flirt with him.
Sure enough,
she ran away with someone not long ago.
Well,
what kind of man is the guest
she ran away with?
How do I know?
Well, Healer Lin,
can you talk about something else?
Can you
save me some face?
Do you want this piece of clothing?
Do you want it?
Brat.
Brat,
what are you thinking?
Still waiting for your mother?
Your mother ran away with her paramour.
Still waiting.
Just wait for your death.
Did you hear what I said?
Mr. Wei.
Today, for Healer Lin's sake,
I spare you.
If you work hard,
I can offer you meals.
This robe seems to belong to that guest.
Your wooden hair stick
is quite special.
Was it given to you by your mother?
This was
made for me by my mother.
Your mother made this?
She said
poverty
was nothing.
One should be
beautiful every day.
A poor man can also
be dressed beautifully.
Tell me,
she will come back to pick me up,
won't she?
Yes.
As long as you are alive,
there is hope in everything.
This piece of clothing
belonged to the messenger.
Are you sure?
Yes.
I didn't expect
he would find it so quickly.
No rush.
Just wait.
[Shennong's Classic of Materia Medica]
Every healer in Lanfang County
has seen him.
None of them has a solution.
Well...
The Magistrate said
he should be fine.
In three to four days,
we will know the outcome.
It's just a possibility.
He is always like this,
mentioning but vaguely.
In three to four days.
I think in two days,
Ma Rong will die first.
She won't eat, drink or sleep.
No one can persuade her.
She is so stubborn.
Don't be anxious.
I'll go take a look.
Tai,
as we grew up,
if I messed up,
didn't you cover for me?
What's wrong with you this time?
You are just lying here,
ignoring me.
Are you really angry with me?
Wake up quickly.
What's more important
than us being together as a family?
What are you doing?
I told you I wouldn't eat.
Don't hang around me all the time.
This is for you.
I went out on that day
and bought this for you.
[Enlightenment Training]
What do you mean?
I know.
I know you look down upon me.
You all look down upon me
because I'm illiterate.
Because I always get into trouble.
You just look down upon me.
You are quite good.
You know kung fu.
You have a job
in the Magistrate's Office.
You can walk on the streets.
Most importantly,
you are always free as a bird.
You can go wherever you want.
You don't let anything get in your way.
You can do whatever you want.
You don't have to read people's faces.
Many girls can only imagine
what you have seen
and what you have experienced
in their lifetime.
With this,
you are a hundred times better
than those women who got married
at the behest of their parents
and live a life centering on family.
You travel a lot
and see a lot.
Your mindset
is naturally different from others.
In my opinion,
it is most important
for a person
to be able to support himself.
You are not supporting yourself.
Aren't you spending
the Magistrate's money?
I am an accountant
in the Magistrate's Office now.
According to the Code,
my salary is 300 qian a month.
I can afford
what I buy.
So,
when you buy those things,
you are spending your own money?
Aren't you the same?
Yes, indeed.
Do you believe in the Magistrate?
Of course.
So do I.
I believe
he will come back safely.
I also believe Qiao Tai
will wake up soundly.
Why don't we do something
instead of sitting here
staring into space?
[Enlightenment Training]
Boqi devours dreams.
Explain dreams in Qingchuan.
Greetings.
Magistrate Di,
don't make it so complicated.
I'm Lang Liu.
I'm passing through here on business.
Are you staying?
Healer?
Magistrate Di,
stalking people,
you could
get into an accident.
Dead cows, dead horses,
or dead people.
Does it have anything to do with you?
An autopsy is unnecessary.
Their bodies have been buried.
You are used to asking questions,
but I can't answer.
Why did you say "also"?
This gourd is empty.
Mr. Wei.
You are stalking me.
Something big is about to happen.
Heiyan?
You are from Heiyan.
Who would make deliveries
in the middle of the night?
[Lanfang County Magistrate's Office]
Mr. Hong,
I have some discoveries.
You know medicine.
Have you heard of this?
[Upas]
Upas?
It is recorded in this book
that upas is native to Tianzhu.
If the roots are extracted,
it can cause a person to fall unconscious.
The unconscious person's pulse
is stable
as if he is asleep.
It's quite similar
to Qiao Tai's symptoms.
Hong.
Hong, I have a solution.
Hong, let me go in.
[Young Hong Liang]
Huaiying, you can't go in.
My father...
My father must have been poisoned by upas.
That's why he has fallen asleep.
Just fumigate
with cypress leaves,
and he'll wake up.
Have you forgotten
how your father instructed him?
This really isn't heterodoxy.
Shut up!
Don't mention this again.
Today, I'll send someone
to check out the markets nearby
to see if they have it.
Maybe things will change.
If it's really caused by upas,
what Huaiying said is true.
The poisoned person
will wake up in three days.
There are no such records
in the medical book.
How do you know it?
Many years ago,
I was told
that this is not an art of healing,
but the vanquishing method.
Who was it?
♪Beacon smoke rises
from the vast desert♪
♪The moon shade waves
above the mountains♪
♪The flute blows away the cracked dream♪
♪Into the dark cold night,
the song I pursue♪
♪Where to hear the song
in the earthly life♪
♪The night is half bright
when coming back♪
♪Wild geese fly high at the frontier♪
♪West wind and snow
all over the foreign sky♪
♪Wild geese fly high at the frontier♪
♪West wind and snow
all over the foreign sky♪
Brat,
have you finished singing?
Come prepare the noodles
after you are done.
Healer Lin,
would you like a bowl of noodles?
Is it mutton noodles?
Well?
You
don't like mutton?
I
love mutton very much.
That's great.
What Mr. Wei has prepared for us is
mutton casserole.
Healer Lin,
my neck and shoulder
have been bothering me lately.
Could you
take a look at it
for me?
Okay.
Let's go
to the back room.
Magistrate Di,
I was wrong.
No.
I've searched everywhere.
Magistrate,
I'm an unrefined man.
Please be the bigger person.
Don't stoop to my level.
Solving big problems matters.
Heiyan
has really infiltrated Qingchuan.
Commander Xiao,
you haven't heard of them
for quite some time, have you?
That's true.
But I've heard of you.
If you have come to Qingchuan,
something really big is going to happen.
It's just that some people will die.
In Qingchuan,
it's common.
Magistrate,
you don't think
I have something to do
with Heiyan, do you?
That's not impossible.
Magistrate.
Magistrate,
my ancestor
Xiao Yiran
was a subordinate
of Mr. Cheng Yaojin,
also known as Mr. Zhijie.
They helped Emperor Taizong
to conquer the whole country.
His achievements in battle were great.
I always keep in mind
my ancestor's good reputation.
You are an offspring of Xiao Yiran?
Yes.
You...
I was in a very important position
in the army before.
Because I was too straightforward,
I was banished here.
I see.
That's why I became indolent.
I'm unworthy of my ancestors.
Magistrate,
you have come here.
Something big is surely going to happen.
If you don't tell me,
I won't ask.
There are around a hundred people
under my command.
I've brought them all here.
They are waiting outside the inn.
If you need me,
I'm
at your disposal.
Are your shoulder and neck
feeling better?
Yes.
Go back then.
If I need you,
I'll go to you at any time.
Understood.