[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 27]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
It's you.
I've already given you the drug.
Within four hours,
you can't move.
In Penglai,
Di Renjie failed to kill me.
I was lucky.
You killed Lin Fan?
He can't die.
He shouldn't have revealed my secret.
I have to somehow punish him.
Aren't you afraid I will
tell the Magistrate all this?
I hope you can tell him right now.
I'll let him watch me
take control
of Lanfang County again.
Why do you have to cross him?
Are you concerned about him
or me?
Do you remember
the Bingzhou ditty I taught you?
♪The land nurtures sweet osmanthus♪
♪Distant woods stand tall and strong♪
♪Leaves open,
unfolding brilliance in the wind♪
♪Flowers bloom, radiating moonlight♪
[Six hours ago]
Men are gradually enlightened.
Greed, anger, ignorance,
dislike, love, desire, hatred.
Add some.
Think about it.
Those tendencies
will kill you.
Everyone in their lives
has some of those tendencies.
The Magistrate should
take care of this issue.
If the Magistrate could do it,
the people who have died
wouldn't be so many.
- Exactly.
- Right.
Sir,
a pot of tea, please.
Okay.
Hurry. Let's go.
A bunch of fools.
Magistrate.
Sir, bring us another cup, please.
Coming.
What's with this?
I specially kept this for you.
No.
Blacksmith Zhao doesn't think
this meat is clean.
He discarded it
and she picked it up.
Really, they say the meat
is very delicious.
Fine.
Magistrate,
how was your talk with Lin Fan?
This man
is suspicious.
Very suspicious.
There's a good chance
he had something to do
with it.
Do you think
he killed them?
If he was avenging Chu Lei,
that was his motive.
But I have no evidence.
However,
killing Mr. Chen (the Sixth) and his wife
makes no sense.
Magistrate,
I heard a saying.
Men are gradually enlightened.
Greed, anger, ignorance,
dislike, love, desire, hatred.
A few residents
were talking nonsense just now.
How can you listen to their words?
Think about it carefully.
What they said makes some sense.
Look.
Mr. Chen (the Sixth) and his wife
loved each other very much
before they died.
It is known to all.
But in the end,
the couple
slashed each other
and their hearts were gorged out
after their death.
It corresponds to the word "love", right?
Loong
abused women in various ways
when he was alive.
But at last,
he died from self-castration.
It corresponds to the word "desire".
There is also Chu Lei.
He bore a grudge against Chunyu
out of love.
It corresponds to the word "hatred".
You see,
everything corresponds to those words.
Greed, anger, ignorance,
love, desire, hatred.
If these are the reasons to kill people,
in this world,
except for accomplished monks,
all men should be killed.
Take you as an example.
Greed.
But they say this meat
is really delicious.
[Xiao's Dyeing House]
Shopkeeper Xiao,
after Chu Lei returned from the military,
was there any change in him?
What change could such a man undergo?
Answer me.
Was there any change or not?
I don't know.
Oh right.
He came to me once after he returned.
When he heard Chunyu had been married,
he left without saying a word.
Look, wasn't he a coward?
Seems like you were just itching
for him to smash your dyeing house
in a fit of rage.
Take me to Chunyu's room.
[Loong's Meat Shop]
Loong.
Tai.
Well,
if Chu Lei
was really as cruel and unscrupulous
as Lin Fan said,
why would he
spare Shopkeeper Xiao's family
and only abduct Chunyu?
If he was taking revenge,
why did he kill Mr. Chen (the Sixth)
and his wife?
Wouldn't he vent his hatred
by killing everyone
in Xiao's Dyeing House?
There is also one thing
I can't understand.
I was once in the border army.
Under that kind of harsh environment,
even the most ordinary soldiers
had more courage
than ordinary people.
He couldn't be someone
who yelled inordinately in prison.
Besides,
if Chu Lei
was really as bloodthirsty
as Lin Fan said,
it would be very difficult to catch him.
So,
Lin Fan was lying?
Why did he lie?
Shopkeeper Xiao.
Magistrate.
This is not local paper, isn't it?
This is bamboo paper
produced in Tongkang Village.
You may not know it.
Chunyu married into the Lang family
in Tongkang Village before she died.
This
was a gift from them at that time.
After Chunyu had an accident,
as her life was uncertain,
they
ended the marriage
with a letter of divorce.
Our two families have had no contact
since then.
I was too careless.
I forgot
Chunyu's husband's family.
Let's go to Tongkang Village.
They are all dead.
It seems they have killed each other.
Were they also coerced to do so?
The farmer couple
and Loong
were all coerced by one man.
But how could
one man
coerce all the villagers?
I'll kill you!
Who are you?
[Mrs. Lang]
I'll kill him.
Greed, anger, ignorance,
dislike, love, desire, hatred.
Ignorance.
The saying came true.
Kill him.
Follow her.
Dead.
They are all dead.
It's mine.
Nothing.
Nothing inside.
Liars!
All of them.
If Chu Lei
was really as bloodthirsty
as Lin Fan said,
it would be very difficult to catch him.
So,
Lin Fan was lying?
Why did he lie?
Lin Fan.
You...
She is in the room.
You have met Heiyan,
but you never told me about it.
He taught you
that Bingzhou ditty?
He just taught me how to sing it,
nothing more.
Besides, I saw with my own eyes
he got shot and fell into the sea.
I thought he died long ago.
So,
I didn't mention it.
What about Lin Fan?
You were suspicious of him.
Why didn't you tell me?
Now it seems
I really misunderstood him.
It doesn't matter
if I told you or not.
You should have told me.
That way,
you wouldn't get in trouble
in the mason's shop.
Magistrate.
Lin Fan has woken up.
Nothing serious now.
Have a good rest.
Thank you.
Magistrate,
I've already changed his dressing.
Thank you.
How are you feeling?
Before last night,
I was almost convinced
you were the murderer.
Chu Lei is still alive.
He is Heiyan.
Where is he?
He stabbed you with a knife.
Do you still want to cover for him?
We were comrade-in-arms.
We were as intimate as brothers.
You said that to me.
Now you want me
to betray him.
I am asking you to uphold justice.
How is this betrayal?
What is justice?
Not to kill the innocents?
Who are the innocents?
When the nest is overturned
in a rainstorm,
no egg stays unbroken.
Chu Lei taught you this?
Magistrate,
it's not that I don't want
to tell you his whereabouts.
I truly don't know.
You are in my Magistrate's Office.
No one
is able to hurt you.
You don't have to worry about anything.
Magistrate Di,
since you found me,
I have been a dying man.
My life
is in your hands
as well as his.
What can I worry about?
Magistrate, I checked it.
There is no sign of a break-in.
Nor is there any sign of struggle.
None of these sharp objects
match
the cut.
Looks like the murderer
has taken the murder weapon away.
When Lin Fan was in a coma,
we checked his body.
There is no mark of Heiyan.
If he is from Heiyan,
there must be a mark.
It seems
I really thought too much.
Lin Fan
is just an outsider.
Why
are you keeping me here?
All the villagers in Tongkang Village
died an unnatural death.
Only you survived.
Before the truth is discovered,
you can only stay here.
Where is my son?
Is he dead?
Yes.
He is dead?
Mrs. Lang,
my condolences.
I need you
to tell me
what truly happened
in Tongkang Village.
What really happened
in Tongkang Village?
It was all because
someone posted
a notice on the well of the village
three days ago.
[The well has been poisoned]
It said
the well
had been poisoned.
Who posted this?
Their mouths will rot
- and they will die a horrible death.
- Who posted it?
I saw it in the morning.
There are people
drinking from this well every day.
If it was really poisoned,
no one in our village would survive.
Nonsense.
Help me with my bucket.
What's wrong?
Stomachache.
It's no use to go to the bathroom.
You need to detoxify.
Go.
Let's go.
In the beginning,
no one believed it.
They all thought
someone was teasing them.
What happened next?
Someone died.
On the second day...
It's drinkable.
Someone
died of poisoning.
What's the matter?
What's the matter with him?
Everyone, come and look.
What's the matter?
Wake up.
He...
He's poisoned.
Poisoned?
This water is really poisonous.
Wake up.
Later,
someone found a new notice.
The notice said
there was a crock
on a stump in the village.
In it was the clue to the antidote.
Antidote?
[Notice]
The clue to the antidote is in the crock.
Two days later,
if the population
of the village is halved,
everyone can be saved.
If more than half the people are left,
there will be no way to detoxify.
What should we do?
What are you doing?
Fatty, what are you doing?
I can't wait.
I want to get the antidote.
The antidote
could only save
half the people in the village.
What could we do?
His intention
was to let you kill each other.
On the morning of the third day,
some people were trying to get the crock.
Each with their own axe to grind.
They turned into strangers.
Everyone wanted to know
what was inside the crock before others.
Later on, at night,
someone ventured to take down the crock
secretly to save his life.
He didn't expect
some people had been lurking around there
for a long time.
They were biding their time.
What are you doing?
More and more people were coming
at the news.
The three-day period would soon be over.
No one wanted to be one of the dying half.
There was suspicion,
stalemate, and confrontation.
The desire for life
finally turned everyone
into a demon.
No more examinations are needed.
If they were really poisoned,
how could they have the energy
to fight and kill each other?
Magistrate,
the body of the first poisoned man
was found.
Over there.
Huaiying.
The body has developed herpes.
His fingers are black.
This is the symptom of arsenic poisoning.
He was poisoned by his wife
through arsenic wrapped in a Bing.
They just blamed it
on the water in the well.
The water in the well
was not poisoned at all.
Could everything be done by his wife?
An ordinary village woman
couldn't cause such a commotion.
A crock,
a notice,
and a rumor
caused the death
of nearly all villagers.
Absurd.
Now
do you still think
it was just Chu Lei's revenge?
The tragedy of the whole Tongkang Village
validates "Ignorance".
The ignorance
of all the people in the village.
Chu Lei is Heiyan.
He has gone far
beyond revenge murder.
He wants chaos
in the world.
Mrs. Lang,
have you heard
of Chunyun?
The daughter
of the shopkeeper
of Xiao's Dyeing House.
She once married my son.
Then she suddenly disappeared.
So we let my son divorce her.
Have you heard
of Chu Lei?
If I tell you
what happened in Tongkang Village
was because someone wanted
to take revenge on your Lang family,
do you believe it?
What?
Say it again.
Why?
Who wanted to take revenge on us?
Release Mrs. Lang.
Tell me!
Find a room for her
in the Magistrate's Office.
Yes.
Tell me who it is.
My son...
This is from Miss Qiuyue
across the street.
Have a taste.
Thank you, Magistrate.
It's not tasty?
Yes, it's tasty.
Aren't you curious
how the investigation
of the case is going on?
If you have found any clue,
you would tell me.
Almost everyone in Tongkang Village
was slaughtered.
There is only one survivor.
He still did it.
Just because Chunyu
married into the Lang family.
We are both sure
he didn't do it
just for personal revenge.
Do you know
where other members of Heiyan
are hiding?
In fact, Heiyan has no other members.
Heiyan
is Chu Lei alone.
Sure enough.
Previously, Heiyan
had just a few members.
But every member was very brilliant
and ruthless.
The gangs in Jianghu
were willing to submit to him
and be ordered by him.
In recent years, Chu Lei
dismissed his subordinates.
Some retreated into seclusion,
and some became leaders of the gangs.
Heiyan
seems insignificant.
In fact,
Chu Lei alone
is in control
of all the bandits in Lanfang County
and asks them to do evil.
Occasionally,
he also suppresses them.
What does he get
out of it?
He wants nothing from it.
He isn't doing it for personal gain.
He just wants Lanfang County
to be what he wants it to be.
Go on eating.
I want to meet him.
He will show up if he wants to.
If he hides away,
there is nothing I can do.
What you said to me today
has put you in danger.
I won't let you down.
Thank you.
From tomorrow on,
your task
is to protect Lin Fan.
Don't let anything happen to him.
[Lanfang County Magistrate's Office]
Mr. Qiao.
What a coincidence!
Thank you for your hard work.
I know
the Magistrate asked you to protect me
day and night
to ensure my safety.
Chu Lei and I were comrade-in-arms.
You don't have to worry.
What's going on?
People from the government are coming.
Let's go.
Let's take a look.
[Notice]
Really running wild.
Notice.
Starting from today,
Heiyan will recruit new members
in five days.
Five days later,
those who are not members of Heiyan
will be killed.
Greed, anger, ignorance,
dislike, love, desire, hatred.
Clinging to life
is also a form of greed.
The streets aren't safe these days.
Don't come out alone at night.
What's there to be afraid of?
Don't make me worry about you.
Someone really doesn't mind the cold.
Wait.
What's up?
Why are you dressed like this?
I feel very hot.
You feel hot?
You say you feel hot in such a weather?
Miss,
who said
I couldn't dress like this at night?
Do you think I can't deal with you?
- I'm telling you...
- Let's go.
Let's go.
Stay out of my sight.
Alright.
How is it?
They are really running wild.
I think
we should capture all the people
with the Heiyan tattoo.
I'll see who dares to get that tattoo.
What's your reason for capturing them?
They didn't violate the law.
Even if you want to capture them now,
don't you think it's already too late?
I can't just let them do it.
What kind of thing is this?
[Magistrate's Office]
I'll let him watch me
take control
of Lanfang County again.
I have to somehow punish him.