[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 6]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
[Teng's Residence]
Magistrate,
please sentence me to death.
Please rise.
Please tell me
what happened last night.
It rained heavily last night.
I was writing in my study.
Unexpectedly, I had an attack of madness.
I killed her.
It must be me who killed her.
Magistrate, please
don't be merciful
and sentence me to death.
Mr. Teng.
Rise, Mr. Teng.
The case is still unclear.
I beg your pardon.
I can't close the case and sentence you.
Why don't you go back and rest?
I'll
get to the bottom
of this case.
Please
sentence me to death.
Powder.
Calluses on fingertips.
Hold a pen.
The victim's
fingertips, ears,
and hairs
all found white powder.
Seven stabs.
Why both seven stabs?
Magistrate,
there's no smell.
Teng Kan confessed
to killing his wife due to madness.
We can close the case, right?
Then
why did the screen change for no reason?
Who left the footprints outside the window
and entered the study to move the body?
So many mysteries remain unsolved.
Close the case?
Di Renjie.
I know you're here.
You've won a lot.
I won it all on my own.
It's legal and all voluntary.
Also,
let me tell you something.
My case
is closed.
By whom?
The one who set the rules.
Still want to bet?
The Jianghu power
is not a child's play.
If you still want to bet,
let's do it differently.
What else do you want to bet?
Let's bet on the case you're working on.
If Di Renjie
can solve the unidentified body case
and find the real culprits,
then he'll be in charge
of the Jianghu I control now.
But if he can't solve it,
I don't want anything from you.
The government,
the Jianghu,
each minds its own business.
I accept.
If
you solve the unidentified body case,
you'll be in charge of Penglai County
after that.
Otherwise?
Here are three bronze dice.
For each dice,
I'll do one thing for you.
Within a 50-li radius,
you can ask anyone.
No one dares to refuse me.
I didn't expect you to be so decent.
Thanks.
Wait.
With three dice,
you can only do three things.
Don't try to trick me.
No ''otherwise''.
You're Di Renjie.
You can solve this case for sure.
You have to work hard,
Huaiying.
The money from betting
is not loot.
The boots I bought with it
are not loot either.
These
aren't dirty.
Where are you going?
To change my boots.
Ma Rong,
dogs
are good in every way,
but they love to eat shit.
If this problem is corrected,
dogs
will be good in every way.
Di Renjie,
what do you mean?
Thanks.
Mr. Teng, you've
been grieving too much
and had a relapse.
You should take care of yourself.
That's all right.
Magistrate, do you know?
20 years ago,
when I was in the capital,
I met your father a few times.
Your father
was an honorable man.
I still
remember his face and voice.
Back then,
I was the Secretary General
of the Right Guards.
My name was Teng Zhongyuan.
Wild geese flying south,
I grieve my snow-white hair.
On the lonesome frontier,
mountains and the moon seem so close.
The heavens and the earth fall
into the dark night.
Live and die side by side,
hoping for eternity.
Since my father passed away,
this poem has always been with me.
It's my good fortune
to meet his old friend today.
But
I don't know why...
You don't know why
I switched from the battlefield
to writing and romance, right?
Yes.
Yinlian changed me.
Ever since I married her,
I didn't want to get involved
in the battlefield anymore.
So I changed my name
and only wanted to be a mediocre man
who indulges himself in her charm
and writes love letters.
Now that I'm over 50,
I only want to spend the rest
of my life with Yinlian,
nothing else.
But now I've ruined it
all with my own hands.
I still have one question.
Why did you take the blame
on yourself?
Magistrate,
even if you don't sentence me,
Heaven will.
I killed my beloved wife
with my own hands.
I was ungrateful and wronged her.
Instead
of suffering every day
and living alone,
I'd rather die earlier
and meet Yinlian in the afterlife.
I
beg you,
for the sake of my friendship
with your father,
please sentence me to death.
I
thank you.
No, Mr. Teng.
Since I'm an official,
I should follow the laws.
You were once an official.
You should
know the Tang Code.
By the Tang Code,
if a patient of madness
injures a one's life,
the punishment should be lenient.
Your fame has spread far and wide.
People all over the county
have petitioned for you.
For all reasons,
I should acquit you.
My life is still alive,
but my heart is dead.
There's one thing
I'd like you
to tell me honestly.
You want to ask
about the Four-panel Screen?
Exactly.
Over ten years ago,
I saw that lacquer screen
by chance in a store.
Spring,
summer,
fall,
winter,
four lacquer paintings.
The story in the paintings
was the same as the one
between Yinlian and me.
We saw each other in a dream
and met each other on the balcony.
There are four sisters in the painting.
Before Yinlian married,
she and her three sisters
lived in her family.
Tell me.
If this is not the story
of Yinlian and me,
what else could it be?
Because of all these coincidences,
I decided that this lacquer screen
must only belong to me and Yinlian.
So I bought it.
But who would have thought?
A few days ago,
this wine cup
changed into a sword
and stabbed her in the chest.
Master.
Today,
I'm feeling fine.
No need to drink medicine.
But Madame herself asked me to...
Madam.
I've told you.
No need to drink medicine.
But
Madam said...
Madam said.
Madam said!
My lord,
drink the medicine.
Drink it and you'll be fine.
You drink.
I said no, no!
My lord,
it's fine.
I'm sorry.
Yinlian,
Alright.
This...
Screen!
The Four-panel Screen!
My lord.
Look, my lord.
How did this happen?
My lord.
Evil spirit!
An evil spirit possesses Master!
Master.
At that time,
my madness was getting worse.
I was afraid
that I'd kill Yinlian
as the screen predicted.
So I had the servants lock
up the screen in the storehouse.
In the end,
I still lost my mind.
Mr. Teng,
[Notice]
do you know the man in this painting?
Mr. Teng knows my father.
Why didn't you tell me?
Master had many friends.
How could I remember all of them?
Not to mention
that it was over 20 years ago.
But Teng Zhongyuan's ancestor
was quite famous.
Tell me.
It was the 13th year of the Zhenguan era.
Teng Zhongyuan's ancestor
was the Deputy Chief
of the Imperial Guards of Jiannan Circuit.
He had a promising career ahead of him,
but he fell ill with madness.
He had an attack at night,
broke into the barracks,
and killed 17 soldiers in a row,
causing a mutiny.
Teng Zhongyuan's ancestor
committed suicide to apologize.
From his pulse, it seems like
the yin deficiency concentrates
on the lower body.
The yang hyperactivity concentrates
on the upper body.
It's indeed madness.
If so,
the disease
will be passed on to the descendants.
Is this
why Teng Zhongyuan and Yinlian
have no children?
Before Yinlian married,
she and her three sisters
lived in her family.
It's just like what is depicted
on this screen.
Stop.
Stay away.
[Lai's Ancestral House]
This is Yinlian's ancestral home
before she married.
[Lai's Residence]
Now, only her
unmarried second sister lives here.
Everyone calls her Ms. Lai Er.
[Lai Er]
Ms. Lai Er,
this is Magistrate Di,
the magistrate of Penglai.
We're here today...
I know who you are.
I also know what you want to ask.
You're investigating Yinlian's murder,
right?
You know she's dead?
The great poet Teng Kan's wife is dead.
It's a big news.
Who can you hide from?
Why are you laughing?
Can't I laugh?
She deserved it.
It's retribution.
Retribution?
She was
a woman of easy virtue.
Magistrate, thank you.
With her beauty,
she was always flirting with people.
Many people had affairs with her.
Many also hated her.
But I heard
Mrs. Yinlian
was a woman of good character
and moral integrity.
She and Mr. Teng
were in deep love.
It was all just a disguise
in front of people.
Moral integrity?
She was never
a woman of moral integrity.
For what you said,
do you have any proof?
What proof?
Ask around, and you'll find out.
You said she has many lovers.
Can you
tell me
their names?
I don't like Yinlian,
so we had no contact.
How would I know
who she was having an affair with?
However,
there was a man called Li Han.
He had an adulterous relationship
with Yinlian.
He was her suitor before she married,
a mediocre and boring man
who surrounded her all day.
Afterward,
Yinlian got tired of him.
On day...
Go!
- Li Han broke into the house.
- I don't know you
and want to see you again.
Yinlian reported him.
Yinlian.
Look it up if you don't believe me.
[Xu Kai]
It's all me.
I think the paintings
are all by one person.
Are you familiar with this Xu Kai?
Xu Kai and I
are more than familiar.
In his whole life,
he's loved to draw me the most.
Where is
this Xu Kai now?
He got leprosy
and then disappeared.
That disease
has turned his pretty face
into a mossy mess,
so he can't face people anymore.
I wonder
when was the last time
you met Mrs. Yinlian?
When was it?
It's been a long time.
Ever since that day
when you were flirting
and behaved in a coquettish way,
I swore I'd never see you again.
I'm not like you.
Not like you.
In my life,
I only love Xu Kai.
If I can't get him,
I'll never marry.
I'm not like you.
[Lai's Residence]
When back to the office,
ask Hong to check Li Han's case file.
If what she said is true,
in the old case,
we may find Yinlian was involved.
Magistrate, we received a report
that a painting and calligraphy store
was stolen last night.
Magistrate, it is here.
This is my store.
[Notice]
[Xu Kai]
When did you realize
your store was broken into?
Magistrate,
it was today
around the Shen hour.
I had a few drinks last night.
[Chen's Painting and Calligraphy Shop]
I slept until afternoon
before opening my store.
The door was closed.
If the lock hadn't been broken
and there are many portraits,
I'm afraid I wouldn't have realized
anyone had come in.
[Notice]
Have you lost anything?
I've checked several times,
but nothing was lost.
I'd like to bring
the paintings and calligraphy,
especially those with notices,
back to the magistral office.
After the case is solved,
I'll return them to you,
okay?
Please go ahead.
[Xu Kai]
Xu Kai and I...
He's my lover.
Wait.
Powder.
[Notice]
Where is
this Xu Kai now?
He got leprosy
and then disappeared.
[Notice]
He's Xu Kai.
You went to all this trouble
just to tell me
that it's all about Kai.
He hadn't bathed for long
and even hadn't washed his hands for long.
Dressed in rags,
lived in distress,
and looked like a beggar.
Beggar.
Straw shoes.
Powder.
Hurry up.
Quick.
Quarry.
Huaiying,
what Ms. Lai Er said is true.
I found Li Han's case file.
He was sentenced to hard labor
at the quarry outside the city for theft.
So it's the quarry.
Do you think
Mrs. Yinlian looked strange?
How is it strange?
I can't tell.
Never mind.
Qiao Tai,
prepare the horse.
It's midnight.
Where are you going?
To the quarry.
I'll go with you.
Qiao Tai and I are enough.
I can help you.
The dice
are from Bazong.
One dice solves one thing.
In this region,
no one dares to reject him.
Stop it.
You last slept a long time ago.
Just two days.
That's not long.
I'll try it for you.
If it works,
thank him for me.
Huaiying.
Don't be lazy.
- Quick. Don't dawdle.
- Hurry up.
I'm talking to you. Don't dawdle.
Hurry up.
Didn't you eat?
Move!
Hurry up.
Quick.
What are you doing?
Hurry up.
Who told you to sit down?
Don't dawdle.
You. Speed up.
Hurry up.
I'll whip you. Don't dawdle.
Come here.
Magistrate Di.
This isn't an office.
I don't have food or wine to welcome you.
It's a mess.
If you don't have any problems,
please go back.
You're joking, Mr. Chen.
I'm here
to see a prisoner,
Li Han.
Do you have the provincial governor's
official letter?
Of course, I have.
However, Mr. Chen,
if you see the letter
but don't let me see him,
I don't need to tell you
what's involved, right?
Hurry up.
Qiao Tai,
fetch the official letter.
I have hundreds and thousands
of prisoners here,
so I can't remember everyone's name.
Someone,
go
and bring that Li Han to me.
Have you forgotten?
This Li Han
got leprosy
and was dead.
Right.
I forgot about that.
Magistrate Di,
it's not that I don't want you to see him.
You heard it.
He's dead.
Then take me to his grave.
This Li Han
has been involved in many murders.
I dare not to be negligent.
Mr. Chen,
thank you.
Follow me.
Mr. Chen, it's here.
Magistrate.
How long has he been dead?
Ten days?
20 days.
Fresh soil.
If I want to dig up the grave
and check the body,
Mr. Chen,
can you do me a favor?
Magistrate,
I'm afraid that's against the rules.
Yes.
I've gone beyond my authority.
I have a list of prisoners in my room.
If you don't believe me,
you can check it.
That won't be necessary.
Since I'm here and I've seen it,
I've
done my job.
I appreciate your understanding.
Let's go.
Thank you very much.
Magistrate,
what do we do now?
Magistrate.
Dig the grave.
Dig the grave?
The quarry is heavily guarded.
It's hard to get in again.
Let's wait.
In a while,
someone should be here to show us the way.
Magistrate.
Magistrate,
you know Bazong?
He's a friend of mine.
If that's the case,
it's not a waste for me to risk my life.
Magistrate,
you want to dig up the grave
and check the body?
Yes.
There's a path ahead
that leads to the mass grave.
Please
follow me.
Please.
Magistrate.
Dig.
Magistrate,
this place is heavily guarded.
If he didn't die of illness,
then Mr. Chen must have let him go.
This kind of thing
happens all the time.
I'm a petty man.
I don't know much about it.
Magistrate,
that's all I can do for you.
You're willing to take such a risk.
Is it to help me
or for Bazong?
Bazong helped my family a lot.
I should return the favor.
It's the right thing to do.
If you're a friend of the Bazong,
helping you
means helping the Bazong.
Thank you very much.
You're very welcome.
Magistrate.
Don't yell.
Let him look at the straw mat.
Is that Li Han?
I'll ask you again.
Where is Li Han?
You have no right to ask me.
The provincial governor's letter
doesn't work for you?
Do you have it?
I don't.
Then you're faking an official document.
You're faking... an official document...
If you don't tell the truth,
I'll kill you now.
I can not only judge
but also decide cases.
Maybe, in the end,
your case will fall into my hands.
I'll make sure you'll die for nothing.
Are you on earth
an official or a villain?
When I meet an official, I'm an official.
When I meet a villain,
I'll kill a villain.