[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 10]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
Quick! Lower the sails.
Lower the sails.
Harder.
Watch out.
Get out of the way.
Someone's fallen into the sea!
Help!
Hurry up.
We got into a trouble, Mr. Gu.
The rudder's been sabotaged.
We have a mole.
Hong Liang,
this is our first day at sea.
If anything happens to us,
present this letter to the court
as proof
to let the truth be known.
Last night,
it was stormy.
We have an evildoer on board
who destroyed the mast and the rudder.
But we don't know
who the evildoer is or why he keeps us
stranded at sea.
We've been separated from the fleet.
Last night,
we searched the ship
and decided
to consider it today.
You're being so calm.
I'm trying to help you
reassure the people.
There's plenty of water and food on board.
Help will eventually come in a few days.
As long as we don't lose our footing,
the evildoer on the ship
will be ferreted out.
That's true.
That piece just now.
I've never heard you play it before.
It's a new work by Hu Erniang
in the capital.
It's just with a new notation
that makes it easier to copy.
What did Hong Liang bring you?
What a big box.
Do you still have to deal with paperwork
on the sea?
It's the new clues
I've found in the past few days.
And some old books I found
in the library at the magistral office.
I read some of them yesterday.
They're quite useful.
Going out for a walk?
Sure.
It's just a precautionary measure.
Unexpectedly,
it comes in handy.
Can this pigeon
really deliver messages?
Sir,
when it gets dark,
we can determine the ship's position.
Magistrate Di,
please use the pigeon to tell the shore
to rescue us as soon as possible.
Where are you going?
Ms. Cao is seasick.
I'm going to the front cabin
to get some water.
Get some water?
Not a problem.
Sing us a song.
Yes, sing us a song.
Let me go.
Is this what you do as the Yulin Guards?
Mind your own business.
You pawn. You're dead.
Deputy Secretary Hou is coming.
Let's go.
Let's go...
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
Thank you.
What do you have in mind?
Wang Lide's chart.
So do I.
Don't you think
something is missing on the chart?
Wherever Wang Lide goes,
he'd observe the stars
and check with the marks on the chart
to avoid going off course.
On the night of the incident,
according to the thin guy,
Wang Lide anchored his ship somewhere.
If he was waiting for someone,
there must be a mark on his chart.
That's right.
But the chart we found
doesn't have it.
You did work for
the Ministry of Punishments.
Right on the nose.
How do we find the missing mark?
Deputy Secretary Hou and Magistrate Di,
Commissioner Liu has summoned you
to the cabin.
- Commissioner Liu.
Sit.
Bring Jin Sang up here.
Go.
I've been in the palace all my life,
but I'm not stupid.
I slept on this ship last night.
As the waves crashed,
I remembered my fishing skills
from childhood.
Commissioner Liu,
having gained Her Majesty's high favor,
you must have been gifted since childhood.
When a big fish takes the bait,
you have to use a harpoon.
You do it fast and hard.
Frankly,
I'm taking you to sea
because I've got Wang Lide's chart.
It's strange.
As soon as we set sail,
someone sabotaged the sails.
What's he afraid of?
I've been thinking about it.
I think he's afraid
that the gold could be found.
Or he's afraid
that I'll find out
who's
smuggling the gold.
This Baekje gold
has been flowing into the capital
for quite some time.
Such an attractive treasure,
passing through Penglai,
it's impossible that no one gets involved.
Coincidentally,
the Director of Maritime Trade, Mr. Gu,
and the magistral officer,
all the dignitaries of Penglai
are on board.
There are also two talented singers
who can play good tunes.
Do any of you know
where Wang Lide and the gold are?
Sir, you went to all that trouble
for this voyage,
so I should do anything.
But I really don't know
where Wang Lide and the gold are.
Neither do your men?
Commissioner Liu,
I'm just an agent under Mr. Gu.
I've always obeyed the law
and never seen Wang Lide or the gold.
But as far as I know,
this Baekje singer
was recommended by you.
Magistrate Di found a Baekje man
on the ship that day,
so I asked Ms. Yusu to interpret.
It seems
you've remembered something else.
Sir.
Back on the ship last night,
it was as if I had gone back to
half a month ago.
I seem to remember something.
What is it?
Sir,
one time,
Wang Lide drank and boasted to others
that he had a lover ashore
who is a singer.
Open your eyes and take a look.
There are two singers here.
Which one is it?
Sir,
I haven't seen her with my own eyes,
so I can't recognize.
However,
Wang Lide once said
that the singer
is a Baekje.
It seems to get foggy ahead.
Yes, it is.
It's getting heavier.
Report it now.
Watch out.
- It's getting foggy.
It's getting foggy.
Hurry up.
Get back to the cabin.
Back to the cabin...
Hurry...
Get back to the cabin.
Hurry up.
Hurry...
Quick.
Get back to the cabin. Quick.
How dare you!
You have a relationship with Wang Lide.
Why didn't you tell us about it?
Please spare me.
Please spare me, Sir.
Do you want to get us all killed?
Ms. Yusu.
Please spare me.
Don't be afraid.
Tell me
what Wang Lide told you
before he set sail.
He said he'd be gone for a month or two
and make a lot of money.
He'd come back to buy me out and marry me.
She believes such words from a man?
Who does he hang around with?
I don't know.
I don't know...
I really don't know.
Where's the gold?
I don't know.
Take your time and think.
We don't have better things to do
on this ship anyway.
Someone!
- Yes.
I really don't know.
I don't know.
No...
Get up.
No.
Magistrate Di.
An...
Save me.
An.
Magistrate Di.
Commissioner.
Deputy Secretary Hou said
you were up late last night dealing
with paperwork.
Did you find out anything?
While we're on the subject,
there's something
I'd like to ask
Director Yi.
Me?
the Commission of Maritime Trade
has four small ships
and one large ship
for harbor patrol,
right?
To guard the wharves and collect taxes,
this is the Director
of the Commission of Maritime Trade...
Only the big ship
can sail the seas, right?
So what?
A dozen days ago,
on the sixth day of the seventh month,
Director Yi led a big ship out in the dark
and didn't return until dawn,
right?
The same day as Wang Lide's incident?
Yes.
Magistrate Di,
Jin Sang isn't enough?
You're accusing me, too.
What's wrong with my sailing?
Those smugglers often dock
in the midnight in small ships.
I received a tip-off.
I work hard for the court.
How can you turn it into a crime?
I
just wanted to consult you.
Consult?
You call it consulting?
Why don't you ask me directly?
Just ask me
why it's such a coincidence
that I set sail on the same night
of Wang Lide's incident,
right?
Yes.
Why was it such a coincidence?
What a murderous heart.
Why don't you just say
I set sail that night
to see Wang Lide
and I also took gold?
Jin Sang said
the gold was in a big box.
There were more than ten people
on my ship.
If I hid the gold,
how could I hide it from the whole ship?
Commissioner Liu.
Commissioner Liu,
if you don't believe me,
we can get the answer
when we get back to Penglai.
Commissioner Liu,
it's getting foggy outside.
I think
everyone better return
to their cabins and rest
just in case.
We'll investigate later.
Mr. Gu,
is that you?
Magistrate Di.
Mr. Gu.
It's foggy. I'm just checking around.
What are you thinking?
It's really suspicious.
Yes.
Wang Lide
is the gold dealer.
He's a broker.
He needs a buyer and a seller.
The buyer must be from Baekje,
but what about the Modao?
Tamna and Silla
have been at war with Baekje for years.
Hasn't Baekje been conquered?
Are you saying
that the Baekje use gold
to smuggle arms from Tang?
Why not?
The fog has lifted. Come out.
Everyone come out to work.
Something happened over there.
It's Director Yi.
Director Yi!
Everyone, look!
It's really Director Yi!
Master.
Open the door.
From tonight on,
I won't sleep alone.
I'll sleep here.
Bai Kai, you sleep next to me over there.
You two sleep outside.
Yes.
Whenever I go out,
follow me every step of the way.
If any bastard dares to hide
in the dark to harm me,
kill him
as soon as he appears.
Suicide
or murder?
Commissioner Liu,
we're investigating now.
Everything's up in the air.
What are you doing?
You two,
one is a chief of
the Ministry of Punishments,
the other
is the magistrate appointed
by Her Majesty.
Please calm down.
If there's a murderer,
he must've taken advantage of the fog.
And he
must know Director Yi.
Otherwise,
he'd have resisted.
Shipmaster,
Gu Mengbin.
When the fog started,
sailors were on deck.
Mr. Gu and his attendant, Bai Kai,
were also on deck.
They didn't see Director Yi.
What's strange
is that I just found out
Director Yi set sail
at night ten days ago,
then he was gone.
Unfortunately,
we can't investigate now.
We'll have to wait until we return
to Penglai.
Magistrate Di,
don't you think
too many people are following me
on this voyage?
Sir, you mean...
They're all crying out to serve me.
Director Yi, Mr. Gu,
and two singers.
Didn't you
ask to bring the two singers?
That's because
when I first came to Penglai,
you interrupted me
before I could finish
enjoying a song.
So I didn't get enough.
But after we boarded the ship,
I realized that the Baekje singer
was not telling the truth.
I don't think
anyone on this ship
is telling the truth.
Let me repeat.
Magistrate Di, it was your first clue
that led us to the ship.
If you still can't find the culprit,
I'll have
to do it myself.
After Yusu,
I'll interrogate Ms. Cao.
Tai.
Tai, don't go.
Tai...
- Yusu.
- Tai.
Yusu.
I'm so thirsty.
I want some water.
Water...
She wants some water.
- Some water.
Some water...
Water.
Quick...
Here's some water.
Hurry up.
Open the door.
Tai.
Yusu, hold on.
Guard outside.
Hurry up.
Yusu.
Take it slow.
What's wrong...
It hurts.
Tough it out.
Let me apply some medicine to your wound.
Magistrate Di.
Mr. Gu,
I've brought you
Wang Lide's star leading board.
The size
of each star leading board varies.
If you want to restore
Wang Lide's observation,
you must use his board.
The six-finger board is too small.
Get a seven-finger board.
It's right this time.
Polaris on a seven-finger board.
Along Mr. Gu's direction,
Vega
is exactly flush with the top edge
of the three-finger board.
From one finger to 12 fingers,
there's always a board that matches.
Pollux and Procyon, two fingers.
Polaris, six fingers.
Vega, eight fingers.
Pollux and Procyon, two fingers.
That's weird.
What's weird about it?
Previously at Commissioner Liu's place,
I took a look at Wang Lide's chart.
Based on the marks on it,
Polaris,
Vega
and Pollux and Procyo
were also six, eight, and two fingers.
The mast is broken.
The rudder is also broken.
But we're still sailing
on Wang Lide's course.
We're being pushed by the currents.
It seems his course
also just follows the currents.
Let me go.
- Let me go.
- Are you mad?
Who gave you the balls?
I don't believe Yusu is an evildoer.
What a nice girl.
She's so kind.
Have you ever seen
such a kind-hearted evildoer?
Are you stupid?
Which evildoer will write
"evildoer" on the face?
Don't trust people too easily. You know?
Why are you all so cruel?
Look at her hands.
Don't you feel sorry for her?
Tai,
I stopped you
because I didn't want you
to get into trouble, okay?
If the Yulin Guards find out,
you'll get Magistrate in trouble again.
I don't believe he'll see her
in danger without trying to help.
What?
Shh.
Bai Kai?
Yusu.
I... I didn't tell them anything.
Don't kill me.
You won't stand it.
You must die for the sake of Baekje.
I didn't tell them anything.
You know too much already.
Don't kill me.
Stop.
It's you again.
So you're from Baekje, too.
Stop fighting.
Stop it!
Stop.
Stop there.
Stop. Stop there.
Stop.
Don't let him get away.
Stop there.
He's a Baekje.
So what?
Why are you pretending to be Tang?
Seems like Baekje is collapsing.
Nonsense.
If anyone slanders Baekje people again,
I'll fight them to death.
Who on earth are you?
I'm the captain
of the Huben Guards of Baekje.
Bai Kai.
Baekje's been at war with Silla and Tamna
for years.
You hide in Penglai
to smuggle armaments?
You let Yusu approach Wang Lide
to manipulate him, right?
Bai Kai,
don't resist.
Let her go.
Yusu is innocent.
She knows nothing.
Yusu,
I'm sorry.
No.
Wang Lide is smuggling gold
for you this time.
Where is he?
I don't know.
Bai Kai, put the knife down.
You'll only be charged with smuggling.
Wang Lide is just a broker.
He can't supply enough armaments.
There must
be a high-ranking official behind him.
Tell me,
who is that official?
Interesting.
Baekje will not die!
Long live Baekje!
Bai Kai.
No!
Over a day and a night,
significant incidents happened
on the ship.
Yi Pan is suspected to have been murdered.
Bai Kai resisted arrest and is dead.
Based on the measurement
of the star leading board,
we've been drifting
along Wang Lide's course.
The clues of the gold case
are becoming clearer.
Mr. Hong,
if you don't come to save us,
more and more people
are dying on the ship.
Don't kill me.
Yusu.
Qiao Tai.
Sis.
Don't be afraid...
Qiao Tai and Magistrate Di
asked for mercy for you
so you go back to the cabin and rest.
Why do you still want to board the ship?
Magistrate Di.
About Wang Lide and Bai Kai,
what else do you know?
Wang Lide was actually brought here
by Bai Kai.
I've never asked
about what happened between them.
Magistrate,
Deputy Secretary Hou wants to see you.
If you remember anything,
tell Ms. Cao
and let her come to me.
Yes.
Given the circumstances,
you must be very careful.
If there's nothing urgent,
stay inside the cabin.
If anything happens,
I'll come looking for you.
Yes, sir.
You wanted to see me?
I suggest you
putting a leash on Qiao Tai.
The Yulin Guards told me
he visited Yusu many times
while she was in custody.
I'm worried
that this will reach Commissioner Liu.
I see.
I always feel
that Yusu
has more secrets.
Sis,
now I don't think
I can trust anyone.
Magistrate Di is a Junzi.
You can trust him.
Do you think
Wang Lide is still alive?
You still care about that man?
I don't know where he is.
Is he suffering
like me?
What kind of man is he?
He...
He's a good-hearted man.
He said before he met me,
he liked gold the most.
But when he met me,
he thought nothing
was more important than me.
He may not look so good,
but with a delicate touch.
He can even play stringed instrument.
He's very good at it.
Really?
When we were together,
he always played
stringed instrument for me.
He said we switched roles.
I was the guest
and he was more like a singer,
which made me very happy.
Before he set sail,
he even got a copy
of music score from the capital
and played me a new piece.
Sis,
do you have someone you love?
I see
Magistrate Di does care for you.
In the night there are shocking waves,
but in the daytime it's calm and tranquil.
I know a thing or two
about the tides and the stars.
My grandfather was a military officer.
He used to go to sea for battle.
When the war was over,
he had nothing better to do
than to teach me these.
I was too young at that time
to learn these.
He scolded me many times.
This time, in Penglai,
I saw the chart
and the star leading board.
They remind me
of his teachings.
I've never heard you talk
about your grandfather.
You didn't ask me.
He passed
away long ago.
Stop.
I'm here to see Commissioner Liu.
You must have permission
from Deputy Secretary Hou.
Who's out there?
It's me.
I have important business.
Come inside.
Mr. Gu.
How dare you!
How dare you bring
out gold at a time like this?
This isn't Baekje gold.
This is Tang gold.
Sir, please take a look.
There's an inscription on it,
"Hebei Circuit".
Tang produces gold, too.
I'm afraid Commissioner Liu
won't appreciate this trifling gift.
When we get back to the shore,
I'll pay my respects.
You want me to accept your gift.
What do you want?
I understand.
You're here to investigate Baekje gold.
The Baekje gold flows
from Penglai to the capital.
As a shipmaster in Penglai,
I find it hard to avoid slanders.
Even if I say I had nothing to do with it,
people would say I did.
So were you involved?
I'm here
to report, Commissioner.
Who are you reporting?
Magistrate Di.
Di Renjie.
Exactly.
Didn't you see what a devil his man,
Qiao Tai, was?
Last night,
they forced Bai Kai to jump into the sea
rather than let you catch him alive.
Is that so?
There's been a spate of deaths
on the ship over the past few days,
indicating that
the murderer has nothing to fear.
He tricked everyone to board the ship
and then lured everyone here
to create a dead case.
But the case must be closed.
There must be a suspect
reporting to the court.
Mr. Yi is dead.
I've been thinking about it.
I think Di Renjie is the most suspicious.
Di Renjie has a close relationship
with the singer
from Penglai.
Don't you know that?
You mean
Ms. Cao who plays stringed instrument?
There are only two singers on board.
Ms. Cao is his confidante.
Yusu is Wang Lide's lover.
What if Di Renjie and Wang Lide
are in cahoots,
secretly controlling the gold smuggling?
When the thin guy from Baekje
was found on the ship,
why did Di Renjie rush to get Yusu
to be the interpreter?
He was afraid that the thin guy
would spill the beans.
Spill what?
Maybe he already did.
Only Yusu understood.
The secret is with Yusu.
So on the ship,
as soon as Yusu was taken into custody,
Di Renjie and his men got anxious
and sent Qiao Tai to visit her.
The Yulin Guards can testify.
Really?
Now,
he's put Yusu in Ms. Cao's cabin.
See for yourself if you don't believe me.
If the situation is critical,
Di Renjie will give himself away
covering up for Yusu again.
I'll wait and see.
If he dares to do so,
he
has everything to do
with the gold case.