[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 13]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
Magistrate Di.
Since you are so obsessed with the body,
you can take it away.
But I have to remind you
as the plague has been
going viral recently
and the body appears out of nowhere,
don't get bewitched.
The body...
When exactly was it found?
This morning.
If you intended to cremate it,
then why do you
wait until now?
Yesterday,
a boy found this body
in the swamp.
Why didn't the night patrol soldiers
find it?
Do you remember seeing
those soldiers being punished
when you entered the barracks?
They were supposed to patrol last night,
but these guys deserted.
I don't know where they went to goof off.
They even lost their knives.
They sneaked back early in the morning
and ran into me.
Of course.
I'll make sure
they remember their mistakes
from last night forever.
By the way,
this was found on the body.
Magistrate Di.
That's all the information I have.
Are you satisfied now?
[Zhong's Pawn Shop Ticket Stub]
Zhong's Pawn Shop.
[Eight]
From what I saw,
this barrack is very strange.
And those soldiers
from the Eighth Battalion
are full of obscene thoughts.
They must've visited brothels last night.
They deserted
but were caught red-handed.
Visited brothels?
I saw it with my own eyes with Qiao Tai.
They had erotic pictures
hidden in their chests.
After being whipped,
they were still smiling.
Saying
last night was so worth it.
That's because
you haven't been in the barrack before.
For a group of strong and vigorous men
around 14 or 15 years old,
it's normal to have desires for women.
Magistrate,
the pawn ticket
from Zhong's Pawn Shop in your hand...
Zhong's Pawn Shop...
I think I have heard it before.
Six months ago,
I pawned a gold bracelet
at Zhong's Pawn Shop.
The pawn ticket is right here.
[Zhong's Pawn Shop Ticket Stub]
In black and white.
I remember now.
This morning, those people
we ran into at the Magistrate's Office
are from Zhong's Pawn Shop.
That makes it all easier.
Let's go to the pawn shop and ask.
Let them help us investigate
who this dead guy is.
This is not a pawn ticket,
but a pawn ticket stub.
Pawn ticket stubs
are usually carried
by the pawn shopkeeper.
So
he is the shopkeeper
of Zhong's Pawn Shop.
This morning, those people said
their shopkeeper was missing.
[Mingyue House]
Magistrate.
What's on your mind?
Still thinking about the drama just now?
Feeling emotional.
How unpredictable fate is.
It's a pity.
But I've been thinking
Rain Master knew that he was cursed.
Once the mask is taken off,
it can never fall on the ground.
Then why did he
not tell the woman he loves earlier?
Rain Master is afraid
of losing this love.
He is afraid
once he confesses to her,
he'd lose this love.
This is what caused him
to lose the courage to confess.
Magistrate, please stand up.
Turn around.
What is love?
Isn't it
all about courage?
Lift your hands.
If he had told
the truth to his loved one earlier,
the result
could have been different.
At least,
he won't be stuck in limbo forever.
Penglai is by the sea and it's humid.
The rain will last for a season.
A well-fitting straw rain cape
is something you must have.
The collar is a bit small.
I'll fix it.
Miss Cao.
The straw rain cape is very good.
I like it very much.
Glad you like it.
So this is it.
Let me come back to you
when I have dealt with
all the trivial matters.
You see,
it seems to have grown.
But it will take a few more years
before it blooms and bears fruit.
All in good time.
[Loyalty and Righteousness
for All Generations]
Stabbed twice.
The killer could be two people
or the same person stabbing twice.
From the shape and depth of knife wounds,
the grip and strength
used to hold the knife
were totally different.
It doesn't seem to be done
by the same person.
The fatal stab was from behind.
Should have been attacked from behind.
Why is the body burned like this?
When I arrived,
the captain was asking his men
to burn it.
I snatched the body back.
And
I saw that the barrack
was short of food and clothing.
Send someone to check
the procurement documents of the barrack
to see if there are any mistakes.
The clerk has gone to deliver documents
to the provincial government.
When he comes back,
I will immediately have him verify it.
Magistrate.
Lin, the shopkeeper, is here.
It's him.
My condolences.
How did it become like this?
Please take me to the pawn shop.
Yes, sir.
I heard that Mr. Zhong
[Zhong's]
has been bothered by ghosts recently.
He seems to be weird all day long.
Did he really die?
Has he been possessed?
Everyone.
Excuse us.
- Excuse us.
- I saw it with my own eyes that day.
Absolutely true.
He turned into a bird
and flew away like that.
Turned into a bird?
You saw it with your own eyes?
Magistrate.
Tell me
what you saw.
Yes.
Magistrate.
That night,
it was raining heavily.
All the shops nearby were closed.
I was sitting outside the teahouse,
waiting for the shopkeeper
to come back and close up.
At this time,
[Zhong Fang]
Mr. Zhong walked out of the shop
in his normal clothes
and headed to the north.
Suddenly,
a gust of wind blew,
knocking down the umbrellas
outside the teahouse.
When I looked at him again,
his outfit
seemed to have changed
into
a birdman.
Yes, a birdman.
Turned into a birdman.
In the rain,
he flew away like that.
Magistrate.
If you don't believe
what I saw,
just ask around.
Magistrate.
Thank you.
Please.
Magistrate, this way.
This was found on Mr. Zhong.
Non-performing pawn again.
Magistrate, please take a look.
On this,
[A self-defense dagger]
no record of people, value, and property.
None.
This is the pawn Zhong Fang accepted.
Loss-making business.
How's Mr. Zhong
having zero business acumen
while Zhong's Pawn Shop
can achieve such a scale?
No.
Mr. Zhong did have business acumen.
And
he was very self-driven.
Twenty years ago,
when Zhong's Pawn Shop
just opened, he said
that he would make it
the largest pawn store in Penglai.
Pity.
We were almost there.
He changed later.
Over the past six months,
Mr. Zhong often seemed absent-minded,
spending less time in the shop
and neglecting business matters.
He even disappeared.
Every night,
he'd go out.
The next day,
he appeared.
Master.
You're finally back.
Go back and rest.
Especially the night before yesterday,
after he went out at night,
he didn't return the entire night.
At that time, I had a bad feeling.
Is there any regularity
about his disappearance?
Take me to his room and have a look.
Magistrate, please.
This is our master's room.
This is
a little messy.
It happened suddenly.
Without authority's permission,
I don't really
dare to let our men clean it.
About Mr. Zhong's personality,
he is introverted.
Magistrate.
Let me open the window,
so you can have some fresh air.
Shopkeeper Lin.
I will see for myself.
Magistrate, please help yourself.
Please help yourself.
Are all these painted by Mr. Zhong?
Yes.
I saw
it was him.
Magistrate, please help yourself.
Six months ago, Mr. Zhong
watched a shadow play
by a puppet troupe in the city.
After he came back,
he was too preoccupied
to feel an appetite
and spent all day painting these things.
Can I take this painting
back to the Magistrate's Office?
Of course you can.
Magistrate, please help yourself.
[Zhong's]
One last thing.
Magistrate, anything.
Has Mr. Zhong ever mentioned
Ying'er to you?
No, never.
Goodbye.
Magistrate, take care.
Move these big things
to the north room.
Arrange them properly.
Yes, sir.
Count them quickly.
I'm back.
Magistrate, you're back.
This
is listed by Hong.
Take a look
and see if anything is missing.
The rest of the properties
have already been prepared
and sent to the pawn shop.
What's the rush?
The directive says
to report for duty immediately.
You have to prepare early.
All right.
Hong, you make the arrangements.
Huaiying.
Haven't you
told Miss Cao about us leaving?
When are you planning to do it?
I know.
You are afraid
if you tell her about us leaving,
she won't go with us, right?
I will tell her.
I will.
Magistrate, you're back.
Hong.
If I seriously consider leaving,
it is not easy inside.
What is not easy?
Penglai...
I have had enough.
Especially the weather,
it rains and rains and rains.
I almost forget what the sun looks like.
When we arrive at Lanfang County
in the desert,
we're going to have a tough time
with all the wind and sun.
That will not make it easier.
Better than this humid weather.
Days after days,
I can't get my clothes dry.
Since we are definitely
going to Lanfang,
and we are still now in Penglai,
do well what is at hand.
Don't always be restless.
Particularly you.
Quickly count this.
Mind your own business.
[Pawn ticket]
This feather...
This beak...
And these clothes.
Exactly Rain Master.
That means
Huang Ying'er lives in the watchtower.
And the body of Mr. Zhong
was also found in the watchtower.
All of this
can't just be a coincidence, can it?
Magistrate.
Should we arrest Huang Ying'er first
and interrogate her slowly?
Huang Ying'er
is not an ordinary person.
That won't work.
Tomorrow morning,
I will go meet her.
May I ask if the Magistrate is here?
What do you want with Magistrate?
Miss Cao asked me
to deliver this improved straw rain cape.
And give it to Magistrate Di.
Magistrate said he doesn't need it.
Take it back.
Well...
Give it to me.
Where is Ma Rong?
I don't know.
Since she knew we were leaving Penglai,
her mind has already been elsewhere.
I don't know where she's now.
Thanks.
The straw rain cape is well woven.
It's quite comfortable for me to wear.
You give this to him
just to remind him
of coming and seeing you more often, huh?
Unfortunately,
he's busy with the investigation.
So I came on his behalf.
What?
You don't want me here?
He is the Magistrate.
As he's investigating a case,
he must be focused.
I'll wait for him.
No wonder he likes you.
If I were a man,
maybe I would fall in love with you too.
But I came today
to kindly advise you
to stop waiting.
Magistrate no longer needs
a straw rain cape.
Because soon
we will go to a place
where it never rains.
[Zhong's]
Shopkeeper Lin, what are you doing?
Step aside!
Put it back! Put it back!
Don't take it away! Don't take it away!
Move aside!
What's going on?
Magistrate.
Sir.
Zhong Fang has already handed over
this shop to our shopkeeper.
We're here to move some things away.
Go!
No way.
Magistrate.
Our master wouldn't do this.
This is his 20 years of hard work.
There's no way...
What hard work?
Signed and sealed. The sale documents.
Everything is here.
Take a closer look.
[Register of Pawns]
[Green jade hairpin]
Take a good look. Is it his handwriting?
Done?
We're leaving.
[Gold ring, gold bracelet]
Magistrate, this way.
Magistrate, have you ever
deeply loved a woman?
There used to be a scholar
who loved a woman so much.
But this woman was trapped
in the world of prostitution.
So
he needed money to buy her out.
Mr. Zhong believed
in this love story
and accepted his heirloom.
Can you guess
how much is this pawn worth?
Such a gold ring
is worth...
[5,000 wen]
5,000 wen?
Moreover,
Magistrate, you're mistaken.
This ring
is not gold at all.
Like this,
Mr. Zhong
was always moved
by these scammers' love stories.
So,
there are quite a few pawns here
that have no value.
I also found
that valuable items are missing.
Actually, I have been thinking
our shopkeeper
must be aware of this.
Haven't you tried to persuade him?
I did.
But
after
a few useless persuasions,
would you still do it again?
I also found...
[Register of Pawns]
[Gold ring, gold bracelet]
that valuable items are missing.
[Gold bracelet]
Miss Cao, have you heard
about the woman in the watchtower?
Magistrate has come
to inquire.
In answer to your question, Magistrate,
I have seen her.
You have?
Where?
In the theater.
She was watching a shadow play.
Then what?
One day when I went out,
I happened to see the puppet troupe
performing "Rain Master" in the theater.
That lady was also among the crowd.
That day,
the expression on her face
suggested she was very engrossed.
Just like a child,
crying and laughing.
After the performance,
she kept asking the members of the troupe
how Rain Master could come back to life.
It seemed that she couldn't distinguish
between the play and reality.
As if in this world,
there truly was a Rain Master.
When was that?
Six months ago.
Thank you for providing
such valuable information.
That's not necessary.
Magistrate.
Do you have anything else?
What else can I have?
These days,
I have been occupied
by this watchtower case.
I haven't listened to your music for long.
I remember
the other day you mentioned
"Song of Xunyang" to me.
About what Magistrate inquired,
I have already told you everything I know.
If there is nothing else to ask,
please excuse me, I've got to rest.
Where have you been in the midnight?
You were waiting for me?
I have some good news to tell you.
What good news?
Last night,
I told Cao An
about the upcoming transfer
of the Magistrate.
How can you be so silly?
What's wrong with me doing that?
Magistrate is about to leave,
no doubt about it.
I'm doing this for her own good.
To help her cut off all attachments.
Where did it come from?
You stole something again!
Shh!
Come on! This is not stealing.
We're leaving.
I did it just for the keepsake.
After all we've been through,
you still can't kick
the habit of stealing.
A leopard can't change its spots, indeed.
Magistrate!
Magistrate.
Magistrate, I'll give her
a piece of my mind.
Don't be angry, Magistrate.
Come in quickly.
Take shelter from the rain,
you fool!
Are you stupid?
Leave me alone!
Just swallow your pride a little.
It won't hurt you!
You see,
it seems to have grown.
But it will take a few more years
before it blooms and bears fruit.
All in good time.
Miss Cao.
The straw rain cape is very good.
I like it very much.
Glad you like it.
Six months ago, Mr. Zhong
watched a shadow play
by a puppet troupe in the city.
After he came back,
he was too preoccupied
to feel an appetite...
Like this,
Mr. Zhong
was always moved
by these scammers' love stories.
After the performance,
she kept asking the members of the troupe
how Rain Master could come back to life.
Seemed that she couldn't
distinguish between the play and reality.
As if in this world,
there truly was a Rain Master.
Magistrate.
It's raining.
It's raining heavily.
She's still out there in the rain.
She knows she was wrong.
Come in.
[Xiang's Fabric Shop]
Looks a bit like Rain Master.
I got it!
Whoever puts on Rain Master's clothes
becomes Rain Master!
Why haven't you come for so many days?
Do you know I've been waiting
for you every day?
Do you know how much I miss you?
How come you're so quiet?
What's wrong?
Why aren't you speaking?
You are not him.
There is no Rain Master in this world.
Who are you?
His last name is Zhong.
He's called Zhong Fang.
He likes you.
That's why he pretends
to be Rain Master
to get close to you.
Tell me.
What really happened that night?
Don't come any closer.
Put the knife down.
Do you remember seeing
those soldiers being punished
when you entered the barracks?
The Eighth Battalion.
They were supposed to patrol last night,
but these guys deserted.
God knows where they went.
They even lost their knives.
They must've
visited brothels last night.
They deserted
but were caught on the scene.
They had erotic pictures
hidden in their chests.
What do you want?
After being whipped,
they were still smiling.
Saying
last night was so worth it.
Stop it!
What are you doing?
It was me.
I killed him!
Who is there?
Stop!
[Wang Sanlang]
Did you kill the person?
Does this have anything to do
with the woman in the watchtower?
How about those child soldiers?
Were they present?
How did you kill him?
Magistrate.
He confessed.
Magistrate?
He has already confessed.
We can wrap it up now.
He confessed?
He didn't confess to anything.
Isn't it obvious
that he's the one who did it?
His fatal wound was in the back.
The stab in the chest
was completely different
from the one in the back
in terms of force and angle.
But every stab he made just now
had the same force.