[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 15]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
[Zhong's Pawn Shop]
[Zhong's]
Magistrate.
Please check this for me.
A dagger?
When was it?
On the day when Mr. Zhong was killed.
It must be after the shop was closed.
Mr. Zhong handled this deal himself.
This is his writing. I can recognize it.
On that day,
after the shop was closed,
apart from Mr. Zhong,
were there other people in the shop?
Shopkeeper Lin.
Where is Shopkeeper Lin?
He is in Mr. Zhong's room.
I remember when I was little,
I saved a bird
in my hometown.
After I saved it,
I wanted it to live a better life.
I bought it the best cage.
I let it drink the cleanest water
and eat the best food.
I thought
in this way,
it would be safer
and more comfortable
than when it was outside.
But in the end, it still died.
My father told me
that the bird longed for freedom.
But it couldn't get it,
and eventually, it died of depression.
Are you leaving?
Magistrate.
The shop has been sold.
Mr. Zhong has passed away.
Zhong's Pawn Shop
would eventually disappear.
Since the pawn shop would disappear,
why would you still
keep these account books?
I might offend you.
But this
has nothing to do with you.
It even has nothing to do with Mr. Zhong.
It mainly
has something to do with me.
You cherish them?
It's been 20 years.
We kept all the account books
for the past 20 years.
What kind of people would come
to the pawn shop?
Greedy people.
People with financial difficulties
would pawn their family heirlooms.
Cash-strapped people
would trade jewelry
for cash.
Those people
were very interesting.
They were
either ashamed to speak out
or greedy for property.
There were also people
who haggled over every penny.
I could at once...
Please excuse my behavior.
Why do you
come here today?
I want to ask you something.
Mr. Zhong
had someone he loved.
Do you know that?
He did?
A woman living in the marshland.
Very beautiful.
Mr. Zhong
loved her very much.
Beautiful?
So,
he was killed by that crazy woman.
What do you mean?
Sorry for my hasty conclusion.
Frankly,
no matter who Mr. Zhong loved,
or who killed him,
I don't care at all about these things.
A man who had been with you for 20 years
died.
You don't care at all?
What should I care about?
Care about
why he had turned into a Rain Master.
In the past six months,
Mr. Zhong
often looked spaced out.
He loved to go out on a rainy night.
Only children would believe
there is a Rain Master.
He could just fool that crazy woman.
Why should I care about it?
I need to care about the business
of the shop.
If I cared about all those
weird things like them,
our shop
would have long been closed down.
If I guessed it right,
on that afternoon,
there was a heated argument
between you and Mr. Zhong.
You hoped he could
stop doing those crazy things
and focus
on the business.
But he refused.
This world
has long destroyed me.
Only my Ying'er
never looks at me that way.
In her eyes,
there is only love
and admiration.
I feel the same for her.
Mr. Zhong,
wake up!
Are you sure whether she loves the mask
or the real you?
Mr. Zhong,
if one day
when you take off the mask
and stop being the Rain Master
who can only fool children,
will she still love you?
Mr. Zhong,
I beg you. Okay?
We finally got
to where we are today.
For a crazy woman...
Don't call her that way
in front of me!
That's why
you killed Zhong Fang?
I
killed Mr. Zhong?
On that day,
those child soldiers
from the eighth camp
pawned that dagger
after the shop was closed.
I have to say,
you have successfully
shifted my attention
to those child soldiers
from the eighth camp.
What a wonderful story.
Magistrate Di,
you made me
the protagonist of this story.
I'm very honored.
But I'm
just a manager in this shop.
At most, I can be considered
a vice shopkeeper.
Why would I kill him?
Do you really consider yourself
merely a vice shopkeeper?
It's been 20 years.
You were with him,
starting from scratch.
From nothing
to building the pawn shop
to what it is today.
In the past 20 years,
you knew all accounts by heart.
You watched him
spending all the money
on a crazy woman.
Can you accept it?
No.
But what could I do?
He is the owner here.
Kill him.
Kill him,
and all the wealth here
would be yours.
All the...
wealth.
Magistrate Di,
do you know
what this shop
means to me?
No.
Of course, you don't.
How can a bureaucrat like you
know about what a nobody like us
has been through
to climb
the social ladder?
I do want to know
what you've been through.
In fact,
there is nothing strange.
Any pawn shop is like this.
At that time,
Zhong's Pawn Shop opened.
I welcomed the customers
with a big smile.
[Zhong's]
I had to
serve the customers with great care.
[Zhong's Pawn Shop]
Sir,
such a price is low?
No. Please don't go.
Don't be angry.
We can discuss it.
It's okay
to meet good-natured customers.
Those bad-tempered customers
would curse me
or spit on me.
With a smile,
I wiped off the spit.
I even apologized.
I continued to smile
and say it's okay.
I kept apologizing
until he was satisfied.
20 years.
I have been working hard for 20 years.
I made Zhong's business grow.
Magistrate,
we were about to open a branch
in Jinan Prefecture.
A branch!
I went there excitedly
and arranged everything for him.
As long as I could come back
and get the money,
we could open it.
But where was the money?
The money was gone.
He gave it to the crazy woman.
He,
Zhong Fang,
not only destroyed this shop,
but also my 20 years of time.
My whole life!
So, you killed him.
Yes,
I killed him.
The two of them
never hurt anyone.
They just wanted
to live their own lives.
He hurt me!
Do you know?
He also hurt
those who had been working hard
with him for 20 years.
He even said some nonsense
that he had found
the World of Ultimate Bliss.
In real life,
there has never been
a World of Ultimate Bliss.
What can he eat
or drink?
Without our 20 years of effort,
how could he have money
to make that crazy woman happy?
How could he have money
to buy those ridiculous outfits?
Without those ridiculous outfits,
he would have been killed
by that crazy woman a long time ago.
It's better for him to be killed by me.
Being killed by me,
he could get
one last shred of decency.
Kill him!
It was right here
where Shopkeeper Lin killed Zhong Fang.
To frame Ying'er,
he carried the corpse to the watchtower.
With your own eyes,
you saw Ying'er stabbed Zhong Fang.
That's why you wanted to protect her.
But
he was not killed by Ying'er.
Before Ying'er stabbed Zhong Fang,
he had already died.
Afterwards,
you carried the corpse to this place
to clear up the suspicion of Ying'er.
I killed him.
You love Ying'er,
but Ying'er
only likes the Rain Master.
You could only follow her
and do everything
you could for her.
Two stabs.
Two murderers.
Three crime scenes.
Three people
with unrequited love.
Zhong Fang wore a mask
to get close to Ying'er.
Wang Sanlang can die for Ying'er.
The human heart is too complicated.
Love is crazy.
A group of cowards.
In the end,
they were all running away.
Just don't find any excuse!
When you love someone,
if you have no courage to tell them,
that's not love.
What do you know about love?
Row the boat.
[Phoenix Inn]
You okay there?
Come on, drink!
Come on.
[Phoenix Inn]
Lanfang County is too far away.
No matter how good the wine is,
I can't drink with you anymore.
Do you know it already?
Who said you couldn't drink with me?
After I settle down in Lanfang County,
I'll invite you to drink at that place.
Are you serious?
A word spoken is past recalling.
I carved it myself.
I'm not good at it.
It's not as useful as your copper dice.
But if you carry it with you,
maybe it can really bring you luck.
Keep it.
Don't forget me.
How can I forget you?
Even if this dice is lost,
I won't forget you.
Take care.
[Phoenix Inn]
Time to set off.
Where is the Magistrate?
I haven't seen him since this morning.
Let's go.
Let's wait for him on the official road.
[Penglai County Magistrate's Office]
[Mingyue House]
I'm going to Lanfang County.
I'm leaving.
I want you to go with me.
I've thought about it.
When we get there,
you can work as a clerical assistant
or do some other job.
You can do whatever you want.
I'll give you full support.
I know
you've been in Penglai for many years.
My invitation seems quite abrupt
right now.
You are right.
A man should have courage.
If one lives behind his mask
for a lifetime,
he is too pitiful.
I'm going to Lanfang County soon.
I will be very sad
if you're not with me.
What's going on?
Is Magistrate planning
to walk to Lanfang County?
Why don't you ask him?
I may be slow,
but I'm not foolish.
He is clearly not in a good mood.
Who is willing to get scolded?
He is not in a good mood?
Can't you tell?
Why is she here?
♪Today, under the flower tree♪
♪It feels like it has been ages♪
♪Since early summer♪
♪Your youthful face is blushed
with colors♪
♪Lies hidden in lips♪
♪Were revealed between the eyebrows♪
♪The old love appears in dreams♪
♪Where love and pain intertwine♪
♪We continue to explore life together♪
♪Fate brings us together and apart,
yet my heart remains undisturbed♪
You've come.
I've come.
She has really come?
She is going to Lanfang County with us?
Let me go ask her.
What do you want to ask?
It's not your turn to ask.
What do you mean my turn...?
It is such an important matter.
She didn't make it clear to us,
yet she is going with us now?
Why?
They are doing very well.
Let's go.
[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Red Pavilion]
We are back in the desert. Wonderful.
Comfortable.
Magistrate, do you still remember
how we met for the first time here?
Yes.
Two
starving men.
Robbery.
Hold on.
How long haven't you eaten?
Several days.
No work to do?
If we have work to do, we won't rob you.
Work for me from now on.
Okay.
If we hadn't been starving on that day,
we don't know what we would be today.
Magistrate, what are you looking at?
Yeah. What's the matter?
It is coming back, too.
The sandstorm is coming. Let's go!
Let's go!
Hurry up.
Hurry up!
This way.
Hurry up.
It's dangerous!
Hurry up!
Hide over there!
Be careful, everyone!
Quick!
Don't get separated.
Follow quickly!
Quick!
Don't get separated.
Follow quickly!
Hide behind the rocks!
Quick!
Hurry up!
Go!
Hide quickly.
Quick!
This way.
Hurry up.
Don't go out.
Come here quickly!
Magistrate,
the briefcase!
The briefcase!
Magistrate,
all are cases that were closed.
[Sealed by Penglai County
Magistrate's Office]
Magistrate,
the city defense team sent us
a letter today by a pigeon.
What's the matter?
The city defense team for the next shift
is also trapped by the sandstorm.
It will take them ten days to arrive.
Ma Rong,
you set off with Qiao Tai at once.
Ride quickly and explore the way
into the city.
Let's meet at the city gate then.
Remember.
The city defense team hasn't arrived.
Be careful.
Yes.
I didn't expect
after the storm,
there would be such a quiet starry sky.
And
it is so close to us.
Indeed, I didn't expect
after the yellow sand dispersed
from the sky,
there would be a brilliant galaxy.
The desert has its own beauty.
But...
Do you have a load on your mind?
Today, in the desert,
I found a small peach wood sword
that I had kept for many years.
This small peach wood sword
means a lot
to me.
I don't believe that peach wood
can ward off evil spirits.
But by bringing it along,
I can always turn ill luck into good.
Today, I reunited with it.
Maybe it is trying to remind me
that Lanfang County
is a very dangerous place.
Are you scared?
I'm afraid you might suffer.
I don't believe that peach wood
can ward off evil spirits, either.
But I believe in you.
I believe,
no matter who it is,
you can face him calmly.