[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 16]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
[Lan Ward]
Sir, please, give us some water.
[Han Zaifeng]
Please give us some water, Sir.
For goodness' sake.
Come.
Thank you.
Thank you, Sir.
Next one.
Compensate me for the water.
- You hit me.
- Compensate me for the water.
Don't go.
Compensate me
for the money to buy water.
What are you doing?
You dare fight over it!
Stop fighting!
Do you hear that?
You dare fight over it!
Make way.
Fight!
Stop!
What are you doing?
Everyone, stop!
Stop beating.
Do you dare to fight over it again?
Everyone, stop!
Stop beating.
Stop!
Mr. Li.
Isn't it just for money?
It's useless.
This place is Lan Ward.
No matter how much money you have,
you can't save all of them.
Thank you, Mr. Li.
You are welcome.
Go fetch water.
Fetch water quickly.
[Li Tao]
Everyone, don't worry.
Everyone can get some.
Everyone can get some. Don't worry.
Don't worry.
One by one.
One by one. Everyone can get some.
Everyone can get water.
Let's go.
The elder come first.
Don't worry.
Everyone can get some.
Boss,
give us some money. Quick.
Hurry up.
Let's go.
Magistrate.
Magistrate,
the magistral office of Lan Ward is gone.
The magistral office is gone?
Just a heap of rubble.
Let's go take a look.
[Lan Ward Magistral Office]
If we didn't see it with our own eyes,
who would believe this was
the magistral office of Lan Ward?
Magistrate,
in the Lan Ward,
all kinds of business are controlled
by the factions.
There is no peaceful place to stay.
That flag
belongs to one of the factions.
Black Tiger Gang.
Burned land in contrast
with the red tower.
This Red Pavilion
[Red Pavilion]
is extraordinary.
Well,
let's stay here.
Magistrate,
you mean staying here?
Is it appropriate?
We will stay here?
Just listen to Magistrate.
Is it appropriate?
You don't like it?
Please come in.
Are you here to stay?
Yes.
[Biyu]
Follow me.
The first floor is usually noisy.
I hope you don't mind.
The second floor
is much quieter.
The people staying here
are all merchants.
Like you,
they are just lodgers.
This way, please.
Here we are.
This is a very sunny room.
It's most suitable
to be your study.
Thank you, Miss.
Just call me Biyu.
After we arrived in Lan Ward,
we saw many flags here.
Which flag
is your place under?
There is no flag
in Red Pavilion.
Compared to the outside,
it's a peaceful world here.
You might not know
that there are three major factions
in Lan Ward.
Green Dragon Gang,
Lone Wolf Gang,
and Black Tiger Gang.
[Red Pavilion]
Apart from these three major factions,
there are over ten other factions
of various size.
Even I can't tell the specific number.
In a word,
they rise one after another.
[Lan Ward]
Taking turns to rule endlessly.
Has Lan Ward
always been fragmented
by rivaling factions?
In the past,
they were commanded by Heiyan.
Heiyan?
But for some reason,
five years ago,
they seemed to have suffered heavy losses.
Later on, they all disappeared.
Heiyan disappeared,
but someone has to rule over Lan Ward.
That's the reason
for the current fragmentation.
To consolidate their positions,
they are controlling
all kinds of business in Lan Ward.
They also take Anhua.
You must be fatigued
by a long journey.
Please rest early.
If you officials
need anything,
feel free to tell me.
If there is anything inconvenient,
you can also tell me.
I will take care of you carefully.
Well,
thank you then.
How did she know we were officials?
Magistrate
looks very much like an official.
There are so many wharves in Lan Ward.
But you got water from my well.
There are many people in Black Tiger Gang.
There isn't enough water at home.
It's the Black Tiger Gang again.
[Qian Hao]
After today,
there will be no more Lone Wolf Gang.
These bandits
have soldiers and money.
It's hard to deal with them.
Before the city defense arrive,
we can't take any action.
Let's first do what we can do.
[Red Pavilion]
Miss Biyu.
[Qiu Yue]
My name is Qiu Yue.
What do you want to see Biyu about?
I
want to ask Biyu
about something.
If it's something urgent,
I'll ask her to come right now.
No need.
I'll look for her myself.
Business as usual.
Okay.
Go on.
Carry on.
Very good.
Cui, raise your hand higher.
My fault.
I didn't mean to steal your money.
I won't do it again.
[Red Pavilion]
[Ying]
Magistrate,
what are you doing?
I had nothing else to do just now.
So I drew the map of Lan Ward
according to my impression only.
I don't know
whether it is accurate or not.
Come here!
Mr. Hong,
protect Miss Cao and send her back
to her room.
Go. Follow quickly.
- What's going on?
- What happened?
What happened?
Gave me a fright.
What's going on?
Mr. Li...
Come.
Sit down first.
Miss, don't be afraid.
Take your time to talk.
What did you see?
Stop!
Isn't it just for money?
Here you are.
You must be terrified.
Don't be afraid.
Find something to do.
Tell us
what happened.
Just now, I came in to give him some food.
Mr. Li,
please have something to eat.
As soon as I entered the room,
I saw Mr. Li...
What's the relationship between you?
He once proposed to me in public.
Miss Qiu Yue,
I've made up my mind.
I will buy back your freedom
from Red Pavilion.
Then I will leave Lan Ward with you.
We will go to a faraway place.
These are the betrothal gifts.
They are all for you.
After we leave here,
I will marry you.
Only the two of us will live together.
Okay?
But I refused him.
Mr. Li,
thank you.
He committed suicide because of this.
It was all my fault.
You mean
Mr. Li
was trapped in love.
That was why
he committed suicide.
Is that what you mean?
Yes.
Do you have any basis
for this statement?
Previously,
he told me
he was writing a will to me.
I thought he was joking with me.
Are you copying the scriptures?
I'm writing a will.
It's to you.
Mr. Li,
don't joke with me.
Have you gone through anything
in this room?
No.
As soon as I came in...
Qiu Yue,
what happened to Mr. Li?
Well...
He has died.
He has died?
Qiu Yue,
in the past few days,
was there anything strange
about Mr. Li's behavior?
He was not in a good mood recently.
He often looked into the mirror...
Qiu Yue,
don't talk nonsense about him.
How could such a thing happen?
Bad luck.
You can go down first.
Wait.
Qiu Yue.
Qiu Yue usually took care
of Mr. Li's food and living.
Such a thing happened today.
She must be greatly terrified.
Sir,
it must have disturbed you, too.
Please go back to rest.
How can we rest?
Someone has died.
There should be people looking into this.
It's the local officials' business
to solve the case.
What does it have to do with you?
You should report the case right now.
The magistral office of Lan Ward
has long been burnt.
Even if we want to report the case,
we have to wait until tomorrow morning.
You don't understand this.
The crime scene...
I will lock up the room.
Before the officials come tomorrow,
no one is allowed to enter.
Nor will anyone
move Mr. Li's body.
I've been manager Red Pavilion
for over ten years.
Everything has been peaceful.
I will handle this
properly.
What did I say?
Our family can't do
without me.
The ink is not dry yet.
Mr. Li had written something
before he died.
He told me
he was writing a will to me.
I thought he was joking with me.
The lower part of the cut
is deeper than the upper part.
He seemed to have held the knife
with his right hand.
The blood has congealed,
but the ink is not dry.
Besides,
the wound
is not above the pool of blood.
Someone has moved the body.
He didn't commit suicide.
What's that?
Magistrate,
these are all evidences of debt.
Today, I borrowed 500 qian from Mr. Li.
No need to pay back.
Such a good thing.
No need to pay back the money you borrow.
Mr. Li might have lent
too much money to others.
He lost all the money
and couldn't make a living.
He could only commit suicide.
His wound
is not above the pool of blood.
Did you say that?
The blood has congealed,
but the ink on the table is not dry.
His body has been moved.
Obviously, he didn't commit suicide.
Did you say that?
That makes sense.
There is a needle hole on his neck.
Come and take a look.
That's not right.
There's no trace of other people entering.
Have you gone through anything
in this room?
No.
Qiu Yue
has lied.
[Magistrate assistant, Mr. Li]
Who are you?
Greetings. I am Li Luo,
the magistrate assistant of Lan Ward.
I didn't know you had arrived in Lan Ward.
I should have welcomed you earlier.
Please forgive me.
When was the magistral office destroyed?
Magistrate,
it was destroyed
early last month.
Where were you at that time?
Did you save
the documents?
Except for
the previous magistrate,
who abandoned
his official position and fled,
all others stayed in Lan Ward.
Magistrate, rest assured.
Tomorrow morning,
I'll ask them to report on their work.
[Red Pavilion]
Greetings, Magistrate Di.
You
reported the case
and asked Mr. Li to come?
You may not know it.
Although it's a pity
that Mr. Li has committed suicide,
I just wanted Mr. Li
to witness it.
Later on, we can explain it to his family.
Just to avoid trouble.
You said he had committed suicide?
Why are you so sure?
Didn't he commit suicide?
Do you know Mr. Li's background?
He is the same as you.
Also a lodger in Red Pavilion.
So far,
he has stayed here for 47 days.
I don't know
about anything else.
He has stayed here for so long.
Yet you know nothing
about him?
If a customer doesn't tell us,
how could we ask him?
If I ask everybody,
don't you have to show me
your letter of appointment?
I think I'm experienced in judging people.
Mr. Li was just like you.
He was gentle, kind,
and righteous.
He was very polite
to the ladies
and he loved Qiu Yue
deeply.
He never got close to other ladies.
He was truly a gentleman.
It's really a pity.
You may go get busy.
What is this woman's background?
You may not know it.
Biyu is a legendary figure
in Lan Ward.
She has been juggling
various forces for years.
That's how she was able to keep
Red Pavilion intact.
There are a lot of stories
about her.
There was a rich gentleman surnamed Lu.
He was deeply in love with Biyu.
He wanted to marry her.
But Biyu
didn't want to part
with the ladies of Red Pavilion.
She declined Mr. Lu.
No one could expect
Mr. Lu
had died for love
because of Biyu
right in Red Pavilion.
After that,
Biyu rose to fame.
She had a sudden rise in social status.
It was passed
from mouth to mouth with approbation.
The ladies here all tried to imitate her.
Then Mr. Li must be killed by Qiu Yue.
She wants to imitate Biyu.
So far,
there is no evidence to prove that.
Magistrate,
what should we investigate next?
[Red Pavilion]
Magistrate.
Magistrate,
shall we inspect Lan Ward today?
This is the emblem I found
below the signature on a painting
hanging in Li Tao's room.
If I remember correctly,
this is the emblem of Li Weijing,
the former governor of Tingzhou.
Is Li Weijing
from Lan Ward?
There was indeed
a Mr. Li in Lan Ward
who was once the governor of Tingzhou.
He has retired to his hometown.
Do you know where his home is?
Could Li Tao who has died
be from the Li family?
Do you know where his home is?
Yes.
Magistrate, please.
Our master grew all these flowers.
Please.
Magistrate Di,
you've come from afar
to visit us.
I should have welcomed you earlier.
I've come without invitation.
Sorry for disturbing you.
I've resigned from office for many years.
I was no longer the governor.
It's about you son,
Li Tao.
I...
[Mr. Li]
I'm sorry for being impolite.
Magistrate Di,
do you know this flower?
Please tell me.
This kind of flower
is called tulip.
It is abundant in the Western Regions.
My wife loved them
before she passed away.
This kind of flower is my favorite.
I planted them in this place
and took care of them for many years.
They are finally blossoming.
Mr. Li.
When the tulip withers,
the spring
is about to end.
I'm in poor health.
I may not make it through this year.
My son
has been benevolent
since childhood.
If you want to take away what he loves,
he will offer it to you with both hands.
If you
beat him,
he just lets you do it.
He never fights back.
I once asked my son
why he was too weak
to fight back.
Guess
how my son answered.
My son said
that if he fought back,
there would never be an end
of taking revenge.
If he didn't
fight back
or ever
consider it,
he could win others' trust.
How could an innocent child
know the evils that lurk in the world
and in the human heart?
My son always feels
I'm too strict with him.
He was only close to his mother.
He seldom
talks to me.
Now,
he even ran away from home.
He didn't want to come back.
If you meet him,
please take care of him on my behalf
and persuade him to come home early.
After all,
he is my only son.
Magistrate.
Take care.
My Lord,
it has been arranged.
Investigate quickly.
Yes.
It wasn't easy for you.
We really
didn't know
how to tell this to Mr. Li.
I admire your sympathy
for him very much.
I've worked as an official
for seven years.
I've worked under five magistrates.
No one has changed
the situation in Lan Ward.
If you want to make a change,
I will do my best.
Magistrate Di,
what should we do next?
[Sealed by Lan Ward Magistral Office]
Thank you, Secretary Bai,
Mr. Po.
[Secretary Bai, Magistrate assistant Po]
Mr. Hong, you are welcome.
We will be colleagues in the future.
There are several more boxes of documents.
We will send them over tomorrow.
Okay.
Thank you.
Now that today,
Magistrate and Mr. Li
are away on business,
we will
report on our work tomorrow.
Okay.
I'll see you off.
Mr. Li,
may peace be with you.
May peace be with you.
Mr. Li,
may peace be with you.
May peace be with you.
Mr. Li had done a lot of good
to a lot of people.
Did you find anything
after going to Mr. Li's mansion?
I can't even tell him
Li Tao has died.
I may be disrespectful to the dead
if I say the following words.
But Li Tao's case
may be an opportunity for you.
A chance to break the ice
in Lan Ward.
What are these people
doing here?
Magistrate Di,
the new magistrate of Lan Ward,
is now holding court for cases.