[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
[Episode 18]
So his target is you.
I'll kill him.
Are you ready?
The Lone Wolf Gang
still has some evil members left.
Go to hell and meet your leader.
I heard that
there was a new magistrate in Lan Ward.
Compared to those good-for-nothings,
you do have some abilities.
I repeat my words.
You can't take
that Anhua.
Now, what do you have to say?
Today,
you saved my life.
I will spare you once.
But as for Anhua, I must take it.
Of course, whether I can take the Anhua
depends on whether you can find
the real culprit.
Whoever you investigate,
I will kill.
Remember,
this place is Lan Ward.
I kill whoever I want to kill.
Magistrate Di,
magistrates
also died in my hands.
See you!
Where is Qiu Yue?
Magistrate,
tonight, everyone in the Red Pavilion
is looking for Qiu Yue.
Why don't you ask them
if they have found her?
[Red Pavilion]
Magistrate,
she has skipped.
All valuable things are gone.
Magistrate.
Madam.
Are you still looking for Qiu Yue?
Where is she?
Do you know where she went?
A couple of days ago, she was so restless
because of the death of Mr. Li.
I thought
she was resting in her room
as she asked for leave.
I didn't expect that
she would run away.
As long as she left the Red Pavilion,
live or die,
it's her own business.
You really don't know?
I really don't know
where she went.
Outside the Lan Ward,
there are Gobi and desert everywhere.
[West of the City]
This is Liuli Post.
[Liuli Post]
This is Zhenxi Fortress.
Zhenxi Fortress is at the border of Tang.
From there, you can leave the Tang land.
If Qiu Yue really killed Mr. Li,
she would definitely flee the empire.
That makes sense.
Qiu Yue is frail and may not ride a horse.
If she took a carriage,
as the way is long,
she must resupply at the Liuli Post.
I'll arrange for some men
to chase her.
I'll do it now.
You see,
I've said it all along,
Qiu Yue is the culprit.
Now, she has run away.
Let's go and prepare the horses.
Wait.
Where is this place?
Hongliu Village.
It's not close, yet not far to the city.
It could be her first place to resupply.
Magistrate, you think...
Zhenxi Fortress
is too far.
The way to Zhenxi Fortress
bears desert,
sandy winds,
and wolves.
I think
Qiu Yue
would most probably flee south.
[Hongliu Village]
We came late.
We are still too late.
Whoever you investigate,
I will kill.
Remember,
this place is Lan Ward.
But as for Anhua,
I must take it.
Magistrate,
tonight, everyone in the Red Pavilion
is looking for Qiu Yue.
Why don't you ask them
if they have found her?
What is this?
It's what I wanted.
We are lucky and blessed by heaven.
What's that?
Isn't it Qiu Yue's hair stick?
Was she dragged away from here?
But here, it shows no traces of dragging.
Wrong.
Why?
Why is that?
No wonder Secretary Bai left last night
and has not returned yet.
He is also involved with those bandits.
The Tang Code
has already lost its influence
in Lan Ward.
People here feel unsafe.
That's understandable.
Had I known this before,
why would I stay in the magistral office?
Mr. Li,
in Lan Ward,
you are the only one I have now.
Magistrate.
Ma Rong and Qiao Tai
are dealing with something important.
I want you
[Governor Li Eyes Only]
to give this letter
to Governor Li in person.
Magistrate, please rest assured.
I will do it quickly
with no delay.
[Red Pavilion]
Stop it.
This letter
speaks of your loyalty.
How can you find it?
Tell us the truth.
Why do you collude with Qian Hao?
Governor Li lost his son at an old age.
What's wrong with him avenging his son?
I have to follow Qian Hao's orders
because I need to protect my family.
What's wrong with this?
If you are truly competent,
kill Qian Hao
and wipe out all the gangs in Lan Ward.
I don't believe you can do it.
Nobody can!
With Authority.
The Magistrate of Lan Ward holds court.
Why did the table tip over?
This...
Someone sawed off the leg of the table.
The magistral office is gone.
What's the meaning
of this magistrate office?
They were commanded by Heiyan.
I don't have time to wait
for your justice.
... was all truth.
As long as she left the Red Pavilion,
live or die,
it's her own business.
Magistrates also died in my hands.
It's useless.
This place is Lan Ward.
This is Lan Ward.
[Red Pavilion]
It belongs to Qiu Yue.
All people in the city know that
all gangs
are pursuing and killing those
who are related to Mr. Li's death.
Qiu Yue disappeared without any reason.
If she didn't run away,​
she must have encountered misfortune.
The hair stick
is one of her favorites.
I don't know if she can wear it again.
Why don't you first ask me
where I found it?
Miss Biyu,
this golden hair stick
was put in that cellar
by your workers, right?
Miss Biyu,
are you aware that
though this scheme is ingenious,
it has one critical flaw?
The flags you left in the Hongliu Village
belong to the Black Tiger Gang.
Black Tiger Gang
loves killing.
Qian Hao
treats human lives like grass.
If he was to find Qiu Yue,
he must kill some people.
Right?
But when I arrived in Hongliu Village,
the whole village
was empty.
Did the Black Tiger Gang become kind
and tell the villagers to leave
before they came to kidnap Qiu Yue?
Your plot is ingenious.
Whoever
finds the golden hair stick
would believe that
Qiu Yue
has been kidnapped.
But why it is that, up to now,
nobody
takes Qiu Yue
to see Governor Li and claim his Anhua?
If my guess is correct,
Qiu Yue
didn't leave Lan Ward at all.
She is still
in the city.
Tell me,
where is she?
I don't know.
Miss Biyu,
could you believe me for just once?
Qiu Yue is in great danger.
I don't know.
All gangs in the city
took the Anhua
and searched the entire Lan Ward,
but they still didn't find a trace
of Qiu Yue leaving the city.
They searched everywhere.
Qiu Yue might not have left the city.
Perhaps
she is still in the Red Pavilion.
Then we should tear down the Red Pavilion.
She killed my son
and wants to hide.
If she makes me lose control,
I'll have everyone at the Red Pavilion
buried with my son.
Understood.
Things not going smoothly?
I didn't find Qiu Yue.
Biyu knows where she is,
but she won't admit it.
Give her some time.
Are you sure
that Qiu Yue is the culprit?
No.
Li Tao committing suicide
makes no sense.
Qiu Yue
is the prime suspect
for imitating Biyu in committing murder.
But now,
Governor Li has offered Anhua.
All forces in Lan Ward want to kill her.
Qiu Yue
faces imminent danger.
Is there any other suspect?
I have excluded the possibility
that a thief broke in through the window
to steal promissory notes and kill him.
The last person to enter Li Tao's room
was Qiu Yue.
Qiu Yue said that
when she entered the room,
Li Tao was already dead.
Li Tao once told her
he
was writing a will.
To prove that she is innocent,
she searched Li Tao's belongings
to find the will.
That explains
why Li Tao's body
was moved by someone
and his room was messy.
But the point is
the will
hasn't been found by Qiu Yue.
I haven't found it, either.
The only evidence
that can prove Qiu Yue's innocence
is gone.
Qiu Yue said that
Li Tao loved her deeply,
and so did she.
If so,
Qiu Yue
didn't have a reason to kill Li Tao.
He was nice,
gentle,
and kind.
... like a lotus under the sunshine.
From Qiu Yue's words
and tone,
I can see that
she is indeed in love with Li Tao.
Magistrate, have you ever thought that
perhaps
it is really a suicide.
You have excluded the possibility
that someone broke in and killed him.
Yes.
Li Tao loved Qiu Yue,
and it is for sure.
Yes.
Qiu Yue loves Li Tao,
and you do believe it.
Yes.
They love each other,
but due to some unspeakable reason,
they can't stay with each other.
So, Li Tao
had no choice but to commit suicide.
Is this story
not reasonable?
When you exclude all the possibilities,
the remaining ones,
however unbelievable,
are the truth.
Mister.
Get out!
You get out!
What's the matter?
Mister.
Magistrate,
Mr. Hu woke up.
I'll go there.
Let's go.
Thanks, Miss Cao.
You've finally come.
Look at this.
He keeps drawing things.
These are messy.
He also keeps mumbling something.
But I don't know what he is saying.
That's it!
I finally got the drawing right.
Burn!
Burn.
I must burn them all.
Is that you who burnt
Li Tao's corpse?
Burn it all and leave nothing.
We can't let it scourge the world.
Burn!
What will scourge the world?
It.
Sand flea.
It bites man.
It bites man to pieces.
It's more horrible than tuberculosis.
Burn!
Help!
Fortunately, I burned it.
The red spot on Li Tao's body
was caused by sand fleas.
He was not poisoned.
Right.
I don't have time
to wait for your justice.
He told me
he was writing a will to me.
I thought he was joking with me.
Whoever kills the murderer
doesn't matter.
Magistrate Di.
Governor Li  found Qiu Yue
at the Red Pavilion.
Miss Biyu urges you to go there quickly.
Governor Li!
- I'll kill you!
- Spare her!
Stop there!
Magistrate Di,
are you going to stop me?
Qiu Yue
is not the murderer.
This girl
seduced my son
and played with my son's feelings.
To raise her own social status,
she even took my son's life.
Today,
I'll kill her at this place
to mourn for my son.
Miss Qiu Yue,
do you know that
Li Tao
truly committed suicide?
What's more,
he committed suicide for you.
Liar!
You are lying!
How could you
humiliate my son
just to absolve this girl?
Governor Li!
I would like
to go bail for her with my life.
Your son
truly committed suicide.
Nonsense!
That's nonsense!
Why would my son kill himself?
Why would he?
He had a bright future.
He was only 25.
How would he
commit suicide for this prostitute?
Because he suffered
from a terminal illness like you.
Impossible.
Impossible!
Get out of here!
You are not my son!
Father.
After I knew I fell ill,
I at once expelled him
and sent him to Lan Ward.
How could he
be infected by me?
Because Li Tao was not suffering
from tuberculosis.
Neither do you.
Governor Li,
your illness
was caused by sand fleas.
Sand fleas
are very poisonous.
After being bitten by sand fleas,
people will fall ill.
At the beginning, people feel itchy.
Then,
the body begins to fester
until the bones are shown.
The patients
will suffer from endless pain
until
they die.
Also,
it's incurable by medicine.
Do you remember
the flowers you cultivated?
It was those tulips
that attracted the sand fleas.
Your son
didn't know what kind of disease he had,
but he knew
his body
had a great problem.
That was why
he had changed his attitude
toward you suddenly.
He scolded you deliberately
and avoided you intentionally.
Mister.
Get out!
You get out!
Mister.
Get out!
He didn't want his beloved girl
to have any feelings for him.
Mister.
Don't come over.
You once told me that
when Li Tao
first came to the Red Pavilion,
you took desserts to him,
and you two
fell in love at first sight.
Mr. Li
was refined and courteous.
He was generous and benevolent.
He was good in every aspect.
He and you
developed an affection for each other
after staying together for long.
On that day,
he finally confessed to you
and proposed to you.
Governor Li,
all of these
can be testified by everyone here.
Right. That's right.
Miss Qiu Yue,
the reason why you denied his proposal
was that you saw the evil
of human nature when you were little
and you didn't believe that
in this world,
you could encounter
such wonderful things.
You were afraid.
You feared all of these
were not true.
You dared not believe that.
So,
you shrank back.
Qiu Yue,
I believe you.
Li Tao
had indeed written that will.
Maybe he didn't know
why you would shrink back.
But he loved you.
That is true.
Don't blame him for what he did
to you afterward.
That must not be
his true intentions.
In the midst of a flowing stream,
my heart is unspeakable to you.
Pitifully,
I didn't find the will, either.
Perhaps,
just as you said,
the will
was most probably
blown away
by a gust of wind.
He really wrote a will for me.
Governor Li,
the man who pushed your son to death
is you,
not Qiu Yue.
Miss Qiu Yue,
I am so ashamed.
I lost my courtesy.
I would like to apologize
for my offense.
Di Renjie,
Magistrate Di,
thanks for clarifying all of this.
I really have become senile.
Thank you for what you did.
You saved Miss Qiu Yue
and told me my son's
last will.
I am
deeply touched.
You are a beautiful girl.
No wonder my son loved you so much.
I have no other way to show my apology.
If there were another life,
I would surely repay you generously.
Magistrate,
please allow me to die with dignity.
Master.
We are city guardians.
Surrender yourselves!
Please don't kill me!
[Lan Ward]
Everyone can get some.
Thanks!
Line up.
Wait in line.
Thank you.
Thank you!
Thanks...
Be careful.
[Red Pavilion]
Where did you buy this?
It looks beautiful.
Yeah. It's really beautiful.
Please take us there.
Okay. Let's go.
Set out!
Di Renjie,
I still challenge you!
Have you ever
recollected that girl
whom you deceived?
That girl who hung herself.
Strangled by the rope. How does it feel?
Bit by bit...
The blood flows down.
Pain
is far from over.
The wheel of karma turns.
What goes around comes around.
This is the natural law.
[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Desert Pursuit]