[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 19]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
Oyez.
Who are you?
I am Han Yongnan.
I live in the eastern suburbs
of Lanfang County.
I am the owner of a silver mine.
On the 27th day of the tenth month
of the first year of Linde,
that is, the day before yesterday,
my friends and I
were feasting in my house.
In order to add to the fun,
we indulged in dallying
with some prostitutes.
However,
I'm accused of rape
by ill-intentioned people.
[Han Yongnan]
I'm really wronged.
Dallying with prostitutes?
Zhao Wangrui
is under age.
[Miss Jin]
Her mother Miss Jin
works as a maid in your mansion.
Since there was a feast in the mansion,
you were short of hands.
Miss Jin
asked her daughter
to go to your mansion to help.
You scoundrels
raped her daughter
after drinking.
Han Yongnan.
Yes.
Do you admit it?
Magistrate,
this place is not the capital.
In Lanfang County,
many girls
have been abandoned
since they were born.
Rather than let her starve to death
in the wilderness,
it's better
to find a good partner
when she is young and beautiful.
That's a way out.
Nonsense!
According to the law of Tang,
if a woman is unwilling,
it is considered rape.
How can you judge
if she is willing?
You can't get an answer
from the girl.
But
her mother agreed.
Magistrate,
I didn't pay them a penny less.
Miss Jin,
you can't slander me
after taking my money.
I didn't take your money.
Magistrate,
I have evidence.
This is the purchase contract.
Miss Jin's fingerprint is on it.
Give it to Miss Jin.
Is the fingerprint
on the purchase contract yours?
Magistrate,
I...
I am illiterate.
How dare you?
Miss Jin is illiterate.
How could she know
what contract she was signing?
Qiao Tai,
did you find anything
in Miss Jin's house?
Magistrate,
in Miss Jin's room,
there is indeed 3,000 qian.
No, Magistrate.
No.
Magistrate,
if you want to ask
what happened
that night,
being in this court,
I can only tell you one thing.
Now there is something
called Five Stone Powder in the capital.
After you take it,
the fun will double
and you'll feel like in heaven.
You can't describe
that kind of feeling in words.
If you are interested,
I'll find a day...
How dare you?
Ma Rong.
Magistrate.
Magistrate,
you caught me
yesterday.
It's been
24 hours now.
I know something about the law of Tang.
If there is
no conviction,
the maximum detention time
cannot exceed 24 hours.
Magistrate,
ever since you took office,
you've been following the law of Tang.
You can't break your rules
just because of what she said.
The case of Han Yongnan
raping a girl
will be rescheduled
for lack
of evidence.
Han Yongnan
is released on bail pending trial.
During this period,
you can't leave
Lanfang County.
Leave the court.
He is coming out.
[Lanfang County Magistrate's Office]
Bureaucrats shielding one another.
Exactly.
He is a villain.
Han Yongnan,
I'll kill you!
What are you doing?
Calm down.
The Magistrate will give you justice.
[Wangdong]
I'm Wangdong, Rui's elder brother.
He harmed my sister.
I can't let him off!
Don't let him off!
I'm not guilty.
Stop shouting!
The law can't even convict me.
Who are you guys?
Stop shouting!
Magistrate,
in broad daylight...
Let go!
He committed physical assault.
You can't just
let it go like that.
Magistrate,
please give us justice.
Avenge my sister!
This boy committed physical assault
on the street.
Take him into custody.
Magistrate.
What kind of magistrate are you?
Why standing there? Take him away.
You are just a corrupt official!
Corrupt official!
Go.
There is no reason
for the wicked to go unpunished.
Corrupt official!
Magistrate,
I also grew up in Chang'an
since I was a child.
After all,
we can understand
each other.
We aren't like them.
If you don't mind,
please come
to my mansion
to have a drink this evening.
Let's have a good talk.
Goodbye.
Lecher!
Magistrate.
Magistrate,
you released Han Yongnan
and took Rui's brother into custody.
Can't you tell
the good from the bad?
The Magistrate didn't want to release him.
It's just that there is no reason
to detain him.
Mr. Hong,
we can't care
about all those rules now.
Can't you see the situation
in Rui's family?
Isn't she miserable enough?
Then why did you block
the hurt of a knife for him?
Because you work for the government.
You know
you should abide by the laws.
I said
I would raise
the flag of law in Lanfang County.
No one
should let reason
outweigh legal reason at any time.
Wangdong committed physical assault
in broad daylight.
He should be taken into custody
according to the law.
The evidence is inadequate.
Han Yongnan
should be released according to the law.
Understand me?
I can't win the argument with you.
I've worked with you for so many years.
I've never seen you look so weak.
Do you also have something to say?
No.
Follow me.
Give me all the files
related to Han Yongnan's case.
Mr. Hong
asked someone to bring back
this year's new tea from Luoyang.
I'll make you a pot of tea.
This man is Yun Gang
from Chongshan Ward.
He is a famous lecher in Lanfang County.
He deceived and afflicted
countless girls and young women.
A few days ago,
a woman just hung herself
because she was pregnant with his baby.
Look.
Today, his corpse
appeared outside the city.
Another murder for hire.
The third one in this month.
It must be the parents
of the woman who hung herself
or her husband's family.
If they hired a killer,
you can catch them and interrogate them.
No evidence, no witnesses.
Now this corpse
just proves that it was a murder for hire.
You can't blame anyone.
Look,
it's so easy to take revenge.
Now people would rather pay someone
to settle their scores.
But those who were killed
were not innocent.
Who can be the murderer?
This man has a ruthless way
of killing people.
The murders seem to be done
by the same person.
If the Magistrate can bring
all the murderers
and scumbags like Han Yongnan
to justice,
there will be no more grievances
or suffering in Lanfang County.
If there are no more grievances
or suffering,
this can only happen after death
not in Lanfang County.
Most of us are ordinary people.
To be an ordinary man is to be selfish.
The law
is also made by ordinary people.
Nothing is omnipotent.
Mr. Hong,
I don't understand this.
Now that the law
is made by ordinary people,
why does the Magistrate
insist on following it?
He has good reason
for his insistence.
We just have to cooperate with him.
How did your investigation
into the relationship
between Qian Hao and Heiyan go?
Except for Qian Hao,
no one in the Black Tiger Gang
knows anything about Heiyan.
Not even his closest associates
have seen him communicate with anyone.
It feels like the Black Tiger Gang
only works for themselves.
Was Qian Hao a member of Heiyan before?
Later, Heiyan disbanded.
He organized the Black Tiger Gang himself?
He could have slipped through the cracks.
We've been here
for more than six months.
But we only saw
the marks he left.
Have you investigated the 3,000 qian?
Such a large amount of money.
Who sent it to the Jin's? When?
You may find something
from these details.
I clearly know Rui was harmed
by Han Yongnan.
Miss Jin is totally illiterate.
It's obvious she was forced
to sign the contract.
I clearly know Wangdong
was extremely indignant.
If I were
young and impulsive,
I would do the same.
But what could I do?
To release Han Yongnan
was the only thing I could do.
No one in this world
has the right
to take the life of another.
Han Yongnan has no right.
Vice versa.
Before he is brought to justice,
keeping Wangdong
in the Magistrate's Office
is the best protection for him.
You are not wrong.
I think as time goes on
with this case,
you will come to a conclusion.
Take a look
at these cases.
I'm afraid
you might miss something.
All are missing person cases.
The age, gender,
and time of disappearance
of the missing persons
are all irregular.
But if you look
at their household registrations,
they are all from a village
near the silver mine
in the suburbs of Lanfang County.
Liushui?
The Jin family also lives there.
Because of the silver mine,
these villages have lost their crops
in recent years.
Nothing grows on the land.
Maybe they have detached
from their household registrations
to survive.
Even if they did that,
I will investigate it clearly.
Open the door.
Yes.
Are you hungry?
Have some.
Stop glaring at me.
Your eyes are about to drop out.
Corrupt official.
I'm not an official.
I'm just here to make a living.
I hurt you just now.
You hate a man so much
that you can't wait to kill him.
Did you kill the man?
I'll tell you after you eat the flatbread.
Magistrate.
I just asked them.
You will be released
early in the morning tomorrow.
After you go back,
if you still want to take revenge
on Han Yongnan,
I can't see it this time.
I won't interfere.
Okay?
Impossible.
He has many guards at his silver mine.
There are also ferocious dogs.
I can't get in there.
Don't worry.
Magistrate Di
will avenge you.
He is the best man I've ever seen.
Why did he release Han Yongnan today?
The evidence is inadequate.
Do you need evidence to punish a bad guy?
No.
You need evidence for everything.
You say he killed someone,
but he says he didn't.
Who should we believe?
If we can catch or kill someone
without evidence,
what's the difference
between us and a gang?
If the government is so indiscriminate,
it's worse than Heiyan.
How did you know Heiyan?
I've heard the legend.
What legend?
People say
when Heiyan was here,
people were afraid to break the law.
Because Heiyan
would not just work for those
who were rich and powerful
or those scholars
who confused right and wrong.
Even if we had no money,
as long as we joined them,
they would help us get rid of the people
who hurt us.
They are talking nonsense.
Who told you this?
You are still siding
with the corrupt official.
Heiyan is better than you.
Brat, you piss me off!
Whatever, I'm done with you.
Take it.
Ma Rong,
come out!
Corrupt official!
Take out the knife.
Corrupt official,
let me out!
Corrupt official!
Why are you looking at me?
Punish me if you want.
I'm just not convinced.
Why?
Why is it always the good guys who lose?
Why are you such a coward today?
When facing Han Yongnan,
you couldn't say anything.
You worked so hard to be an official.
Why did you end up
being called a corrupt official?
Since you said
that we can't conclude a case
without evidence,
I won't punish you this time.
Release him
tomorrow.
Okay.
The two dead women
were both singsong girls
in the entertainment house in the city.
They were taken here last night.
Go find the butler.
Now there is something
called Five Stone Powder
in the capital.
After you take it,
the fun will double
and you'll feel like in heaven.
Are you okay?
How are you doing?
Nice!
Let go of her!
Arrest
Han Yongnan.
Yes.
[Lanfang County Magistrate's Office]
Under such circumstances,
Master doesn't let us disturb him.
We dare not ask anything.
Does he take that drug
every time he takes girls back?
The drug
was brought back from the capital.
It's not always available.
At times, maybe.
Animal!
At the hour of Mao,
the maid
who brought tea to Master
discovered their bodies.
It's her.
What did you discover
when you brought tea to your master?
Magistrate,
she can't talk.
She is a mute.
You really didn't see Han Yongnan?
No.
I dare not deceive you.
You saw it yourself.
All the horses in the stable
are there.
From last night
to this morning,
no one came in or out.
Magistrate,
people in the suburbs also confirmed
that Han Yongnan hadn't left the city.
An order for arrest has been issued.
He can't escape.
The silver mine is a restricted area.
You need a search warrant
from the state government to get in.
This is Mr. Di,
the magistrate of Lanfang County.
He has been appointed by His Majesty.
Open the gate.
Silver mines are the lifeblood
of the court.
We only recognize the seal
of the state government.
We now have every reason
to suspect that the silver mine
harbors a murderer.
Open the gate.
If you dare barge in,
don't blame us for being rude.
Han Yongnan,
the owner of the silver mine,
disguised himself and ran away
in a mining carriage.
If you saw the carriage
of the silver mine leaving today,
report to us quickly.
[Arrest Warrant]
Those who cover up
will be dealt with according to the law.
Take a look.
Did you see him today?
No.
I haven't seen him all day.
You didn't see him?
Are you sure you haven't seen him today?
You still let him escape.
What are you looking at?
Do you want to see her?
Come in.
See?
My sister is as good as dead now.
If you hadn't stopped me,
I would have killed him.
A life for a life.
I shouldn't have reported the case.
I should go to Heiyan directly.
Don't talk nonsense.
Let go of me!
You too.
Get lost!
You all get lost!
Get out!
And you,
get out!
He released him.
Bullying us commoners.
Corrupt official.
Really a corrupt official!
Please trust me.
I will catch Han Yongnan
and bring him to justice.
Leave us alone.
It's out of your hands.
Get lost!
Leave here!
Get lost, corrupt official!
Get lost!
There is no trace
of Han Yongnan in the city.
Magistrate,
where could he possibly go?
it was confirmed
that a carriage of the silver mine
did leave the city
at the beginning of Mao hour.
It left at a fast speed.
On the carriage,
there was a man dressed like a stableman.
Left the city?
How could you let him leave?
Hasn't the arrest warrant
for Han Yongnan been issued?
His clothes and appearance
could not be linked to Han Yongnan.
There's no problem
with his identity papers.
Yesterday,
Han Yongnan was just released.
We really didn't expect it.
Please forgive us.
Get up.
Where was the carriage going?
Toward Liuli Post
in the west of the city.
[Liuli Post]
Liuli Post should be right ahead.
Magistrate.
I...
I haven't finished my words yet.
The posthouse official of Liuli Post
can't be intimidated
by Han Yongnan, can he?
Magistrate,
someone has just left.
He never lets me finish my words.
I think
we should hide here.
It's a desert out there.
He has to ride you if he wants to leave.
If we hide here,
we can catch him off guard.
Good idea.
Han Yongnan?
What did you say to my horse?
Don't move.
With one wrong move,
my arrow could take your life!
Who are you?
Good.
Three to one.
Three people.
One bow.
If you kill me,
you will be cut into pieces.
Cut into pieces?
Who are you?
I'm not the one you are looking for.
How did you get the horse?
Who said that was my horse?
You can't get here without a horse.
You flew here?
Two hours ago, I exchanged horses
with a man.
Exchange horses?
Yes.
He looks very refined.
There is a mole on his eyelid.
Where did you exchange them?
You are pointing your sword at me.
I can't remember it.
How about this?
I'll count to three.
Let's put down our weapons then.
One,
two,
three.
Stop!
I trust him.
Magistrate.
Just now, he deliberately shot the arrow
in front of my feet.
Who are you?
My surname is Diao.
[Diao Xiaoguan]
My given name is Xiaoguan.
Let's have a chat.
If I'd known this guy was a sleazy guy,
I should have
charged him more money.
Get to the point.
Two hours ago...
Now it should be three hours ago.
He was heading for Yiwu County.
Even if we ride as fast as we can,
it will take us a day
to catch up with him.
Us?
I have to get my horse back.
I can't let such a guy ride it.
I don't need you to go with us.
I'll buy this horse.
You can go.
Okay.
I can sell you the horse.
But can you tell me
your name?
My surname is Di.
The surname is Di?
What about your first name?
You have to keep it a secret?
Could it be Daguan?
[*Corresponding to the name Xiaoguan]
Daguan,
don't you think this posthouse is weird?
Sir,
some people have come.
They must be hiding something in there.
Magistrate Di.
Magistrate, you've come from afar.
I should have welcomed you earlier.
It's my fault.
You know me?
My surname is Pang.
[Mr. Pang, the posthouse official]
I live in Lanfang County.
I'm just
working here.
Did you see
this man today?
No.
The posthouse
didn't receive anyone these days.
Magistrate,
please have some tea.
Wait.
What's in there?
Nothing.
We just hunted two deer a few days ago.
Qiao Tai.
Don't move.
Magistrate.
Really a high-ranking official.
Magistrate,
these are their indentures of sale
signed by their parents.
I'm not lying to you.
Magistrate,
I did not
violate the law of Tang.
You got a right
because you didn't break the law?
There are a lot of merchants
coming and going at the border.
I'm just
pocketing the difference.
As for how they would use the girls,
I never ask them.
If a good family
can adopt the girl,
isn't it a good thing?
Nonsense!
Ma Rong.
If you go on talking,
I'll cut your balls.
Magistrate,
I didn't violate the law.
I didn't violate the law, Magistrate.
Ma Rong,
he really didn't break the law of Tang.
I can't catch him.
I will buy
these girls.
Don't traffic people again.
I won't.
Otherwise,
I won't spare you.
Ma Rong,
give me your money.
I know nothing about the law.
But I have a conscience.
When you are on the way,
hold on to each other's clothes.
Don't get separated.
Make sure the girls
are safely returned to the city.
Come to me with the city defense.
What are you doing?
Okay.
Are you crazy?
Kill them!
Magistrate.
Let's go.
The bandits are coming.
Hide now.
Go hide now.
Close the gate quickly.
Don't come here. Find a place yourself.
Jerk!
Airhead, you'll die in vain.
Kill them!
Magistrate!