[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 2]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
Put out the fire.
Fire.
Huaiying...
Put out the fire.
Huaiying.
Fire...
Put out the fire.
Go away.
Make way.
Hurry.
Move it.
- Huaiying.
- Mr. Di?
Huaiying.
Qiao Tai, hurry. Follow them.
I'll find a way.
Okay.
Quick.
Keep up.
[Fairness fosters discernment]
The scribe of musicians.
A hidden door.
Hurry up.
Hurry up and sign it.
This...
I can't sign this.
It says here
that the fire
at Jushui Entertainment House
broke out because of Heaven's wrath.
But Jushui Entertainment House
was on fire inside,
not outside.
How can you say it's a Heavenly Fire?
Well...
Then tell me.
Where
did the fire come from?
I...
If you can't tell,
then
you set the fire.
To know where the fire came from,
we need to investigate the scene,
find out where the fire started,
and what caused the fire.
You haven't even investigated yet.
There's no proof.
How could you say that I set the fire?
How dare you!
I...
Of course, I have proof.
Nine people, eight died.
You're the only one who survived.
If it's not you,
are you going to say it's me?
If I really wanted to commit the crime,
how could I have let myself
end up like this?
A person like you
from a shady background
could do anything.
Someone,
beat him
until he's willing to tell the truth.
Yes.
Stop.
Move aside.
Apologies for the belated welcome.
Please.
Mr. Wei.
Di Renjie
is the son of the former
Secretary General, Di Zhixun.
Not someone from a shady background.
Besides, he's right.
If he'd committed the crime,
he wouldn't have been in this state.
Di Renjie was once my student.
I have faith in his character
and his intellect.
Mr. Wei,
please forgive me
for making such a reckless statement.
Someone,
take the prisoner to the back office
for investigation.
Yes.
Mr. Wei,
this is
what happened.
Mr. Wei,
according to the sergeant,
the scene was charred black.
No trace can be found.
The coroner is still examining the body.
We can't find any clues
about this case.
I have no idea
where to start.
Mr. Wei,
I didn't set the fire.
As for whether the fire
at Jushui Entertainment House
was a natural disaster
or a man-made disaster,
I volunteer to investigate it
to prove my innocence.
You want to investigate it?
Within ten days,
if I can't solve the case,
I'll take the blame.
If you're afraid I'll escape,
you can send my portrait
to the guards at the city gates.
Your portrait?
What's the use of your portrait?
All the villains know
how to disguise themselves these days.
Mr. Wei,
it's not that I don't want to help.
It's just
against the rules.
Mr. Wei,
He Dajing was your assistant
and your favorite student.
He was also my friend.
I hate to see him die in vain.
Please help me.
Let's do this.
I have an idea.
This black iron is indestructible.
Without the key,
it's impossible to open it.
With this as proof,
even if he disguises himself,
he won't be able to get out of Chang'an
as long as you notify the gate guards.
I'll have him stay in my residence
and keep an eye on him.
With me as the guarantor,
you can rest assured.
Every day at the You hour,
be sure to return
to the Magistrate's Office
and make daily reports.
[Wannian County Magistrate's Office]
He was about to close the case
with a fire caused by a thunderbolt.
Why go out of your way
to complicate things?
We can't blame Heaven
for human sin.
What if you fail to find out the truth?
As long as it's man-made,
clues will be left behind.
And I'll be able to find out the truth.
Be careful.
Let me know what you find
so I can help you.
Thank you, Mr. Wei.
[Day one]
How
did this fire start?
Was it struck by lightning again,
just like the Wutong tree?
How come she's the only one
who's intact?
The other bodies
were all burned to death.
Only this one
was found in another room.
She was choked to death.
How did you get in here?
What...
Don't...
Don't touch it.
What...
Let's have a chat.
What do you want?
Come...
You...
I'm telling you.
- Don't do anything reckless.
- You know Mr. Wei, right?
Mr. Wei.
Don't do anything reckless.
Mr. Wei sent us here.
Grand Secretariat Wei.
I know him.
This key
is from the palace.
What a beautiful...
lady.
This is the third batch.
If the Jinwu Guards are in such a hurry,
something big must've happened
in the palace.
In the palace?
What could happen in the palace?
If we find out who owns this thing,
we should know it.
How can we do that?
Judging from the gilt threads
and the vermilion coloring,
ordinary people can't afford it.
The East Market
has a fragrance shop, Jingyuan Pavilion.
The best fragrances from Hu merchants
are always supplied there first.
Go and find out
who bought
these fragrances.
Mr. Di, where are you going?
Let's go. To the East Market.
[Jushui Entertainment House]
This is...
Did someone lock the door
from the outside?
There's a hidden door, right?
Where does it lead?
You must be mistaken, sir.
There's no such a door.
Yaxin.
Yaxin, it's on fire. Come out.
The other bodies
were all burned to death.
Only this one
was found in another room.
She was choked to death.
Yaxin, open the door now.
Open the door.
Sister.
Sister, open the door.
Open the door.
Why was there
a palace maid hiding
in Jushui Entertainment House?
I've checked it out.
The sachet contains a mixture of myrrh,
sandalwood, and Yujin.
All of them are the Empress's
favorite fragrance.
Could it be that the lady
was from the Empress's palace?
There's surely
something secretive about her.
That's why
the Jinwu Guards
were all over the street.
They're all looking for her.
[Left Jinwu Guards]
Who's disturbing the Jinwu Guards?
I know the identity of that body.
You do?
She's the Empress's palace maid,
who is responsible for treasures.
General.
[Kang Zhiyi]
It's her.
Search Pingkang Ward.
Yes.
Everyone,
search Pingkang Ward.
Don't miss a single corner.
Who is he?
The Empress's guard,
General Kang Zhiyi.
What has the Empress lost?
Judging from this,
it must be something valuable.
Life,
death,
power.
Everyone is terrified of them.
This threatens the very foundation
of our state.
Your Majesty.
We must investigate it.
Such an important matter happened.
[Emperor]
Your Majesty, you must be prudent.
Please think twice.
Your Majesty,
please make a fair judgment.
Your Majesty, I implore you
to make a decision.
Your Majesty.
You must be prudent, Your Majesty.
You must be prudent.
Your Majesty.
Please make a decision.
[Grand Commandant Zhangsun]
Please make a decision, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty.
The loss of the Phoenix Seal
means the imperial authority is at stake.
It was used by villains
to kill the Governor of Yangzhou,
Chen Zhuliang, with poison.
The court is in a state of panic.
The loss of the Phoenix Seal
is an act of misdeeds by the Empress.
She must be severely punished.
Your Majesty,
please
make your decision.
Your Majesty, please make your decision.
[Empress]
[Day three]
[Bulletin of the Court]
What are you looking for?
Look at the mess you've caused.
Who on earth are you?
Who do I look like?
From the government?
From the General's Residence?
From the palace?
Shh.
Don't ask.
It'll bring you trouble.
Excuse me,
how much is this?
It's ten wen.
It's too expensive.
It's not expensive.
I can give you a discount.
It's so pretty.
How much is it?
Eight wen each.
This lady is so beautiful.
You should give her a discount.
- Five wen.
- That's right.
Okay. Fine. Five wen.
All right, pay him.
Five wen it is.
Thank you.
Come here and take a look.
Hello, take a look.
Excuse me, can I try this?
Of course. Have a try.
This is delicious.
Really?
Have a taste.
Let me try it.
Really?
Here.
Have a taste.
Don't just eat it.
Are you buying or not?
Yes, you have to buy
what you need to buy.
You have to pay
for what you need to pay.
Okay.
What's that on your face?
They say it wards off evil spirits.
And you believe that?
Let's go.
Mr. Di is waiting for the Bulletin.
You're taking it too seriously.
I'll go back later.
[Wei's Residence]
Huaiying,
as expected from someone
who has been to Western Regions.
You're so knowledgeable.
I envy you.
Unlike me.
Every day,
I'm stuck in the Imperial Academy,
looking miserable and gloomy
all day long.
I've been copying documents
and writing articles endlessly.
These years,
if it weren't for Mr. Wei's care,
I'd hardly be able to make a living.
Stop drinking.
Drinking can easily lead to a mistake.
I've never made a mistake
because of drinking.
Someone spiked my drink
that day.
What's this?
It's all fate.
People are now living in fear.
They're all saying it's Heaven's wrath.
What ''Heaven's wrath''?
Tell me.
The Empress's favorite Wutong tree
was struck by a thunderbolt.
The entertainment house she liked
was also struck by a thunderbolt
and caught fire.
What else could this be
if not a warning from Heaven?
Jushui Entertainment House
didn't catch fire because it was struck
by a thunderbolt.
You didn't tell me anything,
so I must go outside
to listen to these rumors.
It's not Heaven's wrath.
You're just like the Master,
a miser with words.
Mr. Wei.
Do you know
what He Dajing liked?
For the past few days,
I've been dreaming about him.
But in my dreams,
I can't see his face clearly.
He had been with me
since he was a child.
But recently, I realized
that I didn't know him at all.
He liked drinking,
always carrying a wineskin.
He liked writing poetry.
I like to have a sip every day,
but I don't dare
in front of Mr. Wei.
So don't tell Mr. Wei
about our drinking today.
I didn't know all of this.
He was a timid child,
always careful
with what he said and did.
Being with me for more than ten years,
he never dared to speak out.
And I was mostly
criticizing
and nitpicking him.
My condolences, Mr. Wei.
He has gone.
I'm worried about you now.
Two days have passed.
Do you have any idea
where the fire started?
Jushui Entertainment House
is full of flammable materials.
It's hard to find where the fire started.
The Governor of Yangzhou, Chen Zhuliang.
Five years ago, for opposing
the establishment of the Empress,
he was demoted
to Yangzhou of Nanshan Circuit.
A few days ago,
he was forcibly poisoned
and killed by a forged imperial decree
with the Phoenix Seal on it.
It was because of this
that the theft of the Phoenix Seal
was uncovered.
But the 11th day of the fifth month...
It's exactly
the second day after the incident
at Jushui Entertainment House.
Is this related to the incident
at Jushui Entertainment House?
Yes.
That night,
someone went to
Jushui Entertainment House.
He knew there would be a fire
and locked the gate,
preventing anyone
from entering or leaving.
[Jushui Entertainment House]
It was a fluke
that I survived.
Who wanted to kill you?
He did not want to kill us.
The person he wanted to kill
was the palace maid
responsible for the Seal, Yaxin.
Yaxin
stole the Phoenix Seal
entrusted to her care.
After the deed was done,
she was silenced.
According to the report
from Wannian County,
the musician in charge
of Jushui Entertainment House
was from the same hometown as Yaxin.
So many people were implicated
because of Yaxin.
Did you report this to the magistrate
of Wannian County?
Not yet.
It is all
just my speculation.
There is no proof.
But the incident
at Jushui Entertainment House
and the loss of the Phoenix Seal
are inextricably linked.
I'm afraid the fire
was set by the one who stole the seal,
an enemy of the Empress.
You've read
so many Bulletins of the Court,
why don't you understand?
The Empress' reforms
have offended too many people.
What I want to say is
that Yangzhou's Bulletin of the Court
are not true.
I do not believe
anyone will resist the reforms.
What changed by the Empress's reform
of the imperial examination
was the monopoly of the eminent families.
The agricultural reforms
no longer penalize displaced migrants.
Allowing them to settle down nearby
and giving them farmland.
People can farm,
and plants can be grown.
This is what I've seen
with my own eyes
during my travels over the years.
Just because you saw it
with your own eyes,
does it mean it's true?
The Empress's Phoenix Seal is missing.
All the examination papers
have been sealed and stored
and won't be marked.
The Institute
for the Advancement of Literature
is now a mess.
Those who support the Empress
and those who oppose her
are fighting.
I've never had anything
to do with politics.
I'm too old and just want
to avoid trouble.
But you should know that in Chang'an,
there are too many people
who oppose the Empress.
They're so vicious
and don't need to hide.
They all have their own hidden agendas
and are all in high positions.
Chang'an
is not yours or mine.
It's theirs.
I wonder when you got this habit
of pilfering along the way.
How can you call this stealing?
I just took it in passing.
Okay, you just took it in passing.
But why didn't you
take something valuable?
What's the point
of taking this pile of junk?
It's called
souvenirs.
Wrong direction.
What are you up to?
Is Mr. Di around?
He's not.
I'll go find him.
He's not around.
Some things must be done
when he's not around.
Mr. Hong,
I was looking for you.
This is my handmade Biluo.
I have both sweet and salty flavors.
Have a taste.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
If you have something to ask,
say it here.
You look like you have something
to ask of me.
If nothing, why so ingratiating?
I can't eat this.
I just want to get to know Mr. Di.
For example,
is there anyone else in this family?
Mr. Di's parents
died young.
Well,
does he have siblings?
No,
he's the only child.
Pity him then.
He's an orphan like me.
Even though
Mr. Di
is the only one left now,
he's from a family
that all works for the government,
not the same person
as he is now.
It has nothing to do
with his family background.
If one lives in the world
alone all the time,
one will feel lonely.
Are you worried
that he can't solve the case?
I'm not worried
that he can't solve the case.
- I'm worried about his...
- You're worried about his safety.
Mr. Hong,
don't worry.
From now on,
we will make sure he's safe,
just like you.
You're back.
Come on. Have a taste.
This is my handmade Biluo.
I'm not hungry.
At least try it.
This is the man you want to know.
That's the way he is.
You never know what he's thinking.
[Wei's Residence]
A burnt rope.
Someone set the fire...
and then
locked the escape door
with a leather cord from the outside.
This is never a Heavenly Fire.
Never.
A farmhouse on the outskirts
of Wannian County
[Day four]
was burned by a Heavenly Fire last night.
The report says four people died
in the fire.
What should we do?
Go. Call the coroner.
Magistrate,
the coroner suddenly fell ill
two days ago,
with a flushed face,
continuous sneezing,
and took sick leave at home.
Of all times, why now?
Let me try.
I know a bit about medicine.
Sure... Take a look.
What do you find?
The four bodies
are all male.
They have calluses on their palms
and purlicues.
They were all burned to death.
I know that!
Yeah.
Wait.
They already were dead
before the fire started.
In his mouth,
there's no dust.
I'll go into the scene and take a look.
You...
Follow him.
Yes.
I'll go in the scene, too.
It's burned to a crisp.
What kind of clues can we get?
Let's just do it.
What did you find?
At the murder scene,
anything found
must be turned over to the gover...
What's wrong?
It's just a bunch of dead silkworms.
What's the big deal?
You, go over there and check.
Why these silkworms?
What are you doing?
I want to take some silkworms
and check again.
No need to do so.
Someone,
take these bodies
and everything we found here
back to the office.
Come here. Clean this place up.
Wait...
Magistrate,
let me investigate again.
I'm sure I can find something.
No need to do so.
This case involves the palace.
It's out of my hands.
If you want to investigate,
go to see the Minister of Justice.
Go.
Magistrate,
let me investigate again, please.
Today
is the fourth day.
It's hot.
So hot...
It's so hot.
Don't you get it?
You can't solve this case.
It's a clash of giants.
It's so hot.
Hurry up.
Let's go.
Let's go back and rest.
Let's go. Hurry up.
- Yes.
Careful.
Watch out.
You've got something?
Look ahead. Slow down...
Okay.
Sure.
That magistrate of Wannian County said
''Why these silkworms?''
What does it mean?
Empress Wu emulates Empress Zhangsun
and performs rites on sericulture.
By traditional rites,
be close to people, raise silkworms,
and reel silk by herself.
Who raises silkworms near Chang'an?
So I'm afraid the silkworms
were from the rites on sericulture.
They were spread over farmhouses
to show the Empress's
virtue of caring for all the people.
So this is just an ordinary farmhouse.
It's a farmhouse,
but maybe
it's not ordinary.
I'm afraid those people there
aren't ordinary farmers either.
What do you mean?
There must be something on the bodies.
The problem
is I'm not authorized to examine them.
I can't go any further.
If we walk back to Chang'an like this,
how long do we have to walk? I...
Heaven help the good ones.
There are three. Just one for each of us.
Wait.
Four.
That's weird.
These horses don't look like wild horses.
I've seen these horses before.
[Daning Ward]
They're the Yulin Guards.