[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 20]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
Magistrate!
Mind your own business!
Magistrate, they have reinforcements.
Just run away.
Are you still a man?
Not as manly as you.
Let's go.
Don't move.
Magistrate,
they are just a few roving bandits.
Watch out for their big troops.
They might launch attacks at any time.
Don't think I would thank you.
Magistrate,
he's been following us all along.
Go.
Mutton.
Fresh mutton. Take a look.
Mutton. Sheepskin.
Magistrate,
he has been following us all along.
How do you know he is following us?
Perhaps he is also coming to the fair.
Well,
we don't know his identity.
What if he is a bandit?
I don't care about his identity.
Even if he is from Heiyan, I don't care.
What I want to know
is his purpose.
Okay.
How much?
It's for free.
I'll water the horse.
What's this?
She can't understand your language.
I'll trade you this knife for this.
This is a Wolf Drug.
If you spread a bottle of this
on the ground,
it can attract all the wolfdogs
within a five-li radius.
There is such a powerful Wolf Drug
in the Western Regions?
It's such a big world.
There are a lot of things
we've never seen,
languages you can't comprehend,
and rules you don't understand.
Is this okay?
This should be okay.
Tali.
Sir.
Why are you crying?
Ask him
what's the matter with him.
Tali.
What happened?
My eagle died.
I had kept it for 13 years.
He said he had seen Han Yongnan.
Where did he see him?
Tali.
Ask him.
How did it die?
I wanted to take it to the fair
and buy some food.
Who would have known
that it died on the way?
It was too late. I couldn't take it away.
So I buried it in the desert.
Tali.
He said his daughter had seen
the arrest warrant.
She wanted to report it.
But Han Yongnan killed her.
Her body is still in the desert.
Tali is his daughter's name.
Tell him
I will definitely catch Han Yongnan.
Tali.
We will find it.
You must find it.
Tali.
I told him.
But he said...
Tali.
He hopes you can kill him yourself.
Ask him
if he knows which way
Han Yongnan fled.
Where is it buried?
Over there.
Magistrate,
that eagle seemed
to have followed us all along.
Look ahead.
[Zhenxi Fortress]
This is the frontier Zhenxi Fortress.
It's the westmost place.
I am Di Renjie,
the Magistrate of Lanfang County.
Why should I believe you?
Do you know what that place is?
We risk our lives to stay here
in case the bandits break in
and to guard against you spies.
What nonsense are you talking about?
Who are spies?
Several hours ago,
we just fought the bandits.
Magistrate Di,
why did you come all the way here
from Lanfang County?
They are chasing an escaped criminal.
He must be here now.
How does
that man look?
He has big eyes
and looks very gentle.
There is a mole between his eyes.
Follow me.
I might have seen the man
you are looking for.
I'm a soldier in the protectorate.
I'm responsible
for guarding Zhenxi Fortress.
[Huo Huaili]
My name is Huo Huaili.
Open the gate.
[Zhenxi Fortress]
That
is the man you are looking for.
He's dead?
Don't touch him.
The plague.
Half a day ago,
he knocked at the gate,
saying he was a merchant.
Their caravan was attacked by bandits.
Only he survived.
We had
taken him in.
But he tried to steal a horse
to cross the border.
He also killed a man.
Magistrate,
bandits,
plague,
and sandstorm
scare us already.
Time for dinner.
Yours.
Magistrate Di,
the weather is cold.
I've brought some wine
to warm everyone up.
Not really very good wine.
Please don't mind it.
Magistrate Di,
when you go back,
please give the governor a message
for me.
Tell him
that everything is fine here.
If the visiting envoy comes here,
a lot of money will be spent.
We also need to receive him.
It's better to save the money.
We can buy some military hardware
and pay the soldiers.
You said he had stolen a horse
and had killed someone.
Who did he kill?
He is called Zhou Changyi.
From Ezhou.
Zhou Changyi.
Actually, there is one good thing
if a man is dead.
Others can share
his portion of food.
To Zhou Changyi.
Zhou Changyi.
Open the gate.
If I had known he was a wanted man,
I wouldn't have given him a quick death.
What are you eating?
Is it tasty?
Is this
what you usually eat?
Why don't you ask your officer to write
a letter to the military administration?
The visiting envoy will come
to take care of you.
The garrison is relieved
every four years.
There are people taking care of this.
But we don't need the visiting envoy.
If you have nothing to do,
go back and rest early.
This is a military area.
Don't walk around.
The wine is good.
Take it slow.
He is drunk.
It's okay.
Lash mark.
Magistrate, look,
this city
has to ward against bandits,
thieves,
and wolves.
They are all thinking
about how to barge in and devour us.
When I just came,
I was so terrified
that I couldn't sleep all night.
But now
I can't even remember where this is.
I
belong here when I'm alive.
I will become a ghost here after I die.
Did he leave any words
before he died?
I don't quite understand.
People say the Lanfang County dialect
is difficult to understand.
He was mumbling something.
Very hard to understand.
I remember
before he was strangled to death,
he was mumbling
that he was fed up to the back teeth.
Magistrate,
I also grew up in Chang'an
since I was a child.
After all,
we can understand
each other.
[Archive]
Well, what are you looking for?
That was not
Han Yongnan's body.
I'm checking the background
of these soldiers in Zhenxi Fortress.
Their native places,
enlistment time,
and usual weapons.
Why are you checking
all this information?
Here is a record
about Huo Huaili.
His usual weapon
is a three-section whip.
A whip?
Lash mark.
Just now,
I did see lash marks
on those soldiers.
So
they were caused
by the three-section whip.
No wonder the barracks are so dead.
Huo Huaili is so despicable.
But I think
they respect Huo Huaili very much.
Most of these soldiers
are from a place
called Zhou Village
in Ezhou.
Among them,
there are two brothers.
Zhou Changyong.
Zhou Changyi.
What's hiding under there?
Let's go take a look.
Go over there to take a look.
This...
This is Huo Huaili's three-section whip?
Magistrate Di,
now that you've discovered it,
please come out.
What are you going to do with us?
You will make up
a reason that we stole horses
to cross the border.
Then you will kill us
and hang our bodies?
You are an official
appointed by the court.
If I kill you,
I will be cut into pieces.
You know the law of Tang?
Just because I know the law,
I killed Huo Huaili.
Zhou Changyi.
[Huo Huaili]
[Zhou Changyi]
Your commanding officer
Huo Huaili
[Three-section iron whip]
killed your brother Zhou Changyong.
So, you killed him.
You incited a riot,
offended your superior,
and assumed his identity.
According to the law,
you should have been killed
several times.
He did as he pleased.
He beat us whenever he wanted.
But that is called
training new soldiers.
It was not a crime.
When he was in a bad mood,
he took it out on us soldiers.
This is called giving exhortations.
It was not a crime, either.
He beat my brother to death.
But this is called accidental homicide.
He still couldn't be convicted.
We couldn't bear it.
We had nowhere to complain.
We were even punished by him.
He locked us up for seven days
without giving us food or water.
In order to survive,
we had no choice
but to kill him.
However,
we have thus committed a heinous crime
and should be sentenced to death.
Magistrate Di,
who does the law
actually support?
Whose law is this?
If you want to arrest Changyi,
kill me first!
Don't move.
Don't be silly.
Don't move. Put down the knife.
They just want to survive.
They did nothing wrong.
Huo Huaili deserved to die.
I tell you,
if I were a soldier here,
I would do the same.
Speak!
Huo Huaili
did deserve to die.
But there are thousands of soldiers
guarding the borders of Tang.
If they all mutinied
and killed their officers
because the latter
were tyrannical,
the prosperity and stability of Tang
would be lost.
Well,
what should we do
at that time?
Bravo.
So high-sounding.
You tell me
what they can do.
They have no power.
They can only wait for death?
Cut the crap.
Get us out of here first.
Why?
You...
The less you have to do
in this world, the better.
Fine.
Okay.
I'll tell those soldiers later
that you are with us.
Let them bring you in, too.
Daguan,
who don't you speak?
You can't answer me?
What Zhou Changyi did
is very common in this world.
There are also many people
like Han Yongnan.
You didn't catch the ones
you should catch,
but caught the ones you shouldn't.
You stormed a hundred li
and now your life is in danger.
Is it worth it?
Zhou Changyi incited a riot
and killed his officer.
He deserves to die.
Han Yongnan raped a young girl
and broke the law of Tang.
He also deserves to die.
I, Di Renjie,
am an official appointed by the court.
I have to do this.
You remind me of my father.
He died of fever.
I actually hoped he was killed by someone.
That way, I could have an enemy.
I could travel a long way
to seek revenge
and kill the enemy to vent my hatred.
I could feel better that way.
I catch Han Yongnan
not to take revenge.
I'll take him back to Lanfang County
to stand trial.
Yes.
You will take him back
to your Magistrate's Office.
It will also be you
who will judge him
and execute him.
What's the difference?
I don't understand your laws or rules,
nor do I want to understand them.
But I know
all men, no matter how high or low,
are beasts
beneath the skin.
It's just that some are domineering
and some are trampled upon.
Han Yongnan is a dhole in Lanfang County,
showing his teeth.
But in this place,
he is not even a rat.
He could be torn into pieces
at any time.
There are bandits.
The bandits are coming.
What's the matter?
Come here.
Hurry up!
Attack!
Shoot them!
What do you want to do?
I'm warning you.
If you kill the Magistrate,
you will be cut into pieces.
Now the bandits are attacking us.
I must protect the city now.
You hurry up and leave.
Don't come back.
[Tang]
Push! Harder!
Harder!
Hurry up. Come and help!
[Zhenxi Fortress]
You can report it
to the military office.
But the riot
and the killing of Huo Huaili
were done by me alone.
It has nothing to do with others.
These soldiers are guarding this place.
They are patriotic
and loyal to the emperor.
They have made no mistake.