[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 21]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
The city defense have come.
Retreat.
Retreat quickly.
[Zhenxi Fortress]
Qiao Tai,
give this letter
to the military office.
It's about the entire process
of their mutiny.
Will they be sentenced to death?
They are just accessory criminals.
They did a great job
in suppressing the bandits.
They will be sent back
to their place of origin.
Magistrate,
no one will know
what happened here today
as long as we don't report it.
Just this once.
Okay?
Why do you insist on punishing them?
These soldiers
just fought the bandits like hell.
Can't they make up for it?
Zhou Changyi
even lost his life.
Isn't it enough?
No one will remember
how they were abused.
how they fought the enemies bravely.
If you send them back to their hometown,
people will think they are criminals.
It's their duty
to kill the enemy.
It's their crime
to kill their own people.
Don't confuse
the two.
Although Zhou Changyi
is dead,
his sin cannot be forgiven.
He must be punished by the law of Tang.
After you go back to Magistrate's Office,
tell Mr. Hong
to withdraw 2,000 qian
and send it to Zhou Changyi's family
in Zhou Village, Mei County,
Ezhou.
I'll leave
this place to you.
Where are you going?
Catch Han Yongnan.
Having a superior like that,
it's not easy for you.
To Zhou Changyi.
You didn't catch the ones
you should catch,
but caught the ones you shouldn't.
Now your life is in danger.
Is it worth it?
Daguan,
if your persistence
is just making people feel bad,
what's the point of it?
You should have killed
Han Yongnan.
You shouldn't have let him escape
from Lanfang County.
That way, it wouldn't have involved
so many people and things.
I will find him
and let him be punished by the law.
The law of Tang has been made
for less than a hundred years.
But rage,
vengeance,
and ambition
in the human heart
have never changed.
Anyhow,
without these things,
how could Tang
be founded?
I'll ask you one last question.
If in Lanfang County,
he killed your lover,
would you kill him on the spot?
I've told you.
I will catch him in person
and let him be punished by the law,
no matter who he has killed.
Fine.
I start to feel bored.
See you next time.
How old is she?
I don't want her if she is over 13.
Mr. Pang, she is only 12.
Do you have the indenture of sale?
Yes.
I tell you...
I'm talking to you. Look at me.
Magistrate.
Please spare my life, Magistrate.
Please spare my life.
Magistrate.
[Lanfang County]
Heaven isn't blind.
Retribution!
Magistrate Di,
you went west to search.
In the three directions
of east, south and north,
the people we sent
found no trace of Han Yongnan.
Is it possible
that he has gone to his brother
in Liangzhou?
Magistrate,
Mr. Hong has been here several times
asking about you.
Please go back
to Magistrate's Office first.
So he doesn't worry.
Lock him up.
Yes.
[Lanfang County]
Bravo!
Come on, do it.
Awesome!
Bravo!
One more time!
I'm sorry.
I didn't catch him
I failed to catch
the murderer who had killed Tali.
What are you talking about?
I failed to catch
the murderer
who had killed his daughter Tali.
What daughter?
Tali is his eagle.
His eagle died.
Tali.
He said he had seen Han Yongnan.
He said his daughter
had seen the arrest warrant.
She wanted to report it.
But Han Yongnan killed her.
Her body is still in the desert.
Tali is his daughter's name.
He hopes you can kill him yourself.
That night,
how many people did you see?
One
or two?
Was one of them
wearing a hat
and a veil?
Which way did you see
them going?
My surname is Diao.
My given name is Xiaoguan.
Let's have a chat.
An hour ago,
he was heading for Yiwu County.
Even if we ride as fast as we can,
it will take us a day
to catch up with him.
Magistrate,
he has been following us all along.
This is the frontier Zhenxi Fortress.
It's the westmost place.
Follow me.
I might have seen the man
you are looking for.
I don't understand your law or rules,
nor do I want to understand them.
But I know
all men, no matter how high or low,
are beasts
beneath the skin.
It's just that some are domineering
and some are trampled upon.
Han Yongnan is a dhole in Lanfang County,
showing his teeth.
But in this place,
he is not even a rat.
He could be torn into pieces at any time.
It turns out
you have never left.
Han Yongnan,
it serves you right.
Well done.
Think about your sister.
Think about what he has done.
The knife is in your hand.
You can let him
feel your pain.
Don't be afraid.
This is the punishment he deserves.
Wangdong,
kill him.
Kill him!
Wangdong,
kill him!
Kill him!
Stop!
Magistrate, save me!
You came faster than I thought.
He's been in Lanfang County.
He has never left.
Everything
has been arranged by you.
How could it be possible, Daguan?
I just found you
interesting
and was going along for the ride.
Magistrate Di,
do you know?
Han Yongnan has already dug
this place into an illegal mining hole.
If you dig three chi down,
you can dig through the ground.
You don't know it.
Look,
as a magistrate,
you don't even know this.
Wangdong,
put the knife down.
I will punish him for his crime.
Punish him?
Based on what?
Do you have evidence?
He didn't kill anyone.
I killed those two singsong girls.
Wangdong,
put the knife down.
I have found him now.
I'll give him the punishment he deserves.
You can't kill him.
Think about it, Wangdong.
How did he release Han Yongnan?
Do you trust him or yourself?
If you kill him,
you will also commit a crime.
You can take revenge with a knife in hand.
Go to hell!
Wangdong!
Wangdong,
put the knife down.
Han Yongnan will get the punishment
he deserves.
Don't be silly.
Have you always been this stubborn?
I thought
you could be more interesting.
Wangdong,
if you kill him,
you will also become a murderer.
You will also be punished by the law.
You are an official.
You have lots of ways.
Us commoners have no choice.
Can we just watch our family be killed?
Is it fair?
He is a good man.
He helped me.
Did you hear that?
He needs me. He needs us.
If the government is so indiscriminate,
it's worse than Heiyan.
As long as we joined them,
they would help us get rid of the people
who hurt us.
They are talking nonsense.
Who told you this?
Heiyan is better than you.
Don't listen to him.
He is from Heiyan.
At least, we can give him
justice that you can't give.
Wangdong,
do it now.
You don't have much time.
Magistrate,
help me.
Wangdong.
Magistrate, help me.
Daguan,
do you still want to play?
No more playing, right?
Help!
Help me.
Magistrate.
Help!
I'll kill you!
Wangdong!
Wangdong,
put the knife down.
I'll kill you!
Help me.
I will
kill you.
I'll kill you!
Help me.
Daguan,
do you still want to play?
This time,
you can't play anymore, right?
The last shot.
Let's make it simple.
The law of Tang has been made
for less than a hundred years.
But rage,
vengeance,
and ambition
in the human heart
have never changed.
But I'm an official
appointed by the court.
I have to do this.
You...
Daguan,
you win.
You are more skilled
in martial arts than me.
But Daguan,
you still lost.
Because your law
is nonsense.
This is Wolf Drug.
If you spread a bottle of this
on the ground,
it can attract all the wolf dogs
within a five-li radius.
Magistrate,
Han Yongnan is beyond recognition
as he was bitten badly.
So miserable.
He is not miserable.
He could die a hundred times
for what he did.
Look at you now.
You got yourself into this
just to stick to the law.
Is it worthwhile?
Stop.
He is already like this. Don't scold him.
[Lanfang County]
[Lanfang County Magistrate's Office]
Huaiying,
why did you exert yourself so much?
If something happened to you,
I...
- How can I explain it to your father?
- I'm still
alive.
You think you are still young.
I'll go get you some medicine.
Don't move.
It's okay.
I...
It doesn't hurt at all.
I know.
You are right.
Rest well.
Stop.
Go.
Magistrate.
Magistrate,
we've investigated it clearly.
We thought the missing villagers
in Liushui Village
and the surrounding areas tried to get rid
of their household registration.
In fact, they became
Han Yongnan's illegal workers.
All of them died in the mine.
We've found
all the corpses.
Han Yongnan engaged in over-exploitation.
The mine has been extended
to the surrounding villages.
The land became barren.
The water has been polluted.
The villagers couldn't make a living.
They could only become illegal workers.
Magistrate,
your persistence
is meaningful.
You are right.
Han Yongnan,
the owner of the silver mine
in Lanfang County,
engaged in over-exploitation
and detention of workers,
resulting in the death of workers.
He was morally bankrupt.
He raped a young girl under age
and was extremely evil.
The aim
is to support administration by law.
Violence and adultery are forbidden.
Han Yongnan
is sentenced to death by hanging.
The silver mine in Lanfang County
was prone to mining accidents,
[Sealed
by Lanfang County Magistrate's Office]
which were concealed.
It is ordered to shut down.
The surrounding farmers
will choose new sites
for ploughing.
Return mining to farming.
Ensure the well-being of the people
in accordance with the law.
A life for a life.
Bringing crimes to justice.
No one
is above the law.
This
is what the law of Tang insists on.
I know
in Lanfang County,
we are not good enough.
I know
in Lanfang County,
people believe
in the law of the jungle.
We are human,
not wild beasts.
The law of Tang
is to protect
the safety of each and every one of us.
We stick to the law of Tang
because
it is the bottom line.
We cannot expect
our vicious dogs
to pounce on the villain this time.
Next time,
who can guarantee
that they won't pounce
on the good of us?
So we have to stick to the law of Tang.
Only it can guarantee
the basic security of each of us.
I know
justice
is what you are longing for.
The law
is the safeguard of justice.
I believe in the law of Tang.
I hope
you
can also believe in me.
I'm willing to believe in you.
We are also willing to believe in you.
Believe in the law of Tang.
We believe in you.
We are willing to believe in you.
Believe in Magistrate.
Believe in the law of Tang.
We believe in Magistrate.
We believe in you.
About Han Yongnan's case,
I've submitted a written statement
to His Majesty.
Relevant legal provisions
will be amended.
We have to believe in the law.
Only by believing in the law
can it be
continually amended.
We have to believe in it.
There is power
in believing.
[Huaiying A hero at heart]
[Huaiying]
[A hero at heart]
[Ying]
[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Hollow Gourd]