[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 22]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
The wind rises
in the tenth month of the year.
Wild geese are rarely seen.
What's described in the seasonal song
is right.
Magistrate,
why do you suddenly want
to hunt wild geese?
You didn't have such a habit.
I just need a wild goose.
But it's been three days.
We didn't even see a goose egg.
It's not tasty.
The wild goose meat tastes awful.
The meat is tough
and difficult to swallow.
In this season, we should eat deer.
Let's call it a day.
Yes.
In this season,
venison is delicious.
I'll get you some venison when we go back.
[Lanfang County]
Sir.
Yes?
I'll have another bowl.
Okay.
Here is the money.
Please don't.
Those gangs have disappeared.
We can come out to do business now.
We are grateful to the officials.
How can I ask you to pay?
Thank you then.
I'll cook it now.
Thank you.
Okay.
Take care.
Boss, I don't want it now.
Take a look. Cloth.
There are many colors. All kinds of cloth.
Various kinds.
Take a look at the cloth.
We have silk from Jiangnan
and brocade from Bashu.
We also have
cloth suitable for men.
Please come in.
This piece
- and this.
- Okay.
Okay.
Here you are.
- Thank you.
- It's okay.
Take care.
Please come.
Buy some cloth.
Sir,
how much is the cloth she just bought?
50 qian.
50 qian?
Spending money like water.
Rouge.
Miss, take a look.
Noontime has passed.
You haven't finished shopping?
How is it?
This is the finest rouge.
Buy some.
[Yonghui Code with Comments]
[Marriage ceremony: Proposing through
a matchmaker with a wild goose as a gift]
Good.
Finally thinking about it.
Mr. Hong.
Mr. Hong, come and help me.
Okay.
Mr. Hong.
Why don't you give her a hand?
Give it to me.
- Thank you, Mr. Hong.
- Give it to me.
I just talked with Ma Rong.
From now on, when I go shopping,
you don't need to go with me.
Business is more important.
How can we not go with you?
This place is Lanfang County.
Under the Magistrate's stewardship,
Lanfang County
is no longer what it used to be.
If I go out during the day,
you really don't need to worry about me.
If you say
the governance of Lanfang County
is all the credit of Huaiying,
it is true.
Has the Magistrate gone out?
He's been working hard these days.
He went out shopping early in the morning.
I guess
he went to buy something for you.
I don't lack anything.
Mr. Hong,
are the files
the Magistrate wants to read
ready?
Don't worry about that.
They are already ready.
Okay.
I'll check how the cooking is going.
Ma Rong,
go help her.
Didn't I help her?
I have been shopping
with her for four hours.
Now, my arms hurt, my back hurts,
and my legs hurt.
What did she buy?
Mr. Hong,
she can't spend money like that.
In four hours,
she spent over a hundred qian.
Look,
she bought all these things.
How much can the Magistrate earn?
We risk our lives to solve cases.
With painstaking effort.
You are thinking too much.
What belongs to the Magistrate
belongs to Miss Cao.
In the future, we might have to
change our way
of addressing Miss Cao.
What do you mean?
Recently, the Magistrate
has gone out
to hunt wild geese every day.
I guess he is planning
to formally propose to Miss Cao
and hold a formal wedding.
Really well-intentioned.
The Magistrate really wants to marry her?
Effortlessly.
It's quite fat.
Heiyan is more and more outrageous.
Previously, it was Diao Xiaoguan.
Now they've sent us a wild goose.
What do they mean?
After a long search,
we only found out that Heiyan
infiltrated all the gangs.
We can find nothing else.
They don't trade
or gather.
They just occasionally mess around
or kill someone.
I still feel they are elusive.
Magistrate,
can these people
be targeting you?
We know nothing now.
How many people
they have,
where they are staying,
and what their purpose is?
The only thing we can be sure of is
that there is one person
behind all this.
On the day of the new moon,
this man may appear.
How do you know that?
The leader of the Green Dragon Gang
we took down last month
was also controlled by Heiyan.
According to one of his men,
Chen Xiaoyun,
he had seen the leader of Heiyan
meeting the leaders of the gangs
in a wood.
This wood
is their meeting place.
They meet
on the day of the new moon every time.
The day of the new moon.
Isn't tomorrow the day of the new moon?
Magistrate, shall we...
No.
Why?
It's not easy to have a clue.
Chen Xiaoyun?
First,
we don't know whether his words
are true or not.
Second,
Heiyan and we
go way back.
They never let us get
such a clear clue.
Heiyan can't
contact him only.
Now, we finally got a clue.
We should continue to investigate.
Solving cases
doesn't mean taking risks.
Taking such a risk
is not bravery,
but stupidity.
I...
Stop here.
Don't mention it
again.
Why didn't you say something?
Wasn't the clue provided by you?
When can you stop being stupid?
I'll get the wild goose ready.
Yeah, good for you.
You are busy?
You are back.
These are what you bought on the street?
The white bag contains
what I bought for you.
Gloves?
In autumn,
winds are rampant in Lanfang County.
When you hunt wild geese,
you use a bow,
and your hands are exposed.
I'm afraid they will get cold.
You'll need the gloves.
How do you know
I went to hunt wild geese?
There is sand on your clothes
and you have goose feathers
on the soles of your shoes.
I've been with you for so long,
so I've been influenced.
I've learned something.
I told Hong Liang
not to tell you.
Is hunting wild geese a taboo?
Why can't you tell me?
I just wanted to wait
until everything worked out
before I told you.
"Work" means to enhance.
"Out" indicates reality.
"To work out"
is to enhance reality.
I'm already very satisfied
with the reality.
After all,
no one can predict the future.
Just seize the moment.
Well,
how long do you plan to squat there?
Can you do something productive?
Is there anything productive to do?
Is there anyone
doing anything productive in this house?
My biggest business now
is to accompany this Miss Cao
who is of unknown origin
to stroll around every day.
Is the Magistrate
doing anything productive?
His biggest business
is to chat with her
in the room all day long.
What are you talking about?
All these years, Miss Cao
has never troubled you with anything.
You won't even do her a little favor?
If you are unwilling to go,
I'll go next time.
Did she cast a spell on you?
First, Magistrate Di.
Then, Mr. Hong.
Now it's you, right?
What spell?
You mustn't make baseless accusations.
After Miss Cao came,
aren't the Magistrate's files in order?
Isn't he smiling more than he used to?
What's so great about arranging files?
If I were literate, I could also do it.
If you didn't brag,
you could have been literate long ago.
Don't look down upon me!
Bragging all day long.
What can you do but brag?
Is Chen Xiaoyun
locked in the back?
What do you want to do?
This...
Isn't this... during the day...
What?
It's dead.
Should I just put it in the Archive?
Waiting for it to stink?
Fine.
Just do it.
This is from Heiyan.
Don't get poisoned to death.
From Heiyan, so what?
Poison?
The one to poison me is not born yet.
Chen Xiaoyun, is it around?
Yes, right ahead.
Tai?
You are so bold.
You took the criminal out
without permission.
Let's go.
Go.
If the Magistrate knew
you were acting on your own,
he would punish you.
If we don't investigate
following such a good clue,
we will have to go catch them
after they run away.
The Magistrate is becoming
more and more timid.
How far is it?
Right ahead.
In less than half an hour,
we will arrive.
Behave yourself.
Rong!
Watch out!
Everyone disperse!
Chen Xiaoyun, don't run!
Rong,
don't chase him!
Chen Xiaoyun?
Miss Ma.
Miss Ma,
Mr. Qiao got hit by an arrow.
His wound is not serious.
But I suspect
he has more than just an injury.
He might be
poisoned.
Well,
what kind of poison is in him?
Is there a way to detoxify it?
I've never seen
this kind of poison.
Logically,
any poison attack
would have an abnormal reaction.
But he
doesn't look any different
and seems to be asleep.
- His face is ruddy and serene.
- Charlatan.
Charlatan.
Why talk so much nonsense?
Hong.
You must save him today!
Okay.
Let go of me!
Enough!
Leave this place to me.
Coroner Hu
may have discovered something.
Go take a look.
I see.
What do you know?
You saw
the Fairy of Ninth Heaven.
You saw Qilin.
You also saw...
What did he see?
Dreams are good.
They can make people
forget their worries.
You fell asleep.
You are dreaming.
Obviously, he is as dead as a doornail.
You told me he had just fallen asleep
and had been dreaming.
When did I say he had fallen asleep?
I'm talking about Qiao Tai.
Qiao Tai is okay.
He will wake up himself.
You...
He is like this.
You think I don't know
if he is as dead as a doornail?
Lunatic.
Who?
What happened?
Magistrate,
there was a dark shadow
on the roof just now.
Nightmare for a day.
Wake up in three days.
Boqi devours dreams.
Explain the dreams in Qingchuan.
He is
in Qingchuan.
[Qingchuan]
Qingchuan's location is special.
It is at the junction
of Shannan Circuit,
Jiannan Circuit,
and Longyou Circuit.
The folk customs are mixed there.
The environment
is even more complicated.
You won't know
what situation you'll face
if you go there.
Besides,
Qiao Tai is suffering
from a strange poison.
He deliberately
poisoned Qiao Tai.
Wake up in three days.
Qiao Tai is okay.
He will wake up himself.
Qiao Tai
is okay.
He will wake up in three days.
But if I want to read the dream,
I have to
go to Qingchuan.
[Map of Lanfang County]
[Qingchuan]
Did it ever occur to you
that this was a trap?
Try what you have devised.
Even though I know it's a trap,
won't I
jump in?
Huaiying,
remember.
You are just going there
to pry.
Even if you find something,
you can't act on your own.
If you don't want Ma Rong
to go with you,
I can go.
You don't need to.
I promise you.
Make or break,
I will come back
within 30 days.
I'll prepare the horse.
Miss Cao,
when I'm away,
please help Hong
with the affairs
in the Magistrate's Office.
Certainly, I will.
Although I failed to hunt a wild goose,
I've prepared
all the other betrothal gifts.
When I come back...
I don't care about the formalities.
Thank you, Miss Cao.
I'm leaving.
When you come back,
if you still keep calling me Miss Cao,
I won't respond.
You will return safely,
right?
I'm leaving.
Dreams must eventually wake up.
Life is all empty.
Hello.
Who are you guys?
Who are you?
Get lost!
This is Healer Lin.
He has to go to Qingchuan
on urgent business.
The ladies in the brothel in the town
have contracted a bad disease recently.
If they continue to enjoy their life,
it's not safe.
If you hurt
Healer Lin,
it's not good for anyone.
Let them go first.
Anyway,
you are not in such a hurry
to meet them.
Let them go first.
Let's go.
No matter who you are,
I've saved your life.
You are going to Qingchuan, right?
Take a rest with me.
I'll lead the way for you.
Sir,
what's your name?
My name is not important.
I'm just
a traveling alchemist.
Sir,
are you also a healer?
Why?
What kind of elixir
is in your gourd?
I'm asking you
why you said "also".
You just said
I was Healer Lin.
Aren't you?
This gourd is empty.
Empty?
If it's not empty,
I can't put anything in.
Let's go.
I'll take you to Qingchuan.
Healer Lin,
welcome to Qingchuan.
If you'd like,
just call me
[Mr. Hulu]
Mr. Hulu.
[Qingchuan Town]
Looks like
something bad happened again today.
In such a world,
you never know
how many days you have left.
Yeah.
The officials are so useless.
They can't handle anything.
Stop talking.
Look at how he's dressed.
He didn't seem like a reputable person.
This kind of people
must have ill-gotten gains.
Quick. Carry the dead away.
Make way.
It's him.
You brat,
when did you come out?
Go back to the inn now!
Go back!
Thank you.
They're fighting.
A moment ago,
run amuck.
The next moment,
die violently in the street.
Healer Lin,
Qingchuan
welcomes you.
[Green Bird Inn]
[Propitious]
Stop.
What are you here for?
Where is your superior?
Who are you?
I am the Magistrate of Lanfang County,
Di Renjie.
[Commander Xiao]
Why did no one
tell me in advance
that you were coming?
I received the tip-off.
The leader of Heiyan
has infiltrated Qingchuan.
Heiyan?
I haven't heard of it for quite some time.
Does Heiyan still exist?
Yes.
You mean
those two people
were killed by Heiyan?
It's still unclear.
On my way to Qingchuan,
I happened to encounter the two of them.
I have to perform an autopsy
to see whether they were killed
by Heiyan.
An autopsy is unnecessary.
Their bodies have been buried.
Buried?
Any conclusion from the autopsy?
Did you find out...
Magistrate Di,
don't make it so complicated.
Just two bandits died.
Does it matter who killed them?
Magistrate Di,
there are indeed rumors in town
that something big is about to happen.
The mastermind
can't be Heiyan you mentioned,
can it?
You have a permanent presence here.
You know Qingchuan
better than I do.
If Heiyan does make trouble,
can you please send troops
to suppress it?
You must be joking.
I only have enough men
for civilian security.
If we are to encounter
a force as powerful as Heiyan,
our people are too few.
Commander Xiao,
please don't hesitate.
Please report
to the military office immediately
and ask for reinforcements.
That's not necessary.
After all, nothing serious
has happened in Qingchuan.
Just rumors.
Let's wait and see.
Commander Xiao,
in broad daylight,
a few strangers died on the street.
Is this just gonna go away?
Magistrate Di,
you are the Magistrate
of Lanfang County.
I am the intermediate military officer
of Qingchuan.
I don't need you
to teach me what to do.
Don't take it
personally.
Magistrate Di,
is there anything else
I can do
for you?
Please issue
an identity certificate
for me.
The name is
Lin Muzhi.
From Ganzhou.
The occupation
is a healer.
Who is that man who was shouting
for money in the street just now?
He is
called Wei Sheng.
He is the boss of Green Bird Inn.
Wei Sheng.
Wei Sheng is a miser.
Half a month ago,
his wife ran away
with a guest in the inn.
He curses her loudly every day,
saying she is faithless.
Wei Sheng is not a decent guy, either.
I think
it makes sense his wife
ran off with someone else.
He has a daughter named Wei.
She is really pitiful.
Thank you.
[Wei]
Thank you for today.
Are you staying?
Yes.
Follow me.
Boss,
chalk it up to me.
Let's go.
Boss.
[Wei Sheng]
Are you staying?
How long will you stay?
As long
as it is necessary.
Your identity certificate, please.
Healer?
Come on.
Brat,
take the guest to his room.
Follow me.
You don't look
like his daughter.
I'm not.
I'm a handyman.
I do the cleaning, cook,
clean the rooms,
and everything else.
Isn't he your father?
Foster father.
He seems to have a load on his mind.
He has no heart.
You...
You have too many questions.
Is there
a bathhouse in this place?
Do you want to take a bath?
I've traveled a long way
and I'm travel-stained.
I have to take a bath anyway.
You rich people are so picky.
Do I look
like a rich man?
I am
a healer.
I don't care what you do.
The bathhouse is downstairs.
Also,
don't let other people
know you are rich.
In Qingchuan,
don't show your wealth.
There are people inside.
A private bathhouse?
Get lost!
Can't you hear me?
Don't be rude.
Let him come in.
[Miss Shiyi]
Please.
The home guard
should be disciplined.
Sorry for the rudeness.
It doesn't matter.
Sir,
what's your name?