[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 25]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
[Green Bird Inn]
Magistrate Di.
In Qingchuan,
there has been no rain for a long time.
Commander Xiao,
thank you
for your help in this case.
I will report to the court
and commend you for your efforts.
I could help...
But
we should conduct business impartially.
Qingchuan
can't be like this forever,
especially the military management...
So, what is your idea?
Two points.
First,
all the populace should move out.
Qingchuan
should be managed by the military.
Well...
Second,
from now on,
Qingchuan Town
is under the jurisdiction
of Lanfang County.
The military
and the magistrate of Lanfang County
shall perform their own responsibilities.
Commander Xiao,
what is your opinion?
Since this is your decision,
I should
adhere to the policies of yours.
Qingchuan
originally belonged to Lanfang County.
I've been filling in for you
for many years.
The future
of Qingchuan now depends on you.
Magistrate,
I'm honored to be able
to help you
this time.
Little girl,
you're a good girl.
In a while,
everything will get better.
Take care of yourself.
Your mother
would also want you to live well.
Remember,
the past
will only make you stronger.
I've arranged with Mr. Hulu
to take you together
from now on.
You will live rough
and travel around,
but I'm sure
no one will ever mistreat you again.
Would you like to?
Can I take that red dress with me?
Of course.
Go ahead.
Mr. Hulu,
I'd like to ask
one more thing.
Why did you save me
when we first met?
Why
do I feel that we've known each other
before?
I knew who you were
when I first met you.
Who
am I?
You are the only one
who knows who you truly are.
There is no set date for my return.
Magistrate Di,
take care.
I have a piece of advice for you.
Eat and drink when you should,
and don't take things too personally.
Eat and drink
when I should,
and don't take things too personally.
If that's the case,
there's no difference
from being a dog.
Look at me.
I am a dog.
A
homeless one.
Wei,
time to go.
Sit still.
Not following the masses in doing good,
not practicing loyalty and faithfulness,
not acting with benevolence,
not behaving with respect,
not pursuing desire.
When all things are thus managed,
benefiting from simplicity and inaction
aligns one with the correct way.
The influence of Heiyan covered
Lanfang County.
Many of the local populace
chose to join it,
or they had relatives who joined it.
Heiyan wrote all of their names
into the roster.
In this place,
everyone could be from Heiyan.
He could come from Heiyan.
I could also be from Heiyan.
Even that little girl's mother
could be part of Heiyan.
Daguan.
You didn't arrest the ones
you should arrest
but caught the ones you shouldn't.
[Lanfang County Magistrate's Office]
You rushed for one hundred li.
But can manifesting one's bright virtue
change such a world?
Can loving people
ensure everyone eats his fill?
If you
hand the roster to the court,
when the army marches here,
lots of people
will die.
Do
all the people listed in this roster
deserve to die?
Do they
deserve to die
in your hands?
Kneel down!
Why did you read this book?
Why can't I read this book?
[Young Di Ying]
I've learned there is a counteraction way,
where one thing suppresses another.
Though not a medicine,
it has remarkable effects
against poisons.
For example,
cypress against upas.
[Young Di Renjie]
Shut up!
The book is filled with strange tricks
and heterodox methods
which can harm you.
I've learned a lot in this book.
- Hong,
- What did you learn?
- why is my father so angry?
- If a man with ulterior motives gets it,
- Huaiying, don't be afraid.
- you will
- Don't be afraid.
- bring people endless misfortune.
- It's fine.
- Why can't I
- read this book?
Kneel here
until you realize your mistake.
You should follow Father's words,
study hard,
and be a person he considers useful.
Like you?
Not me.
I don't want to obey
what Father requires.
You're no longer
a member of our family.
Just leave.
I'll be back.
Water.
You scared me.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
Finally, you woke up.
They said it would take three days.
But you kept sleeping.
I was so worried.
If you don't let go,
you'll strangle me to death.
How...
How are you feeling now?
Are you feeling uncomfortable?
Are you in pain?
Let me see.
Rong,
what happened to me?
[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Skylark Chirping]
Huaiying.
Miss Cao has been worried about you
and insisted on coming to see you.
But I stopped her.
What time is it?
It's already past mealtime.
Let's go...
Come back with me.
What are you watching here?
Watching people coming and going.
Watching the intertwining streets
and alleys.
A corner of the city, yet unknown to me,
is the place where he is hiding.
Who?
Heiyan.
Wasn't Heiyan eradicated by you
long ago?
Even if there were some survivors,
they couldn't cause huge trouble.
Hong,
how do you view Heiyan?
Just a couple of gangsters
violating the laws.
I thought the same way in the beginning.
It wasn't until I eradicated those gangs
in Lanfang County.
I found that, among them,
those who were really close to Heiyan
were very few.
You mean
the real Heiyan group members
are still hidden?
Behind the scenes,
they are manipulating everything.
I even think
that the so-called Heiyan
is actually
just one person.
How can one person be a group?
Did you forget
what they did in Penglai?
I haven't figured out this point.
But if Heiyan is not eradicated,
endless troubles will lie ahead.
Okay...
Just stop thinking
if you can't figure it out.
The transfer order is on the way,
and we will leave Lanfang County soon.
Let others handle the matters that follow.
Let's go...
[Lanfang County Magistrate's Office]
Mr. Hong,
these are fruits and candies prepared
by the Magistrate's Office.
Okay.
Put them there.
You have been checking all day.
Have you decided on the date?
It's not easy to choose a good day.
All people in the Magistrate's Office
are hoping to share the good fortune
of the Magistrate.
We are excited.
Do you think
I don't know your intentions?
You want to have some days off
and enjoy drinking.
It's the Magistrate's wedding feast,
and we surely should enjoy drinking.
Please stay reassured.
You will definitely have fun on that day.
There are sky lanterns.
Let's set off the lanterns at night.
Great.
Look.
What color do you like?
Magistrate,
Lanfang County
has changed greatly
compared with before.
Congratulations!
Congratulations...
You said
that Lanfang County
has changed greatly
compared with before.
Is that so?
Magistrate,
I have an appointment with Miss Cao.
Tonight, we'll set off sky lanterns
and make a wish.
What wish do you want to make?
Speaking wishes aloud nullifies them.
Let's go.
[Lanfang County]
Make a wish.
What wish should I make?
Speak out all your
unspeakable wishes.
My wishes are aboveboard.
Tell me then.
I hope
all under Heaven can be at peace,
and the nation prospers forever.
Look, something is approaching.
It looks like a cart.
Why is there no rider?
Right. The cart has no rider.
Excuse me...
Excuse me.
Stop them.
Everyone, don't go over there.
Stop there.
Please don't go over there.
Isn't it...?
Who?
No one...
I mean,
why is the cart
without a rider?
How strange!
That's weird.
It was cut by a sword or an axe.
Beyond this,
I know nothing.
The paper effigy is well made, though.
I have never seen that before.
Qiao Tai is conducting
city-wide inquiries
into the origins of the paper effigy.
I'm afraid
he will find nothing.
In my opinion,
we should go through
the records of the missing people
of Lanfang County in the last ten years.
Ten years!
I don't fear the numerous case files.
But where should I start?
Girl.
About 20 years old.
Beautiful.
Why did the murderer
put the skull
in the paper effigy?
All your goods are here?
Yes, they are all here.
Is there another effigies workshop
in the city?
Lanfang County is a small place.
Mine is the only one.
It's late at night. What is
the knocking noise?
It's Mason Ling
carving tombstones.
In Lanfang County,
Ling's shop is the only one
that carves tombstones.
Has anyone come to inquire?
Magistrate,
everyone took a detour,
and no one came to inquire about it.
What a rich man!
The cart and the horse
must be worth lots of money,
and he decided to discard them.
If they were not stolen,
there is only one reason.
What's this?
Untie the horse.
Magistrate.
Put it on.
Come.
Magistrate,
where are we going?
An old horse knows the way.
Have you heard the saying?
Magistrate,
you are brilliant!
Shh.
Cut out the flattery.
I didn't.
I do feel you are brilliant!
I know that.
Are we going to walk overnight?
Here we are.
This family held a wedding.
Is it appropriate to knock on the door?
Just knock.
Hello?
We're entering.
Ma Rong.
Magistrate.
Go back and bring some people.
Keep your hand in the air.
I've been doing it for a long time.
What are you doing?
This cloth is for your wedding.
Miss Cao's instrument.
Play chess.
I...
I don't know how to play.
I can teach you.
You can play.
When will you
ever finish playing chess like this?
How about this?
Do as I say.
Cannon moves horizontally
from column 8 to column 7.
from column 2 to column 5.
Cannon moves horizontally
Knight moves diagonally forward 2 spaces
from column 2 to column 3.
from column 8 to column 9.
Pawn moves vertically forward
for 1 space from column 7.
Rook moves horizontally
from column 9 to column 8.
Rook moves vertically forward
for 1 space from column 1.
Capture it.
Capture it,
and you can
slash her first.
You love her,
so you can't bear
to slash her.
It's fine.
But
I'll cut your fingers
one by one
until you bleed to death.
Slash her.
Do it!
Your turn.
I...
Just do it.
Very good.
You love each other,
so you can't bear to hurt each other.
How about this?
Let me give you an idea.
Think carefully
about the mistakes you made.
For example,
your wife flirted
with Mr. Wang from the West of the City.
Your husband spent the night
before your wedding in a brothel,
drinking.
In this case,
will you play chess better?
You've got reasons.
Slash!
I think your wife loves you less.
She slashed harder than you.
Then you went on a killing spree.
Then,
you killed her,
and you
killed him.
Both were dead.
After that,
I dug out your hearts.
Two hearts
that once loved each other.
This is the truth behind the case.
Magistrate,
Mr. Hong invited you to pay a visit.
Does your face hurt?
He won't be coming back, will he?
I'll play dead for a while.
Huaiying,
check the exquisite craftsmanship
of the earrings.
They are made from good materials.
I don't think they belonged to her.
Magistrate,
I've inquired about them.
This couple
was kind and friendly
and
had no enemies.
The point is
they just got married before the murder.
There is no chance
of an extramarital affair.
The deceased didn't have pierced ears.
The earrings
were forcefully pressed in the ears.
Investigate the origin of the earrings.
[Gambling House]
Big...
- Small.
- Big.
Have you seen this?
No.
You all have never seen this?
I have never seen this.
Have you seen it?
No.
Miss Ma,
we have never seen this thing.
But if you were to bet it on the table,
it would be ours.
Yes.
Then tell me,
how much is this pair of earrings worth?
I'll give you this amount.
This amount?
Yes.
Are you joking?
You have blind eyes.
I'll leave.
Miss Ma,
I can add more if you feel it's little.
Why does she go?
I've roamed through every humble place
in the entire city.
No one knows this.
It shouldn't be like this.
Someone has died!
Self-castration.
He lost too much blood.
Take it away.
Tai,
what is self-castration?
You shouldn't have come.
Greetings from Qiuyue, Magistrate.
Long time no see.
It's been a long time.
How have you been?
I've been busy,
so I have no time to see you.
You're being too kind.
I should have gone to your office
to see you often.
Besides,
your status
makes it improper for you
to come here.
Do you know
this man?
I do.
His surname is Loong.
He is a butcher in the city
and a regular guest here.
But a few days ago,
I instructed the ladies
not to do business with him anymore.
Why?
He has odd hobbies.
He liked to use needles for piercing
and whips for lashing.
Not only did he hurt people,
but he also often gives less
than what's due.
I've heard that many shops in the city
stopped doing business with him.
Yao,
please recount the details
of what happened to the Magistrate.
Just now,
I was accompanying my guest in the yard.
I saw Loong coming with a knife.
I thought
he came to hurt us because we stopped
doing business with him.
Where are you?
[Loong]
I am an animal.
I'm not a human.
You promised me
that you would spare my mother.
Spare my mother!
You mean
that he was like calling out to someone.
Yeah.
I saw that he was looking at something.
So, I followed his looking direction
and found a man
on the second floor.
Where?
Just there.
Once Loong died,
that man disappeared.
What does
that man look like?
He was wearing a cloak
and a mask.
I... I didn't see his face.
Mask?