[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 32]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
[Gate to Positive Dreams]
He must be affected
by the Yin Qi at the altar.
We must leave here immediately.
But now
the snow hasn't stopped yet.
And it's late at night.
Why don't you leave tomorrow morning?
No.
The Magistrate can't stay here any longer.
Alright.
The Magistrate and you
will have your luck.
He can't walk now.
Please arrange more people
to carry him onto the carriage.
Okay.
I'll make arrangements now.
Thank you.
[Zhao Yun Library]
Miss Cao,
did the Magistrate
take the medicine I prepared for him?
Yes.
That's good.
After you go down the mountain,
go south.
There is a village
less than 20 li
away from here.
You can find a healer
and medicine there.
Thank you.
Watch out.
It's windy at night.
He has a plague.
It'll be troublesome if he catches a cold.
You are really careful.
Hurry.
Miss Cao.
Miss Cao,
let me help you get in the carriage.
Huaiying.
What's the matter with you?
Don't go.
Magistrate.
Have some water.
Magistrate,
why are you here?
Where are we?
We don't know, either.
We followed a group of refugees
to this place.
They said your carriage had turned over.
Where is Miss Cao?
Oh right.
Miss Cao has left a note.
She said she had gone to seek help.
[The axle is broken. I'll go seek help.]
What happened on earth?
This is Xiaobao's sword.
Give it back to me.
Don't grab at it.
Xiaobao is my grandson.
Who is Xiaobao?
His name is on it.
He is called Wei Xiaobao.
Look. I know our family name.
Our family name is Wei.
[Wei]
I know this character.
Before he jumped down, he looked back.
As if he had seen a ghost.
[Nightmare, Soul]
Our library does not teach children.
They are all adults.
The Magistrate saw something
that did not exist
because of the foul aura of the dead.
I know what I saw.
Our teacher repeatedly instructed us
not to disturb him during his retreat.
Otherwise, his previous efforts
would be wasted.
Did he take the medicine
I decocted for him?
After he takes it today,
he should
get better tomorrow.
It is recorded in the parchment scroll
that children will be sacrificed
during a solar eclipse.
It's all heresy.
When there is a climate change...
They can soothe the souls of the dead.
Do you know there will be
a solar eclipse this month?
The dead here
are always restless.
The solar eclipse is coming.
Let's not offend the dead.
Xiaobao.
Qiao Tai, Ma Rong.
Where are you, Xiaobao?
Go.
Xiaobao.
[Zhao Yun Library]
There is no one here.
[Gate to Positive Dreams]
Let's split up and search.
Magistrate,
be careful.
Go.
Last night,
Zhou Li
jumped down from the rooftop and died.
Everybody witnessed it.
Flesh and blood.
Let the Lord live forever.
Conquering demons.
Possessing the mixed brilliance.
Flesh and blood.
Let the Lord live forever.
Conquering demons.
Possessing the mixed brilliance.
Magistrate, save me!
Magistrate.
Help me.
[Wei Xiaobao]
Magistrate, save me!
Magistrate Di,
why are you back?
Why is this child
locked in here?
He is a student here.
He broke the rules
and should be punished.
I saw that parchment scroll.
The day of the solar eclipse
is the day of blood sacrifice.
You want to summon evil spirits.
This child
is a sacrifice, right?
Where is Cao An?
Is she also a sacrifice?
I don't know what you are talking about.
Magistrate.
Save me.
Go.
Magistrate Di,
you can't blame me.
I have no choice.
Mr. Cui forced me to do it.
He is mad.
He wants to live forever.
Mr. Cui has died.
You killed him.
You hide the body
in the tung oil.
That urn is big enough
to contain a corpse.
The strong smell of the sandalwood
was to cover the smell of Mr. Cui's body.
You are really lucky.
The axle is broken
and it was a snowy night.
You actually survived.
What did you do to Cao An?
Don't worry.
Women's blood will defile gods.
I don't need her.
Where is she?
You can't find her.
You can't
even find me.
Where is Miss Cao?
I don't know.
Tell me, where is Miss Cao?
Magistrate,
we searched everywhere
but didn't find Miss Cao.
Magistrate,
we found a corpse in an urn in the study.
It was an old man.
Mr. Cui.
Hold here.
Be careful.
Worry about yourself.
Li Miao.
Flesh and blood.
Let the Lord live forever.
Conquering demons.
Possessing the mixed brilliance.
Why are you screwing with me?
I've been waiting
for this day for decades.
Why are you back?
Where is Cao An?
Why do you force me to kill you?
Why are you meddling?
Since some people have chosen to be evil,
some others will choose to be good.
Hypocritical. A group of hypocrites!
[Shen Wei]
Magistrate Di, I beg you.
I have no time now.
I need this child.
I need to offer his blood
to my god.
Where is Cao An?
I won't kill her.
As long as I can finish the sacrifice,
I'll release her.
Where is she?
If you get in my way,
Miss Cao will die.
Wait and see.
You have no time.
You will see with your own eyes
your eternal life
ends in smoke.
I have no time indeed.
But do you think you have time?
She will die
before me.
Before me!
Where are you hiding her?
I can tell you where I'm hiding her.
There.
No.
She is in a place
you can never find.
She will slowly savor
the horror before death.
I tell you, Di Renjie.
In order to keep you alive,
Miss Cao is willing to stay.
What about you?
You ignored her
for an irrelevant child.
Where is Cao An?
Where is she?
No.
There.
She is in a place
you can never find.
Where is she?
Tell me.
Where are you?
Cao An!
Tai.
It's okay.
It's okay. Don't be afraid.
We are not bad people.
Is your name Wei Xiaobao?
I know your grandmother.
Come, I'll take you out of here.
Cao An!
Cao An.
Magistrate.
Magistrate, step aside. Let me do it.
You came at last.
I would definitely come.
I know you have a lot of questions.
It all started
when I found the little wooden sword.
The moment I saw the little wooden sword,
I suddenly realized
Zhou Li was trying to tell me something.
Later on,
I found Xiaobao
in a corner.
Don't be afraid.
Xiaobao told me
Li Miao was a bad guy,
who wanted to kill him.
Zhou Li saved him.
Xiaobao.
Don't be afraid.
My name is Zhou Li.
I'll get you out of here.
Come out.
Come.
Xiaobao, are you okay?
Then Zhou Li
brought Xiaobao to Mr. Cui's room.
We happened to be there.
Zhou Li was a man of delicate mind.
Carrying Xiaobao,
he deliberately walked backwards
to our door.
Finally,
he kept throwing snow balls at our door.
He wanted me to leave.
Hearing the noise,
I went out to see.
At that time, Xiaobao went into our room.
Xiaobao left the incense
we gave to Mr. Cui at our door
so that we could see Li Miao
for what he really was
as soon as possible.
Did he take the medicine
I decocted for him?
I accidentally knocked it over.
Then I decided to take Xiaobao away
because I thought Li Miao
must have found something.
I figured out a way.
Sell the dummy.
He must be affected
by the Yin Qi at the altar.
We must leave here immediately.
[Zhao Yun Library]
When Li Miao and the others
were seeing us off,
Xiaobao took the opportunity to flee.
We agreed to meet
at the foot of the mountain.
But when I arrived there,
I didn't see Xiaobao.
Xiaobao.
Those who came
were Li Miao's disciples.
They had taken Xiaobao back.
He is an official appointed by the court.
If you kill him,
you will be sentenced to death.
I'm about to have an eternal life.
Would I care about that?
Don't you believe in the will of heaven?
You are about to have an eternal life.
Your life will be as long as heaven.
Why not let his fate
be decided by heaven?
If he can survive,
that's his fate.
As you wish,
whether Magistrate Di can survive
in the snowstorm
is in the hands of heaven.
[The axle is broken. I'll go seek help.]
A year ago,
Li Miao and his men took over this place.
They killed Mr. Cui and his disciples.
He continued to recruit students
under the name of the library.
In Li Miao's eyes,
they were all sacrifices.
In order to live forever,
he killed numerous people.
Zhou Li
couldn't bear
Li Miao's evil thoughts and cruelty.
In the end,
he ended his life
in that way.
He wanted
to send us a warning in this way.
The more I struggled, the more I suffered.
The short period of time
seemed to be as long as a year.
Slowly,
I gave up.
I could only sense death,
darkness,
and helplessness.
But each moment I was praying
you could survive.
[Gate to Positive Dreams]
I'll take people to capture them.
Xiaobao.
Grandmother.
Xiaobao, are you okay?
I'm fine.
Xiaobao.
Come, my child.
- Thank you for your great kindness.
- Thank you, Magistrate.
Madam, you are welcome.
Get up.
Come on, Xiaobao.
Xiaobao.
Xiaobao,
take your grandmother...
Xiaobao.
Go home.
Xiaobao,
let's go home.
Go home.
Where is my sword?
It's time to give it back to me.
Now that you've saved me,
I'll give it to you.
Time to go.
Time to go, my child.
Let's go home.
Go home.
Everybody has a good heart
because they care about someone
in their heart.
The only way to live forever
is to live
in the memory of your relatives.
Hong.
Can't a killer
get away with murder?