[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 4]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
Mr. Di.
Let me go.
That was a close one.
Someone must've tampered with it.
It's got to be Zhangsun Qing.
Di Renjie,
where's your sword?
How can you live without us?
Good boy.
I'll give you beans
when we get back tonight.
It's so big.
This yard is so grand.
It's nice.
[Di's Residence]
[Day Seven]
It's so big.
How do you like it?
If you let Mr. Hong give me more money.
I can make this yard
even better.
You did all this?
I did it.
You don't have to thank me.
Just promised me one thing.
After this case is solved...
After this case is solved,
let's talk about it then.
You don't know him well.
Are Chang'an people all so ungrateful?
Come on.
Here you go.
Thank you.
I'd like some water.
Ma Rong,
when it gets dark,
don't light any lamps,
don't make any noise,
and don't let outsiders know
there's someone in the house.
Qiao Tai.
Eat slowly.
This is...
Rain Dragon Sword.
The Rain Dragon Sword made
by Sword Maker Sanzhi?
If I, Qiao Tai, am destined
to die by the sword,
I'd rather spill my blood on this sword.
Tomorrow night
at Mr. Wei's residence,
it's up to us to guard it together.
Just the two of us?
Even though I'm old,
I can still fight.
[Wei's Residence]
Mr. Hong,
will this work?
Even the most cunning fox
might be trapped.
How did Mr. Di know
there would be a thunderstorm tonight?
I don't know.
[Day Eight]
All I know is
to trust him.
Come on.
[Wei's Residence]
Mr. Di,
how's it going?
Almost done.
Hong is still busy there.
The door...
Leave the door.
I got it.
Qiao Tai,
that day,
Kang Zhiyi's profile,
how did you do that?
We didn't look for it.
Ma Rong took it by chance.
It is a coincidence.
A coincidence?
Truly a coincidence.
How could such a coincidence happen?
Some things
are right in front of you,
but you can't see them.
Some things
you can see
simply because
someone wants you to see them.
So did I see it or not?
[Wei's Residence]
[He Dajing's Spirit Tablet]
[Nonsense. Not distinguish yin and yang.
Violate the rules of order and propriety.]
Have a drink with me.
[He Dajing's Spirit Tablet]
Tanshi.
Someone else who set fire
to the Jushui Pavilion?
Why is it so light?
It leaked?
I've never had anything
to do with politics.
I'm too old and just want
to avoid trouble.
But I tell you,
in Chang'an,
there are too many people
who oppose the Empress.
I have found out the truth.
Who?
Huaiying,
what's the matter?
About the case,
there is one thing
I've never figured it out.
What?
Kang Zhiyi
set fire to the Jushui Pavilion
and killed people,
creating the illusion of Heaven's wrath.
He's already tied up the door
and didn't want to leave anyone alive.
But I survived.
Why?
How to explain?
Because the person
who set the fire wasn't Kang Zhiyi at all.
Right?
Then who was it?
The root cause of the fire
was the spontaneous combustion
of Tanshi in the wine flask
that He Dajing had with him.
And you put that stone
in He Dajing's wine flask.
Right?
You actually know him well.
You know
he was used to carrying a wine flask.
On the examination day,
you put Tanshi
in his wine flask.
Because Tanshi was soaked in the wine,
it won't burn immediately.
You've calculated it carefully
drilled a small hole
in the bottom of the flask.
After
about two to three hours,
the wine would run out.
Tanshi
would set He Dajing on fire
in the examination room
by spontaneous combustion.
Then, you would achieve your goal
of sabotaging the exam.
What you didn't consider
is that this year's exams
have added a new supervision system.
Wine flasks
are no longer allowed to be brought
into the exam room.
To prevent He Dajing
from finishing the wine in advance,
you put Huanglian
on the spout of the flask.
That's why your Heavenly Fire didn't start
until we arrived
at the Jushui Pavilion.
You made a perfect plan,
but
Heaven's plans supersede our own.
He Dajing is my student.
He's also my assistant.
Why would I want to hurt him?
Confucius said,
"Only women and small-minded men
are hard to deal with".
This statement is wrong.
[Nonsense.]
"When it comes to women,
[Not distinguish yin and yang.]
even though they
[Violate the rules of order and propriety]
are arrogant and willful,
treat her the way we treat men,
support and help along the good,
correct and lessen the consequences
of the bad,
embrace her nature,
and through this,
earn the title of "Junzi".
[*Junzi: an ideal person in Confucianism.]
His Majesty's
acceptance of women
has become
cowardice in your eyes.
If I hadn't stumbled upon
your comments
on the Crown Prince's article,
I wouldn't have been able
to figure out your motives.
Your hatred for Empress Wu
is as great as that of Zhangsun Qing's,
right?
No.
He's still tied to his position
and has the fear of death.
Just because she's a woman,
you hate her
more than Zhangsun Qing.
What proof do you have?
After the examination,
you followed us
to the Jushui Pavilion.
This is what I found at the scene.
It's the leather rope you used
to tie up the scrolls.
Mr. Wei.
I didn't expect it
to be you.
Heaven's plans supercede our own.
Tanshi is unstable.
I really didn't know
when it would burn.
But I've thought about it.
If it burns inside the exam room,
it'll have a ten percent effect.
If it burns outside the exam room,
it'll have 50 or 60 percent effect.
But I never thought
that it burned in the lair
of the demon empress.
The effect was 100 percent.
Even Heaven is helping me,
but why do you go against it?
When you did all this,
[He Dajing's Spirit Tablet]
have you ever considered him?
Your Heavenly Fire
was created.
And then what?
You poisoned the horse
and tampered with the stirrups.
You recommended the Yuntie cuffs
to the magistrate of Wannian County.
This way, you can silence me
and frame Zhangsun Qing for it.
Huaiying,
you're smart,
but you really don't know
what you're doing.
This witch
is planning a big conspiracy.
If Tang falls into her hands
in the future,
I don't know what it will become.
You're young and reckless.
You think all the new is good and right.
But the "new"
means changes,
chaos,
severed heads and bloodshed,
and saber rattling and fight.
Huaiying,
aren't you afraid?
Fairness
and prosperity.
That's what I see as the result
of the reforms.
Even if I'm afraid,
it's worth a try.
Mr. Wei.
please stop now.
I've told you.
People can't escape their own fate.
Mr. Wei.
Even if you found me, what can you do?
As long as the demon empress's opponents
are not eliminated,
the Heavenly Fire won't be extinguished.
Sooner or later,
it'll burn her to death.
Wait.
Keep him alive.
[Wei's Residence]
Mr. Di.
This is the sword for the Longnan army.
Longnan
is the domain of the Zhangsun family.
Take this sword
as evidence
and notify the magistrate
of Wannian County
to arrest Kang Zhiyi.
Early Hai hour now.
[Inside Chang'an]
[Leyou Land, Chang'an]
Your Highness,
Di Renjie is here.
Di Renjie.
Your father
is the talent from Bingzhou, Di Zhixun.
Di Renjie,
did you find the truth?
Huaiying.
Father.
Huaiying,
come closer.
I'm coming.
Father.
What took you so long?
I missed you so much.
Have you
finished your job?
Father.
I...
If you haven't finished,
why are you so slack?
I am not.
Huaiying,
go.
Go and do your job.
Go and find it for me.
Find the truth.
- Okay.
You're awake.
Tai,
he's awake.
You're finally awake.
How long have I slept?
[Day Ten]
Three years.
Don't listen to her.
You've been asleep for three days.
Where on earth did you get hurt?
Are you hungry?
Let's have some goat soup.
Hong.
You're awake.
Could you all excuse us for a moment?
Yesterday,
the Ministry of Justice,
the Imperial Court of Justice
and Censorate
held a state trial for him.
Kang Zhiyi confessed
that Zhangsun Qing ordered him
to steal the Phoenix Seal.
Before he could kill Yaxin,
someone else killed Yaxin first.
So he followed the same method,
killed four Yulin guards who delivered
the forged imperial decree
to frame the Empress
for the Heavenly Fire murder
and achieve the purpose
of deposing the Empress.
Everything
was as you expected.
Zhangsun Qing denied it.
He said Kang Zhiyi framed him.
His Majesty had the Zhangsun's Residence
searched,
but the Phoenix Seal was not found.
It's a big problem to catch a criminal
without evidence.
And Zhangsun Qing
is a relative of the Emperor.
That's why His Majesty
has not made a decision
on Zhangsun Qing's case until today.
Where is he now?
He's been in the Qinglong Temple.
Even when he knew
the Zhangsun's Residence was searched,
he didn't come out.
So today,
His Majesty and the Empress
are going to the Qinglong Temple
to confront him and ask him to confess.
Your Majesty,
we guarantee Grand Commandant Zhangsun
is innocent.
Your Majesty,
please help defend Mr. Zhangsun.
please don't wrong Grand Commandant
with the words of a petty man.
You...
I hope you will make a fair judgment
and clear Grand Commandant's name.
Your Highness and Your Majesty
are one and the same.
There's no such thing as a power struggle.
Grand Commandant Zhangsun
is loyal to the court.
He'd never do something dirty like this.
Everyone,
rise.
Your Majesty, don't worry.
I'll go talk to Uncle.
Thank you, Zitong.
What a devout look.
It's said that Zhangsun Qing
has ordered candles of 20000 guan of money
for a blessing.
20000 guan of money.
It's enough to supply the soldiers
battling in Turk for months.
The candles keep burning day and night.
How much longer can they burn?
Since I became the Empress,
I've offended Zhangsun Qing's interests.
He's been trying to bring Kang Zhiyi in
and make me beleaguered.
At the beginning of this month,
he even burned down the Wutong tree
and create a public outcry against me.
If I don't do something,
I'll die.
This new path
will also die.
Fortunately,
Heaven helped me
to have you.
Come on.
Take a bet with me.
Five blacks are called "Lu".
Two whites and three blacks
are called "Xiao".
It's a vulgar trick.
These dice have lead dust
in them.
Some things
seem like fate,
but there's someone else's hand
where you can't see it.
If you're smart enough
to see through it,
you can join them
and dictate the fate of others.
To pray
and study Buddhism,
you need to be sincere.
If it's only for your own selfish desires,
don't defile
this pure sanctuary.
You're right, Uncle.
For this blessing,
I'm honored to study Buddhism
with you.
Uncle,
I have something to say.
I don't know if I should say it or not.
Now that you've said it,
why hide it?
I don't understand.
This is our family business.
Why do you have to make it public?
Heaven's rules and order supersede Heaven.
If we don't let the world judge,
it's not fair.
Let the world judge.
You're right, Uncle.
I won't forget it.
Your Highness,
it's the Zi hour now.
Uncle,
is there really no room for maneuver?
If you knew it would come to this,
why didn't you do it in the first place?
Wouldn't it be better
to be the motherly model of the world,
the Empress?
The Phoenix Seal.
We found the Phoenix Seal.
General Kang.
I'm here.
Have my candles
been sent to the Qinglong Temple?
Your Highness, rest assured.
I've delivered them myself.
Good.
Now, it's down to the last
and most convincing hit.
We can't let him have any chance
to come back.
The Phoenix Seal is really in the hands
of Grand Commandant Zhangsun.
Grand Commandant...
What should we do now?
Why is the Phoenix Seal here?
The Phoenix Seal is here.
What a trick.
You female savage.
Heaven will punish you.
The seal
was never lost.
The seal is just like a title.
It's all just vanity.
But the power behind that illusion
is real.
Even if Yaxin didn't die that night,
the next day,
she would have shown up
and been caught by the Jinwu Guards
and told the truth
about stealing the seal,
thus
exposing the collusion
between General Kang
and Grand Commandant Zhangsun.
I see.
After Yaxin's death,
you ordered Kang
to have the four Yulin Guards
who delivered the forged imperial decree
and killed Chen Zhuliang
kill themselves in the silkworm house.
Then,
you burned the silkworm house,
creating a heavenly punishment on purpose
so that Grand Commandant Zhangsun
could take advantage of it
and perform a series of plays
to stir up public outcry,
digging his own grave.
Your Highness,
more than a dozen lives
have gone to their deaths.
Was it worth it?
Whether it's worth it or not,
you and I can't say.
We have to ask the people of the world.
Your Highness is the motherly model
of the world.
Zhangsun Qing
and the courtiers following him
are in cahoots
and rotten to the core.
They
are not my enemies.
They're the enemies of the Tang.
It's so beautiful.
Look, it's flying so high.
The nine parts of Xiaoshao are performed.
[*Xiaoshao: a traditional Chinese music.]
The phoenix dances.
The phoenix alights on the Wutong tree.
All birds look up to the phoenix.
Come on and take a closer look.
What's missing from this evidence?
Mr. Wei...
Take the evidence down.
Yes.
He's been thrown into a mass grave.
Everything in his home
was confiscated and sold.
Luckily, he didn't have any relatives.
Otherwise,
they'll be implicated.
We studied with the same teacher.
I have a friendly reminder for you.
If you want to pursue a government career,
from now on,
don't mention Wei Wuji again.
Huaiying,
Master ordered it
and had it tailored for himself.
You're about his size now.
I'm sure you can wear this.
Why would I wear it?
Although you threw away the notice
of the palace examination
sent by the Imperial Academy,
I can still find it.
I've checked with the Imperial Academy.
You didn't receive a Jinshi degree,
but
you're on the list
for the palace examination.
Do you know?
In the past, ten years as an official
might not even get one
to enter the palace.
But now, you can see the Empress.
I think
she arranged this on purpose.
Like you,
she loved to fight against fate.
You're young and reckless.
You think all the new is good and right.
But the "new"
means changes,
chaos,
severed heads and bloodshed,
and saber rattling and fight.
Huaiying,
aren't you afraid?
[Taiji Hall]
His Majesty and Her Majesty arrived.
Kneel.
Bow down.
Up.
Candidates take their seats.
[New]
Her Majesty proposed the question.
One word, "New".
The palace examination takes two hours.
Candidates must concentrate
on their questions.
Don't talk to each other
or move around.
The palace examination starts.
[A reform]
A reform...
[means replacing the old with the new.]
We should examine its purpose
and means.
Now, new policies have been enacted.
The new laws benefited the people,
allowing them to live in peace.
You know
the benefits of reforms for the people.
Your understanding of "new"
[Di Renjie]
is more thorough than mine.
The fourth year of the Xianqing era,
the palace examination
for the first category.
Grade A,
number one,
Zhang Yue from Lanling.
Grade A, number two,
Song Jing from Chang'an.
[Di]
Grade A, number three,
Wang Wei from Shandong.
I'm on it. I passed it.
That's weird.
I didn't find the character 'Di".
It can't be.
Mr. Di can definitely
get a position or something.
I passed it!
I passed it.
Congratulations.
You passed it.
Do you know Di Renjie?
- Di Renjie?
- Did he pass it?
This is the list for the Jinshi degree.
Di Renjie only took the examination
for classicists.
What are you looking for here?
What do you mean?
It means even if he becomes an official,
it'd be a minor one.
Let's go.
I'll buy you a drink. Let's go.
What do you mean?
Go. Let's have some goat soup.
I didn't pass it.
Di Renjie,
I'm sending you to the frontier
to uphold justice.
Remember.
What I want is an upright
and selfless official.
But you
haven't found your way yet.
Put your head down
and experience more.
Maybe one day,
you can really work for me.
Failing in the examination
is not a big deal.
Say something.
That's right.
If you don't want to take the exam,
then don't take it.
Right.
Or maybe next year,
we'll take the exam with you.
Hong Liang,
I appoint you as
my inspector.
Ma Rong and Qiao Tai,
from now on,
you two
will be my attendants.
Attendants?
Hong,
I'm going to be
the magistrate of Penglai County
Huaiying,
go.
You haven't finished your job yet.
Di Renjie,
go and find it for me.
Find the truth.
You understand?
Let me go.
[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Screen Case]