[Judge Dee's Mystery]
[Based on the novel of the same name
by the Dutch author Robert van Gulik]
[Episode 5]
[This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance is purely coincidental.]
[Penglai]
Magistrate,
a male corpse was found.
Stop there.
[Penglai County]
Go back.
Why?
It's the Chu hour now. The gate is closed.
No entry is allowed.
Go out.
The drums are still beating.
And the gates are still open.
It's not a violation
to enter the city now, right?
Captain.
Take them down.
Don't move.
Wait.
I'm Di Renjie, the new magistrate
of Penglai County.
The unidentified male corpse
is the first case
I'm going to solve in Penglai.
Penglai County is quite lively at night.
Let's buy some Bing. I'm hungry.
You're hungry again.
Excuse me,
I'd like four Bing.
Sure.
Pick the hot ones for me.
Okay.
How much?
One qian.
One qian for each?
One qian for four.
It's so cheap.
It's much cheaper than Chang'an.
That's right.
Fair trade to all.
That's the rule.
Whose rule?
Penglai's rule.
What other rules do you have here?
Take walking as an example.
Scholars and farmers walk on the left.
Artisans and merchants walk on the right.
For forced purchase and sale
and price gouging,
flogging.
For thieves and robbers,
chop their hands off.
For oppressors of the good,
adulterers
parade them through the streets.
It's so nice.
Since the last magistrate of Penglai
was sentenced to prison for smuggling,
it's been three months.
Look.
I can't believe the market
is still in order now.
It indicates that the assistants
of the last magistrate
did a good job of governing Penglai.
If that's true,
it's a good thing.
Excuse me,
why are all the women on the street
wearing white powder on their faces?
For beauty.
Beauty?
Are you
Magistrate Di Renjie?
Yes.
[Teng Kan]
I'm Teng Kan.
It was Teng Kan
from Penglai
who took the first place
in the Poetry Contest.
You're Mr. Teng.
When your poetry won the Poetry Context
in the capital,
I was just in Chang'an.
Unexpectedly,
I'd meet you in Penglai.
This is my fate
with you, Magistrate.
They are
locals in Penglai.
They heard you'd arrive,
so they're here to greet you.
How did you know I was coming tonight?
Magistrate, you misunderstood.
The banquet is
to celebrate the Yichun Festival.
[*To celebrate the start of spring.]
We just heard about your arrival.
Two happy events come at the same time.
So we're here to welcome you
to join our banquet.
I've traveled a long way
and am covered in dust.
I'll come back to visit you
some other time.
That's great.
We can just help you wash
off the dust with wine.
If you
still don't want to join us,
we will think
you're blaming us for having a banquet
while not waiting
for your arrival at Penglai County.
Huaiying,
they are so courteous.
You'd better accept it.
Just go. Don't worry.
Wagon, horses, and baggage,
we'll bring them back to the camp.
Go.
Let's go.
Please, Magistrate.
Please.
Please, Mr. Teng.
Mr. Teng.
Greetings, Mr. Teng.
Please.
Magistrate,
this
is my wife, Yinlian.
[Yinlian]
Greetings, Magistrate.
Please have a seat.
Whether leading armies
or fostering a cultured romance,
Mr. Teng handles both
with effortless finesse.
Thank you.
Have a seat.
Your poetry is really extraordinary.
It's only natural
that you're the best poet in the capital.
Congratulations.
- I'm flattered.
- Congratulations, Mr. Teng.
Please.
It seems that today's night banquet
is not only
to celebrate the Yichun Festival.
It also celebrates your poetry's
first place in the capital.
I can't hide it from you.
I didn't bring any gifts.
I'm really sorry.
Mr. Teng,
Mrs. Teng,
congratulations.
Magistrate, you're too welcome.
Magistrate, thank you.
Magistrate, have a seat.
Ms. Cao is here.
[Cao An]
Sir,
you looks familiar to me.
Magistrate,
this is
the best singer in Penglai County,
Cao An.
Her talent and skill
are as good as those
of the famous performers
in Chang'an's Pingkang District.
Ms. Cao,
this is
the new magistrate of Penglai County,
Di Renjie,
Magistrate Di.
I'm Cao An from Mingyue House.
A toast to you, Magistrate.
Have a seat.
♪The land nurtures sweet osmanthus♪
♪Distant woods stand tall and strong♪
♪Leaves open,
unfolding brilliance in the wind♪
♪Flowers bloom, radiating moonlight♪
♪The land nurtures sweet osmanthus♪
♪Distant woods stand tall and strong♪
♪Leaves open,
unfolding brilliance in the wind♪
♪Flowers bloom, radiating moonlight♪
You left in the middle of the banquet.
We haven't had enough fun yet.
You can leave me here.
Just now,
someone at the banquet mentioned
the Four-panel Screen.
It's a family matter.
Magistrate,
please don't worry about it.
Mr. Teng.
Nothing.
I'm a lightweight drinker.
How much wine have you drunk?
Leprosy.
It's already cured.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Seven.
I'm back.
Go.
Draw a portrait for him.
A dead person.
I don't want to do it.
I don't.
Di Renjie.
Di Renjie,
your shoe is broken.
You shoe...
Ma Rong,
it's fine.
Let him be.
Go.
Go to grink ink.
Don't be afraid.
Come on.
Treat him as a normal person and draw it.
Stop there.
Don't run. Stop there.
Wait for us.
Stop there.
Heiyan.
Mr. Heiyan,
we're from the Penghai Gang.
You know me?
Mr. Heiyan,
we didn't know you were here.
This girl,
if you like her,
we'll keep her for you.
Let's go.
Wait.
If you know me,
you have to leave me something.
[Cao An, in her youth]
Heiyan.
You shouldn't say that name.
[Notice]
Have you found everything?
Yes.
The warehouse was emptied overnight.
Documents and files of decades.
Good. Let's get some rest when we're done.
There really isn't a single unsolved case.
Indeed not.
Mr. Wang,
the magistrate of Penglai County
has been vacant for over three months.
No one in the county
filed a complaint?
Magistrate,
there are complaints,
but they
are all minor
and trivial,
so they're resolved
on the same day
and not included in the case files.
The county is at peace.
Great.
Hong,
it seems we really have come
to a great place.
♪The land nurtures sweet osmanthus♪
♪Distant woods stand tall and strong♪
♪Leaves open,
unfolding brilliance in the wind♪
[Mingyue House]
♪Flowers bloom, radiating moonlight♪
♪The land nurtures sweet osmanthus♪
[Director]
Sir,
we're not open yet.
Please come back later.
May I ask
who's singing a Bingzhou ditty?
It's Ms. Cao An.
♪Flowers bloom, radiating moonlight♪
Huaiying,
you should go to have some rest.
How about the portraits posted?
Any news?
The dead man's face
was disfigured by leprosy,
so it can't be recognized easily.
I'm afraid
we'll have to wait and see.
When my father was in the capital,
did he have dealings
with an official named Cao?
I remember one.
18 years ago,
an official was confiscated
for illegally minting coins.
It's Cao Hexian.
It's him.
But Cao Hexian has no dealings
with Master.
No dealings.
The first reason is the Bingzhou ditty.
What is the second reason?
Huaiying,
I'm afraid it's not just this case
you're thinking about.
Why are you asking about this suddenly?
Nothing.
I'm just asking.
Just asking.
A new broom sweeps clean.
A new officer has three fires.
The first one
burns like this.
In my opinion,
the second and third fires
won't hardly burn.
I've heard of portraits used
to catch criminals,
but not portraits used
to recognize a corpse.
That's true.
Look at this portrait.
The nose doesn't look like a nose.
The eyes don't look like eyes.
The face is rotten
and pockmarked.
Who would recognize this?
Exactly.
An official with a classicist degree
is really not well educated.
How can he
get such a high position?
It turns out the time
I spent studying is pointless.
Let me see.
Who is this?
Maybe I'll recognize it.
The person in the portrait
looks very similar to you.
You...
If you're not a woman,
I'd never spare you.
Thank you.
You...
I'll bet with you.
Two hours.
Fifteen minutes.
Why are you here?
When did you come back?
I've been here the whole time.
That's weird.
I didn't see you just now.
You thought I was in the house.
That's why you kept looking inside.
That's how people are.
Di Renjie,
I'm telling you.
I didn't peep at you.
When did I say
you were peeping?
What did you mean by ''15 minutes''?
It'll rain in 15 minutes.
You bet
it'll rain in two hours.
I bet in 15 minutes.
You can even guess this?
Huaiying,
did you deduce it again?
How did you do it?
Tell me.
You won't understand it.
Well...
Then deduce me.
Deduce me.
You're like a bowl of water.
I can see the end at a glance.
What do I have to deduce?
Di Renjie,
I have nothing
to say to you.
You don't need to say thank you.
Change it.
I'm a magistrate.
It's inappropriate for me
to wear stolen boots, right?
Your eyesight is bad?
Check the bottoms.
They're white.
They're new.
Do you know?
The magistrate of Penglai County
has been vacant for over three months,
but there's no single unsolved case.
What's wrong?
Isn't it good
that there's no unsolved case?
It's good for you.
For me,
I could only solve new cases.
We have a new case?
You stole someone else's money today.
This is the new case I need to solve.
You...
You want to catch me?
I'm an official now.
You're not an official.
You're just an officer.
No. You're even not an officer.
You're just one of my attendants.
I...
I stole the money to defend you.
That criminal...
That criminal is still out there.
That body is still lying there.
You don't go to catch the criminal.
You want to catch me?
Fifteen minutes.
If I win,
I'll bring you to justice.
What if I win?
You won't.
Also,
I forgot to tell you.
Those people in the streets of Penglai
wore white powder
on their faces because they had leprosy.
Who is it?
Isn't that the money bag I lost?
Lucky you.
Put it on her.
Are you okay?
Kidnapping a woman in broad daylight.
Who gave you the nerve?
You...
You're a thief.
I advise you to be smart.
If you break the rules of the Bazong,
he won't let you go.
Bazong?
As long as you're in Penglai,
you have to abide by his rules.
Bazong
is the King of Justice.
The King of Justice?
Come on.
What are you doing?
Don't you want to tie me up
and take me to see Bazong?
You go.
Tie her up.
I...
Hurry up.
Come on. Put it on me.
Put it on me.
Go.
Don't steal from people
with no family to support them.
Don't bully the elderly, the weak,
the sick, and the disabled.
That's the rule.
If you can't remember,
get out of Penglai.
Yes.
Take him down.
Next one.
Boss.
Here.
[Bazong]
A little girl.
Why so serious?
Untie her.
Okay. Untie her.
What are you doing?
What do you want?
You're Bazong.
That's right.
I heard
you're in charge here.
That's right.
Well, I'm curious.
If you're in charge,
what's Magistrate Di in charge of?
You work for the government.
That's right.
Let her go.
Go.
Quick.
What do you mean?
One who works for the government
is in the government's charge,
not mine.
Get her out of here.
Yes.
- Go.
- Don't move.
It's easier to invite the devil in
than to send him away.
I just heard your men say
that anyone who wants to live in Penglai
has to follow your rules.
I'm here today
just to tell you.
Di Renjie, Magistrate Di, is here.
From now on,
he's in charge of all of Penglai.
You can rest now.
Since ancient times,
the government is the government.
The Jianghu is the Jianghu.
But don't forget,
there's still the law above us.
I have to take your Jianghu power
back from you to Magistrate Di.
Power isn't something you take.
It's something you earn.
You have to earn it yourself.
Then tell me.
How to earn it?
By drinking.
Right. Drinking.
Chug it.
Drink with Rong?
It's courting death.
Get up.
You wake up.
Magistrate, I didn't expect you
to come to my place so soon
after taking office.
I'm honored.
When I was passing by,
I heard you play a Bingzhou ditty.
I wonder
if you could play it again for me.
The director told me
that it was you.
We have many singers here.
She must
have made a mistake.
Why don't
I sing Mr. Teng's new piece
for you, Magistrate?
That won't be necessary.
You don't like Mr. Teng's poetry?
The theme of love and romance
is not what I like.
Unexpectedly,
you don't understand romance.
Mr. Teng is well-known.
Even though he has no children,
he has no intention of taking a concubine.
He's deeply in love
with his wife Yinlian.
What he wrote and said in his poetry
is also the hope
of living happily with his wife.
Even His Majesty
would be moved by it
and granted him two words,
''Elegant Affection''.
All this
can't move you?
You're so well-informed.
You don't look like
a common singer living
in a remote place like Penglai.
Do you know where I come from?
When my father was in the capital,
did he have dealings
with an official named Cao?
18 years ago,
an official was confiscated
for illegally minting coins.
It's Cao Hexian.
That pouch is old,
but it's not something you'd expect
from a commoner.
The colored glaze on the side of the pouch
is also not ordinary.
You do like to investigate, Magistrate.
You're so perceptive.
Nothing escapes your notice.
I'm sure you're from Jinzhou.
Because I want to hear a Bingzhou ditty.
That's the first reason.
What is the second?
I've traveled to Bingzhou
and have seen the culture
and people there.
The original plectrum
on this pipa is broken,
so I can't play the heavy sound.
Let me sing
''Misty Rain of Penglai''.
[Mingyue House]
[Hongsheng Woodwork Store]
[Teng's Residence]
What's wrong?
Who?
Master.
Hurry up.
- Master.
Madam.
Master still has a pulse.
Hurry, save Master first.
Save Master first.
Slow down.
Keep up.
Why are you following us?
Go back to the study and stand guard.
No one is allowed in.
Master.
What happened?
Madam said!
My lord,
drink the medicine.
I said no, no!
[Magistral Office of Penglai County]
Mr. Teng.
Teng Kan.
Why is he kneeling?
Magistrate,
I
came to seek death.
I've come to turn myself in.
Master.
Wake up.
[Teng's Residence]
Three stabs on the front,
four on the back.
Seven stabs again.
Same as the unidentified male body
found outside the city.
Has anyone touched that sword?
I've sent someone to guard the study.
You. Come in now.
Answer Magistrate's question.
Magistrate,
I've been on guard.
No one's come in.
Right here,
there was a screen.
Magistrate.
Madness and insomnia can
be cured by Chaihu,
Xiangfu, Qingpi, and half of Mutong.
Diankuangmengxing Soup.
[*Traditional Chinese medicine.]
When did
Mr. Teng's madness begin?
Well,
about
half a year.
By the wall,
is there a four-panel screen?
In fact,
that thing
is an ominous piece.
So after the incident,
Master sent us to move it
to the storage room.
Screen.
An ominous piece?
It was the evil screen
that attracted the evil spirits
and caused Master to kill Madam.
Please have a look, Magistrate.
The willows grow new shoots.
A spring scene.
The scholar is taking a nap at his desk.
A woman enters the dream.
Green hills and fields.
This portrays that the scholar
is on his way
to the examination in the summer.
Then in the late fall.
The scholar gains a degree
and returns home in glory.
Happened to meet the woman in his dream.
This last one should
be a painting of winter.
Why did it turn into a picture
of murdering his wife?
It wasn't like this before.
It was supposed to be a picture
of a happy couple embracing.
But I don't know
why it turned into this.
Turned into this?
Since when?
Five days ago.
The murder weapon showed signs
of having been moved.
Judging from the traces at the scene,
someone entered the murder scene
and escaped over the wall
after the murder.
Is the murderer
someone else?