You're leaving already?
I haven't even
made us breakfast yet.
Oh, I'm sorry, rabbit.
I got a lot
to take care of today.
How much longer are we
gonna have to keep doing this?
You said you wanted
to be with me and only me.
I do, but it's not that easy
Baby, this is so unfair.
I know. You know, but it
won't be like this forever.
Okay.
Can you stay wearing that
'til I get back?
Mm-hmm. I'll be waiting.
Oh, my gosh.
- Hey.
How was your flight?
Uh, it was good.
A little turbulence,
but, uh, freaked me out a bit,
but it's all good now.
So, I'm gonna go to Alan's.
He asked me to help him with
some stuff around the house.
Okay. I'm going to go
shopping this afternoon, so.
Okay. Well, just be here
at 6:00.
Reservation is at 8:30, okay?
Oh, if you see Lydia,
please tell her not
to overdress tonight.
Every time she does,
I feel like a complete slob.
Sweetie, you can never look
like a slob, even if you tried.
Hey, tell me what you think.
Does this go with that?
No.
Oh, I know the perfect one.
Yes, that's it.
So, did your boy toy
come over last night?
Honey, he is so much more
than a boy toy.
You sure about that?
Because he mainly
comes over at night.
Well, that is because
the sex is incredible
And not because
he's hiding from his wife?
Okay. There's that too.
You are the only one
that I can talk
to about this stuff.
Thank you for not judging me.
Oh, girl,
all your skeletons are hidden
in the depths of my soul.
No, but seriously.
It's not like
I wanna be a homewrecker
or a husband stealer,
or whatever you call it.
The other woman. I mean,
that's what you call it.
At least,
that's my term of reference.
It's a little more discreet.
I fell in love
with a married man.
-Yeah.
-Oh, my God!
That sounds terrible
when you say it out loud.
What's her name?
Ugh. Celine. Celine Castillo.
-This one?
-Mm-hmm.
Girl, she's flan
and you're....
Seriously,
you tell anyone, kick your ass.
Never talk to you again.
I ain't gonna be
no snitch, man.
I ain't saying a word.
That good in bed, huh?
Like you wouldn't believe, man.
Yo, you wouldn't leave Celine
for this girl, right?
No. No. I-- I-- I love Celine,
but, uh, I think
I'm falling for this girl.
Things are just getting
so intense.
I don't know how to stop it.
And to be honest, I--
I don't know if I want it to.
Yo, when you get caught,
don't come crying to me.
Shut up. I don't even want
to think about that, all right?
All right, bro.
I love the dress.
I can't wait
to wear it tonight.
You like it?
All right.
Well, I'm out of here.
-Where you going?
-To buy my wife a dress.
I would
like to propose to toast.
- Yeah.
- To our beautiful wives
for choosing us lucky bastards.
That's sweet.
-Salud.
So, what's new with you?
So, I have
an ovulation calendar
and reminder set on my phone.
I mean, we're going for it.
Like, we're really trying
the old-fashioned way first.
And if that doesn't work,
I'll look into IVF.
I think he's gonna be
a great father.
Yeah.
Yeah, I don't know if we--
Like 15 times.
She's wearing my dress.
Don't worry about it.
You're wearing it better.
Can I get you started
with some drinks?
Yes. I will have
a tall glass of Chardonnay.
Okay.
Oh, my God! Baby!
It's perfect. I love it.
I can't wait to wear it.
Well, I saw that dress
and I immediately
thought of you.
It belongs on these curves.
Um, I'll be right back.
I'm gonna head to the restroom.
I'll go with you.
You know what, I'm actually--
I'm gonna freshen up really
quick. I'll be right back.
-Take your time.
-Thank you.
Caleb!
You're on a date?
Are you kidding me right now?
You are literally wining
and dining with your wife.
-Shh!
-What am I supposed to do?
You want me to just
sit at home waiting for you?
You know what, Caleb?
You can fix her up like me,
you can dress her like me,
but she's never
gonna fuck you like I do
because that's all
I am to you, isn't it?
I'm just a good fuck.
No, Fiona. I love you, okay?
You love me?
Well then,
I'm gonna go tell her.
No, no. Do not
cause a scene like this.
Not like this. Please.
Do you wanna
leave your wife or not?
It's really so simple.
But if you keep
lying to me, Caleb,
I swear, I will
make your life miserable.
Just not tonight, please,
all right?
Please, please
don't say anything.
Just go.
Tonight was fun.
I think we needed that.
Ah, I had so much fun.
We need to do
date nights more often.
Hm. Like we used to?
Yeah. You looked
so beautiful tonight.
Mm-hmm. What about now?
Extremely.
You wouldn't text me back
and I just had to come see you.
Well, guess what?
She's gonna be outta town
for the next few days and--
- Unbelievable.
- Fiona.
Look, I know you think
you're getting the short end
of the stick here.
You're right. I am getting
the short end of the stick.
You're just stringing me along
and you know it.
No, we're done, Caleb.
No. Come here. Come here.
-Fiona, come here.
-No.
This is
the honest to God truth.
I am in love with you
and I don't wanna lose you,
all right?
Look, give me two months
to do what I gotta do
and take care of
what I gotta take care of
and I will leave her.
I wanna start a life with you.
And I mean that, Fiona.
Two months.
I don't know why,
but I think
you're for real this time.
I am.
Just don't let me down, Caleb.
I promise I won't.
Oh, my God, baby.
This is the best news ever.
But if you're lying to me,
I swear I will never
speak to you again.
Honest to God truth.
And for the record,
I was so jealous
of your date that night.
I wanted to kill him.
Oh, is that so?
-Mm-hmm.
-Well, don't worry.
I didn't fuck him
in my new dress.
You better not have
I took it off first.
-Oh, I probably deserve that.
-Mm-hmm.
And you deserve this.
I'm gonna tickle you now.
Come here. Get over here.
Stop it!
No! You know I hate that.
Stop! Baby, please.
I'm gonna kick your ass.
I'm letting you know
I hate that.
I know.
Come get me.
All right,
we're gonna have some fun.
We're gonna have some wine,
some cheese.
-Some carrots.
We're gonna have some carrots
for your bad eyesight.
They can't be that bad.
I chose you.
That's true. Actually,
you have great eyesight.
All right, let's do this.
So does my rabbit, uh,
have her carrots for the day?
You'll always tease me
about eating them.
Well, besides the obvious,
there's a second reason
why I call you that.
Oh? You don't even
know the real reason
why I eat them so much.
Duh.
No, dummy.
For the beta carotene.
'Cause if I have
at least two a day,
it makes my skin a glow.
See? Look. Don't I have a glow?
Your skin is glowing
and your eyes are beaming
just so beautifully right now.
You know, it's the first thing
I noticed about you, right?
Mm. You know, the first thing
I noticed were these.
Oh, sorry.
- Sorry.
- I'm sorry.
No worries.
So, uh, what are
we making tonight?
-Excuse me?
-Oh, let me rephrase that.
I meant what are you
making tonight?
Oh, uh, nothing crazy.
Just some quinoa shells
and chicken broth
and tomato paste.
It's kinda like
a healthy version of fideo.
You know,
tomato paste can actually
help smooth out cellulite
'cause it has high amounts
of lycopene.
Wow. No, I did not know that.
Okay. That was too much.
What are you making?
Uh, spaghetti Bolognese.
-Spaghetti Bolognese. Oh!
-Bolognese. Sorry.
Wow, master chef.
Well, it's not
like I make my pasta
from scratch or anything.
Oh, I'm no longer impressed.
But it is damn good.
I bet it is.
Um, well enjoy your evening.
Okay.
Which one is your favorite?
Let me guess. Strawberry.
No. I mean, strawberry's great,
but coconut is better.
Gracias. I drive all the way
across town for la michoacana.
It is the best there is.
Nice. Look, I-- I know
this is gonna sound strange,
but, um,
I feel like I know you.
Really? Where from?
I mean, nowhere specific,
but it's just--
Hey, listen, I can see
that you're married, okay?
and I am not the mistress type.
-No. And I'm not the, uh--
-The cheating type.
No, I'm not.
Okay. Good. Well,
your wife is a lucky lady.
Hey. Hey. You forgot these.
Oh, my carrots! Yeah. I can't
forget these. Thank you.
You are welcome, Fiona.
How do you know my name?
Oh, duh. Oh, my gosh. I always
forget that that's there.
Um, well, okay, now you
know my name. And you are?
Caleb. Pleasure.
-Nice to meet you, Caleb.
-And thank you for that
lycopene tomato paste
cellulite tip.
I'll be sure to work on that.
-Okay. Yeah, no problem.
-Pleasure.
-All right, bye.
-Nice to meet you.
Oh, I'm sorry.
-Okay. You ready?
-Oh.
Show me.
Okay.
"Fiona, an up-and-coming
Latina fashion designer
who makes this year's
top 100 designers of the year
alongside her partner
and friend,
co-founder, Miguel Munoz
of Spark Fashion Line.
Fiona is on the hit list
for her innovative imagination
and spitfire designs
that have rocked the runway
and red carpet
in recent years."
Wow.
Congrats, babe. That's amazing.
Thank you. Oh!
I got you a little gift.
-You did?
-Mm-hmm.
Oh, baby. It's us. I love it.
I'll cherish it
forever and ever.
All right. So, what
do you wanna do tonight?
So, Miguel is having
a celebratory get-together.
-Mm-hmm.
-And I know you don't know
any of my friends,
but Miguel knows all about you.
Hey, before you
even think it, okay,
nobody there knows who you are.
And besides,
we're gonna be together
in a couple
of months anyway, right?
Yeah. Okay. Let's do it.
It's your day, okay?
Did someone say more champagne?
-Oh, yes. Please.
-Ooh, yeah.
Well, congrats and cheers
to Miguel and Fiona.
Yes!
Oh, that's good. Yeah.
I cannot believe you
are here in the flesh.
I've heard so much about you.
Your photos
don't do you justice,
but I can see
why Fiona's so sprung.
If you're interested,
I have some shoes
that could prop you up
about an inch or two.
Oh, sorry about
my fashion friends.
They're obsessed
with height and looks.
I mean, aren't we?
Hello, everybody.
-Hi, Molly.
-Hi.
Oh, is this your design?
I love it.
It is. Do you wanna buy it?
Maybe I do.
Oh, congrats again on
your new feature in Vogue.
Thank you.
Is this your boyfriend Fiona?
I never met him.
Yes. This is Caleb.
You must be so proud
-of your girl.
-Mm-hmm.
How long have you
guys been together?
About a year now.
Yeah. The best year
of our lives.
Absolutely. Mm-hmm.
- Yes.
- Get a room.
Oh, we will.
So,
what did you think of Miguel?
He's cool.
What an interesting group.
Me and my-- me--
And your soon to be ex.
My soon-to-be ex.
We, um, we really don't hang
out with interesting people.
You know
my favorite part of tonight?
Mm-hmm.
It gave me a glimpse
into our future.
You know, for once
we weren't sneaking around.
It was just nice and normal.
It did, huh?
I felt completely at ease.
The--
Whereabouts is your sister?
She lives in Paris.
I actually haven't seen her
in over a year.
We had a bit of a falling out.
Over what?
It's a long story,
but we'll reconnect again.
We always do.
And once your divorce is final,
I'll introduce you to my mom
and the rest of my family.
I'm sure you'll meet
my sister too.
These last couple
of days have been
so amazing with you.
I'll call you later, okay?
You promise?
I promise.
Fiona, don't worry, okay?
I'm gonna follow through
with what I said.
I made my choice
and I choose you.
Hello. Baby, I'm home.
Oh, no.
The plants are dying.
Baby, are you here?
Hey, Celine.
-Hey.
-Hi.
My plants are dying.
Why didn't you water them?
Oh, uh, I forgot. I'm sorry.
Um, how was your trip?
It was okay. You miss me?
Of course, I did.
But you barely texted me.
I know. I'm sorry.
I was really busy at work
and um, I know how focused
you have to be
on your work trip,
so I didn't wanna bother you.
Well, it's tough.
If only I could get
the VP of marketing position,
things would've gone
more smoothly
and I wouldn't need
to troubleshoot as much.
Well, you're gonna get it.
I have a good feeling
about that.
Um, oh.
Oh, this is work.
I-- I have to get this, okay?
Hello? Hey.
What's wrong?
I'm exhausted, babe.
How are we gonna have a baby
if we aren't even doing it?
We're gonna try tomorrow.
It's not how it works.
I'm ovulating now.
I thought you
said you wanted to try.
Hm, tomorrow. I promise, okay?
I cannot wait.
I'm telling you just a little
bit longer and he is mine.
He's yours? Like completely.
Yeah.
No, no, no, no.
I don't sound that dumb.
-Yeah, you do. Sometimes.
-You are an asshole.
Come on.
Aren't you happy for me?
At least now,
you won't have to hear me bitch
and complain about his wife.
Oh, thank God.
But you are making it
sound so easy.
You do realize
divorces take like for evs.
Yeah, but at least
he'll be with me
while he's going through it.
When he finally does it,
then I'll celebrate with you.
Wait, wait, wait. You--
you don't think
he's gonna do it?
Girl, I see this happen
all the time.
The husband tells the lover,
"I'm gonna
leave my wife for you."
And then, when it actually
comes to doing it,
things get complicated,
reality hits
and most of the time,
señor prince
charming backs out.
I'm just saying
if he finally does it,
we can celebrate.
Hell, I'll even
get you a fucking cake
and I'll have it decorated
"The boy is mine," Huh?
You are such a jerk.
Come on, Zora. We gotta
get back to the studio.
-We got a lot of work to do.
-Yeah, work.
You just wanna get back to
your fuck boy waiting on ice.
Good to see you, Celine.
Is your husband with you?
No. He's at work. Why?
Is everything okay?
Your health is A-okay,
but I'd hate for you
to hear this alone.
Is there a chance
you can call your husband in?
He's at work.
What is it? Just tell me.
Your endometriosis has scarred
your fallopian tubes
and your chances
of conceiving are less than 1%.
Um, 1%?
Uh... W-- what about IVF
or other alternatives?
I have your charts here.
I can show you.
1%. 1%.
I am terribly sorry.
Mrs. Castillo!
It's gonna
be good for business.
Hey, let me
call you back, okay?
Honey, what's wrong?
It's just, uh, I just got back
from the appointment
with the doctor
and they said
that I'm unable
to have children.
All I ever wanted
is to have your baby, our baby,
and now that I can't have it,
I want it even more.
And it's not even possible.
It's never been possible.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Everything is
not gonna be okay.
It is never gonna be okay.
You can't fix it.
Let me get you
some tissue, okay?
Oh, my God.
Honey, I think
we're out of tissue, okay?
I can't find any.
Who's Fiona?
Huh?
Who's Fiona? Answer me.
She's just a friend, okay?
-Let me get my phone back.
-Just a friend?
Yes.
Give me.
Celine, give me back my phone.
You changed your password.
Now, I know that
you're hiding something.
-Celine.
-Give me your password
or I will break your phone
into pieces I swear.
No need to get crazy.
Fine. There's only
a couple things it could be.
Caleb, have you
been having an affair?
This bitch just said
she's pregnant.
-What?
-Is it your baby?
Are you having a baby
with someone else?
Look, I-- I've been
meaning to tell you.
I've been meaning
to talk to you.
Have or haven't you
been having an affair?
I don't know
anything about a ba--
Yes, I had an affair.
But I don't know
anything about a baby!
How could you! How could you!
No, no.
She's having my baby.
My baby.
No.
I want you to start
at the beginning
and I want complete honesty.
I first wanna
start off by saying that
it wasn't my intention
to hurt you
or ruin our marriage.
Celine, you are
an incredible woman.
Where did you first meet?
I'm happy in our marriage
and I wasn't out there
searching for another woman
or to have an affair.
At a grocery store
over a year ago.
When was the first time
you had sex?
It's-- it's not important.
Answer the question!
Within a week.
Is that her?
Caleb, is that her?
My mom always said
I could never choose a man.
I guess she was right.
Celine.
You are a fucking coward.
I hate myself
for doing this to you.
Not as much as
I hate you right now.
And I can promise you
that you will regret this.
I'm so sorry.
Baby.
I've been waiting
for you to text me back.
What's going on?
I-I just wanna ask,
and I don't wanna sound cruel,
but is it my baby?
It is yours.
100%.
Aren't you happy?
I am.
I will be.
I just gotta tell you
everything that happened today.
-Okay. Let's go inside.
-Okay.
I-I guess this is it.
You never even gave us a chance.
A chance to work out
whatever it was that went wrong.
And now you're not
even fighting to stay.
You don't deserve this.
You don't deserve
to be treated like this.
Just know if it doesn't
work out, you can't come back.
My lawyer will be in touch.
You know,
this isn't easy for me either.
Okay?
I still love you.
You don't get
to say that to me anymore.
-Caleb.
-Yeah?
Is it your baby?
Yeah.
Son of a bitch!
She's all yours.
Hey, wait,
you have to sign this.
Uh, you have to sign this.
Hey!
What the hell?
I am definitely outta my league
with all this stuff.
It's okay.
I know what we need.
Good.
This is the one.
Alright.
Well, let's do it.
And we'll come back
one more time
or many times
'cause I'm not sure
what we're gonna
get from the shower yet, so.
Okay.
I can't
wait to have your baby.
And to get my body back.
Yes, please.
I need your body back.
You made me
be happiest woman on earth.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Can I get by you
to grab that item there?
- Sorry.
- Good choice.
- Thank you.
- We will, uh,
email you the receipt
and the tracking number,
and, uh, you should get it
by next Friday.
Perfect. And you
have our card on file?
Yes, I do.
-Awesome.
-Thank you.
It's pretty easy and fast.
Yeah.
They don't want you to have
any time
to think about it.
Just don't look
at how much it costs.
Hey, lady!
What's wrong with you?
-Hi.
-Hi, there.
Congratulations.
Excuse me?
Newly pregnant?
Uh, yes, just a few weeks along.
It never hurts
to read up on everything.
Good for you.
I had four children
of my own, you know.
I thought, oh no.
Maybe I was mistaken and you
were just buying for a friend.
You see, I can always tell.
You can always tell?
I can always tell
who the mothers-to-be are
and who's just
shopping for a shower.
You see,
I wasn't wrong.
Thank you so much.
It means a lot. I've
always wanted to be a mother.
Boy or a girl
wouldn't matter to me.
I'm sure your husband
is very excited.
He is. He's gonna be
a great father.
Bye now. Take care.
Come back soon.
I will.
- Just pack it up?
- Yeah.
Hey, how's Celine?
Has she been
by your place lately?
We see her from time to time.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
Yo, I thought
you two were happy.
I was until I met Fiona.
Dude, I'm having a baby.
Yeah, I-I can't
believe it either.
All right, let's get outta here.
Hey, is that your new car?
I passed by that Italian place
that you love so much
and got you some of like
crunchy bread that you like.
What is this?
Why are you here?
Shouldn't you be off
enjoying your new life?
Celine, everything
happened so fast. Alright?
Truth is, I'm just
not used to not living here
with you
and being apart from you.
And?
And we were together
for such a long time.
I can't just forget about you.
Save your useless words.
They're empty
and they don't change anything.
You wanted this divorce and now
you're trying to butter me up.
You have some damn nerve.
-I am sorry.
-Go.
Caleb!
Hey.
Come on, let's go outside.
That bitch!
Celine?
Yes, Celine.
Who else would do this?
Are you going to take care
of this or do I need to?
I got it.
What the hell is wrong with
you?
I beg your pardon?
Is everything okay?
Our house has been vandalized.
And by the looks of it,
it's pretty obvious
-that it was you.
-Trouble in paradise, Caleb?
Cut the shit, Celine.
Do you really think
the people don't know
what you did to me?
To us?
Do you think people
look at you
and are honestly happy for you?
You don't deserve
a happy life, Caleb.
Am I gonna have to get
a restraining order against you?
'Cause that's not
a good look for your reputation.
Do you really think
you can convince anyone
that I had
anything to do with this?
Prove it.
What happened?
What did she say?
I swear,
if I wasn't pregnant,
I would handle that
myself.
So are we gonna
have to get a restraining order?
I mean, I don't wanna be
looking over my shoulder, Caleb.
I don't know.
It might not be a good look
to get a restraining order
while I'm trying
to finalize divorce.
Not a good look?
Look, it's gonna be
hard to convince anybody
that she's behind this.
Listen,
if she does something else,
then we'll get
the restraining order.
Until then
I'll just install some cameras.
-Okay. Fine.
-Come on.
Damn, girl. That's crazy.
But if the tables were turned,
I'm sure you
would've lashed out too.
You're not
taking her side, are you?
Of course not.
But I'm just saying, girl,
you didn't think
she would actually let
him go quietly, did you?
I mean, I kinda did.
I just, I didn't
know that people
in the suburbs had it
in them to get this crazy.
Never underestimate
a white bitch with money.
Yeah. Well,
after I have this baby,
she better not
underestimate me either.
Shit!
You miss me, baby?
Come fuck me.
Oh my God, you're wasted.
- Where's your clothes?
- Come on, Caleb.
Stop being such a.
Cover up!
Playing hard to get, are you?
You're drunk.
I'm taking you home.
No!
Oh my God.
Jesus Christ!
How could
you do this to me, Caleb?
Slap on
the hand for the vandalism.
It's done.
I'll forget about it.
But no more surprises, please.
Or it's gonna get ugly.
I mean that.
It's all nice.
And the spread looks so good.
Oh.
Mi amor.
Hi, baby.
-What's up, bro?
-Good to see you.
-Good to see you too.
-Quick pic.
-Yes.
-Oh, yeah.
Yes.
I'll sign it later on.
Oh good.
Me too.
This is looking really nice.
-It looks good, right?
-Yeah.
Alright, baby. You're
used to getting all these balls.
You got this.
There you go.
So far you got two balls.
Good job.
You're lying.
I have to have more than that.
Girl, come on. No.
- Come on, sweetie.
- Right there.
- There you go.
- Right there. Okay.
Are you taking them away?
Oh, no. Not at all.
You're gonna
open your eyes and see.
Oh, okay.
Okay, okay.
There you go.
You guys are messing with me!
Oh my God.
It's hot in there.
It sure is.
This probably doesn't help.
But it looks like
everyone's having so much fun.
Everyone
is having a great time.
- It's so good.
- And you won
all the games.
I love it.
I think
everyone let me win.
Yeah, of course.
-Oh, I feel it.
-You feel that?
Oh, my God.
Oh my God. Oh!
Oh!
Oh my God.
It like butterflies.
Yeah.
- I love you.
- I love you too.
Alright,
I think I need to sit down.
I got you.
-Alright. Thank you.
-Alright. You good?
Yes.
Oh, my goodness.
Oh, so cute.
-Gracias, tia.
-De nada.
Lena, where's Fiona?
In-- in the ambulance.
Go. Go.
Fiona! Fiona!
Hey. Oh my God.
Are you okay? You okay?
I'm okay.
I got out--
-Is the baby okay?
-Yes.
The baby's okay.
I'm okay.
I got out as fast as I could
and I just held my breath.
Oh, my God.
Oh my God, baby.
Where's my mom?
She's fine, she's fine.
She's back there. She's okay.
She's fine. Okay?
Looks like nobody got hurt.
- Caleb. Fiona.
- Yeah.
I'm Martin.
I own this building.
Look, I'm sorry
about what happened today,
but I'm so glad
that everybody got out safely.
- What the hell happened?
- I'm not a 100% sure
but it could have to do
with an electrical shortage.
Here's my card.
We'll be in touch
with further information
and insurance
for any losses or damage.
I'm terribly sorry.
Okay.
Hey, don't
get yourself worked up.
Fiona,
I could have lost you
and I don't take that lightly.
Your whole family was inside.
I know. But I'm...
trying not
to think about it
so I don't
put stress on the baby.
You're right. I'm sorry.
I have
the owner's card, um,
I'm gonna be in touch with him.
Okay?
My wrist
is starting to cramp.
I know.
Oh, we are going
to make a killing
on this collection, Miguel.
-I can feel it.
-We better.
Ooh, break me
off a piece of that.
Ooh. Oh, Those eyebrows
are on point.
I know.
-I'll be right back.
-Okay.
I know I'm a little late,
but I did promise.
- No!
- The boy is mine.
He is.
-You got him, girl.
-Mm.
You got my favorite?
-Yeah.
-Mm. Mm.
He freaking better be
at this point, right?
Alan.
Look, there's Celine.
What?
What in the actual fuck?
Hide. I don't
want her to see us.
We're not gonna
mention this to anyone.
We're just-- we're just gonna
pretend like we never saw this.
Okay? She would be
mortified if she saw us.
Why?
This
is a friend of Jacques'.
My confirmation code
is 439B as in boy,
T as in Tom, 99.
I need something big done
and I'm willing to pay
any amount of money
to get it done.
Sounds fantastic.
I'll be in touch.
Please!
Please take care of my baby.
No.
Please. No!
-Please!
-Baby.
Wake up. Wake up.
You're just
having a bad dream.
Okay?
Just a bad dream.
If anything happens to me,
just know that I love you.
Please take care of our baby.
Hey, hey, hey.
Relax.
Don't be saying that.
Okay?
You're fine.
It's just a dream.
I'm not gonna let
anything bad happen to you.
Oh, that's beautiful.
Beautiful.
Caleb, you can
go ahead and join her.
-Hey, baby.
-All right.
Oh, I love it.
Perfect.
You guys are too cute.
You did it.
I am looking for Celine.
I'm Celine.
I'm here
to pick up payment
for today's
business transaction.
So when you say today,
does that mean
that they're
at the hospital now?
Correct.
So can you tell me
who's on the job?
That, I cannot.
What are you
offering an exchange
for this information?
What do you want?
Dr. Smith?
Yes.
Are you new here?
I'm Celine.
I hired
you for today's transaction.
What on earth
are you doing here?
It's company policy
that we don't meet.
If I were to speak of this,
our new messenger boy
would be killed.
I'm just here to make sure
everything runs smoothly.
This isn't my first rodeo, dear.
Do you know
what bothers me about society?
No one ever pairs a pretty face
with unspeakable crime.
Pretty people
don't have perfect lives.
Run along now, darling.
I'll take it from here.
Look at the little cheeks.
Gracias, Lena.
Hi.
Now that I see him, he looks
like a Brody.
What do you think?
Brody Caleb Castillo.
It's got a nice ring to it.
Mm-hmm.
Hi, baby Brody.
I'm gonna take
him to the nursery.
Okay. Alright.
Not for long.
Oh.
Thank you.
-We did it, baby.
-We did. Huh?
That was weird.
-Yeah.
-It's a haunted hospital.
Stop.
It's okay, baby.
You can take it.
Yeah?
All right. Well--
I'm exhausted.
I'm just gonna take a nap.
Okay. I'm gonna take
it outside. All right.
If you need anything, text me.
I can't wait for you to see him.
He's adorable.
Oh, my gosh.
Could you step out for a moment?
I wanna go over
some protocols with Fiona.
Sure thing, doctor.
Wait, is that really necessary?
I would rather keep them open.
We want some privacy.
I have some
questions to ask you.
About what?
You are not the doctor.
I'm so sorry.
Clear.
-Hey, what's going on in there?
-Sir, I'm sorry.
I can't have anyone over here.
Why is he doing that?
That's my girlfriend in there.
Why is he doing that to her?
What's going on?
-Doctor knows what he's doing.
Please, please.
I need you to calm down.
Let's just wait
right over here for me.
Okay? Come on.
The doctor will come out.
The doctor will come out
and everything is gonna be okay.
Alright?
The doctor will come out.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Just wait right here for me.
Please. Wait right here.
Oh God, Fiona.
Do you know something?
Tell me--
I don't know. I don't know
what's going on. Hey.
-Are you Fiona's husband?
-Yeah.
There were
unforeseen complications.
She went into cardiac arrest.
We did everything
that we could to save her,
but I'm sorry
to tell you this,
she didn't make it.
Wait, I was just in
there a few minutes ago.
What do you mean she didn't
make it? She was fine.
I'm truly sorry for you loss.
What do you mean
you're sorry for my loss?
What happened-- what-- Fiona?
Wait, what happened?
Tell me.
What happened?
What do you mean
she didn't make it?
What do you mean?
What the fuck does that mean?
What you mean?
What do you mean?
Tell me, please.
What do you mean? God, no!
What the fuck does that mean?
Yeah.
Caleb, I know you're sad.
I sad too.
Every day I miss my daughter,
but she's in here now,
and she left us
the best gift ever.
Baby Brody.
Um, I have to get to work.
Um, now I'll be
back at six as usual.
Caleb, I like cooking for you.
You are working all day.
Okay. Fair enough.
Gracious, Elena.
Bye, Brody.
I love you.
Gracias.
Okay.
Uh, Elena...
...could you
put these inside for me?
Mm-hmm. Gracias.
Okay.
I've been meaning
to reach out to you.
I just didn't know what to say.
I wanted to give you some time
and let you grieve in peace.
It might sound strange,
but I'm sorry for your loss.
I think of you
and I think of you
raising a baby all on your own.
I can't imagine
how hard that must be.
Despite everything,
I'm here for you.
I've put the past behind me.
Please call
if you need anything.
Hopefully, someday
I'll get to meet your son.
Yours truly, Celine.
Oh, Brody.
I am sorry your mom's not here.
- Hey.
I was calling to see if you
wanted to do lunch sometime.
You-- you wanna go out
for lunch? What for?
I know you've been
through so much
and I just wanna catch up.
You said you could never
forget about me.
How's Saturday?
Yeah, sure.
Your order
will be coming right out.
Great.
Here you go.
I'll go ahead and take these.
Oh, thanks.
Caleb, hi.
Hi.
-It's good to see you.
-Good to see you.
You-- you look great.
-Thanks for meeting me.
-Yeah.
-Oh.
So, uh,
I-I think it's Brody?
-I'd love to see his picture.
-Yeah, yeah, yeah, of course.
Um.
Oh.
He's adorable.
Wow.
He looks just like you.
You have a mini-me.
Yeah, that's-- that's my boy.
He's growing up so quickly.
Well, if you ever need
a babysitter,
you can call me.
I mean that.
Really?
You sure?
I put the past behind me.
I don't resent you anymore.
So there's no reason
why we can't be friends.
I guess as long
as it's not painful for you.
-It's good to see you.
-You too.
Here you guys go.
Yes.
-You guys enjoy.
-Thank you.
-Of course.
Um, it's your favorite,
pastrami.
Yeah. Alright, let's do this.
No, problema.
I-I'll call Lucia.
Gracias.
Hola , Lucia.
You can't come in
Wednesday either?
Elena can't do it on Wednesday.
No. No, problema.
I'll-- I'll figure it out.
Gracias. Okay?
Oh, Fiona, I wish you were here.
Hi, Celine?
Yeah. Ab-- absolutely.
Are you sure?
Uh, yeah.
I'd be happy to.
Well, come by on Sunday
and if I see that you'll,
you know, do okay with him
then I'll let you
fill in on Wednesday.
-Wait, aren't you working?
-Not on Wednesdays.
Perfect.
Great.
Clean bottles are up there.
The tops are somewhere.
I'm sorry the kitchen's
such a mess.
-I haven't had time to clean.
-It's fine.
Yeah.
Look who woke up.
Oh! There he is.
May I?
Yeah.
Hey there, cutie,
We are gonna have so much fun,
aren't we? Aren't we?
All right. I gotta head out.
Um, you good?
I'm great.
Well, call me
if you need anything, okay?
-Celine.
-Yeah.
Thank you.
Bye.
I miss you so much.
Oh, is today Thursday?
I totally forgot
it was your day to watch him.
Um, Caleb had
to leave to work early.
If you want, I can watch him.
Celine, this is my grandbaby.
I have not seen him all week.
I watch him today.
You, you go home. Mm?
Last night reminded me
of the year
we first started going out.
Mm-hmm.
That was a fun time.
-Caleb.
-Mm-hmm.
Let's go home.
-Hi, Celine.
-Hi.
- Look, who's that?
- That's Mama.
That's Mama. Yeah.
Look, look. Who's that?
That's Abuelita.
Grandma.
Nana. Yeah.
You recognize her, huh?
Ah, she would've been
so happy to be here with you.
You look so much like her.
Look, it's mama again.
I can't tell you how
ecstatic I am for you, darling.
There was a minute there
where I thought
you'd spiral down
a rabbit hole so deep
that even I
couldn't dig you out.
Who's watching
the little bugger today?
His grandmother.
How's that dynamic?
What?
You and the grandmother?
I mean, she's his grandmother.
It is what it is.
If my mother were alive,
she'd be the one
watching him today.
Well, he is
an absolute heartbreaker.
Thanks.
I think he kinda looks like me.
Hmm.
Oh!
Oh my God. I know you.
This-- this is you, right?
You're Caleb.
I'm Fiona's sister, Fabiola.
-It is so nice to meet you.
-Hi. Yes. Uh, right.
I-I hope you don't mind.
Um, I'm--
my mom gave me her locket
after she passed.
No.
You know, I-I thought
we would've met sooner,
but you, um,
you weren't at the funeral.
Yeah. I-I'm sorry about that.
I just couldn't face going.
Yeah, no, I get it.
I can't believe
I ran into you like this.
I just moved back into town
and it's been
a little crazy,
but I've been meaning
to get in touch
because I'm dying
to meet my nephew, Brody.
Yeah. Yeah, of course.
Of course, you can meet him.
Um, and see 'em. Yeah.
Oh, God. I-I've seen
pictures of you before and--
and I know that you
were identical twins,
but to see you in person,
it's just,
it's crazy. Wow.
Yeah. Heh-- it used
to drive our friends crazy.
You know, I was gonna call
and schedule something,
but this just feels like a sign.
Is there any way
I could come over now?
Like right now, right now?
Yeah.
If that's-- if that's okay.
Oh, it-- it--
it's best to schedule it.
Um, you know what,
maybe instead on Saturday
we're having a block party
for Labor Day.
Maybe you can meet him then.
Oh, it's just,
it's gonna be my first time
meeting with Brody
and I really want
that moment to be private.
Please.
I-I will be super quick.
Yeah. Um, sure.
Why not?
Okay.
Are you ready now?
-Um, yeah. I'm ready.
-I'm just gonna leave those.
Okay.
Hey, honey.
You won't believe
who I ran into at the store,
and she's here to see Brody.
This is, uh, Fabiola.
Fiona's twin sister.
Twin sister.
Hi.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you as well.
Caleb never mentioned
she had a twin.
Oh, well, I'm sorry to intrude.
I told Caleb I've been meaning
to come by and meet the baby,
and I just,
I-I couldn't wait anymore.
Yeah.
Well, he's over there.
-Can I?
-Yeah.
Oh, you're cute.
Hi, baby Brody.
Oh my gosh.
He's the last thing
I have left of my sister.
I promise you,
I'm gonna be the best tia ever.
I'm gonna have these
all the time.
I'm gonna take all your photos.
He's so beautiful.
Is the baby asleep?
Yep.
I'm sorry for how I went down
today with, uh, Fabiola.
It's just we already have
the mother and the aunt,
and now the sister.
And you never told me
that she had a twin.
Well, look, she has a twin,
and now, you know.
And I understand why you're
upset, but this is family.
It isn't family.
Not your family. Not my family.
It's Brody's family,
and you can't change that.
I know, but do they have to be
so involved?
Brody is the only thing
they have left from Fiona.
Oh God! Yes. I know. I know.
I hear about it all the--
Hey, hey.
Lower your voice, okay?
The neighbors
are gonna hear you.
Oh, I'm so sorry
if I'm interrupting!
Listen, I invited Fabiola
to the block party tomorrow.
What?
Why would you do that?
Doesn't she have anything
else to do?
I know that this doesn't
occur to you,
but seeing her,
seeing her face
reminds me of losing you
and everything else
that went down.
I know.
And I'm sorry for that.
And... she looks just like her.
So, yeah, it's making
me feel a little uneasy.
You and I are back together.
Okay?
And you're Brody's mom now.
You're right.
This is our second chance,
and I don't wanna ruin that.
And maybe just, maybe
we can get married
again in the future.
-You mean that?
-Yes, I mean it.
Caleb.
All right?
Now let's relax
and enjoy our drinks.
Okay. You wanna put him
in the playpen?
Yeah. Oh, baby.
-He's tired.
-Come here.
Come here, Brody.
I'll show you pictures of your
mother another day, Brody.
Hey, Celine, can you please come
back here when you get a chance?
Yeah.
Here, sit down.
Yeah. Okay.
What did you do
with Fiona's pictures?
Oh, um, that's right.
Here.
Why did you make another booklet
with your pictures in it?
Excuse me?
Celine, we both agreed that
you're gonna be Brody's mother,
but the reason I did this
is so that he can see
his mother
and remember who she was.
This has been
hard on me too, Caleb.
Yeah, but this isn't about you.
You know what?
You never think about how I feel
or what I've been through.
Oh my God!
-Which one would you like?
-I want that one!
-That one! I want that one!
-This one?
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
-Yay!
You want a little turtle?
I want cotton candy.
Okay. Here, honey.
Thanks.
Yeah. I'll get a punch bowl
for the drink table.
What do you think?
Strawberry or orange?
Uh, either one should be fine.
Oh, and the balloon lady wanted
a bottle of water earlier.
I totally forgot
to give it to her.
Can you bring it to her
while they go and get the ice?
Sure thing.
You know, random thought.
I was thinking,
why on earth was I not invited
to your baby shower?
I mean, gosh.
-I know it was a long time ago--
-Time flies.
And you never mentioned
about the day you gave birth.
I mean, you know, us moms
love to indulge in the details.
Can we talk about this later?
The kids are lined up
around the block for some punch.
Okay, we'll catch up later.
Bitch.
Miguel, hey.
I know I haven't called.
I'm so sorry. It's rude of me.
I should have done it before,
but--
Don't be silly.
It's good to see you.
I heard you were in town
and wanted to know
what you were up to today.
Um, no real plans. Why?
Well, Fiona and I always spent
our holiday weekends together.
And I'd be lying if I said
you weren't the next best thing.
Thanks a lot.
Plus I haven't seen you
in forever.
Oh, you are so sweet.
You know what? I told Caleb
I would go to their block party.
Caleb? Wait, you met Caleb
and the baby already?
-Yeah.
-Oh, girl.
There's so much to catch up on.
Okay, go get ready.
-We're gonna be late.
-Okay.
Wait.
Uh, where are we going?
What should I wear?
-Oh.
I got you some lashes.
-Oh!
I was wondering if you
have a bikini to go with them.
- Hmm?
- Okay.
Maybe you can
help me pick something out?
-Yes.
-Okay.
I would like some.
Excuse me.
Can I get a beer, please?
- Oh, yeah. Of course.
- Thank you.
Mm, that's so strong.
-Oh, hey, Miguel.
-Hey!
Oh, girl, you look amazing.
-Thank you.
-Is all this real?
Everything but the lashes.
Okay. Okay.
Excuse me.
Get a strap on already. Ugh!
Never a dull moment, I swear.
Ooh, love this song.
Turn it up.
Ooh!
-Hey.
So you met the baby.
Yeah.
He's beautiful.
-Yeah.
-I already love him to death.
How have you been
dealing with everything?
Oh, Miguel.
It's been rough.
Yeah.
I just feel so guilty.
I can't believe
I wasn't there for her
-during her pregnancy.
-No.
I-I just wish I could have
been with her one more time.
Don't be so hard on yourself.
Fiona was the happiest
I had ever seen her.
I mean, she was
on her way to motherhood.
She had the man of her dreams.
And career-wise,
she was at the top of her game.
I mean,
that counts for something.
Yeah, it does.
I prefer you brunette.
What are you doing here?
This is a pleasant surprise.
Do you live close by?
It's none of your business.
Look at the balloons.
I miss Mama.
There you go.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Yeah. You good?
If you have any
more business for me,
you know the number...
...pretty lady.
It was a one-time thing.
I'm not gonna need
your services again.
So just walk away
and pretend
like I don't know you.
Never... say never.
Hey. Hey, you okay?
Who was that
you were talking to?
Oh, he was just
looking for something.
I'm starving.
You guys ready to eat?
Yeah. That cheeseburger
calling my name.
Do you wanna take him
and I'll make us a plate?
Yeah.
There you go.
Let's go.
Let's go get a hot dog.
Yeah, let's go get a hot dog.
Can I tell you something?
Yeah.
I have had this awful
feeling about her death.
What do you mean?
My mom said that
after the labor she was fine.
Yeah, she was.
I don't know,
it just doesn't make any sense.
Something about her death
just feels... off.
I don't know.
Maybe I'm just trying to
find something
or someone to blame.
Well, you can't blame yourself.
It'll get better.
Hey, uh. Oh, Doctor,
you, um, you dropped this.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
You know,
today really lifted my spirits.
I think Fiona would've liked
this: Us together.
I think so too.
Well, cheers to Fiona.
Cheers to our angel in heaven.
-Oh, no.
-What's wrong?
I just got promoted
to VP of Marketing.
Congratulations.
That's awesome.
-Why aren't you excited?
-Because they want me
to come into the office
for half the week.
Who's gonna watch the baby?
-I have to say no.
-What?
No. No. Celine...
you've been wanting this
for such a long time.
Yeah, but who's gonna
watch Brody?
You'll be home half the week.
Okay?
And I know you
don't wanna hear this,
but he's got
a family to watch him too.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
Come on. He's gonna be
in good hands and you know that.
Celine, take the position.
You deserve it.
It'll be a significant
pay increase.
And I would finally
be able to manage
-the direction of the company.
-There you go.
And maybe after a year,
they'd allow me to pick
and choose the hours I come in.
You really think he'll be okay?
I'm positive.
Alright.
I'm gonna say yes.
Sent.
Awesome. All right.
Let's go to dinner.
I'll coordinate with the family
and I'll text you
Fabiola's number, okay?
Um, why would I need
Fabiola's number?
Well, she's gonna
be excited to watch him.
She's part of the family.
Mmm! So proud of you.
Wow.
This is her last collection.
It's beautiful, Miguel.
Oh, wait. I'm sorry.
Can I take photos?
I wanted to show my mom.
Of course.
Just don't show anyone else.
You got it.
This collection's
gonna be such a hit.
And wait 'til
you see the men's line.
New York Fashion Week is
two and a half months away.
And in honor of Fiona,
the industry's
decided to give her an award.
I was wondering
if you could be there
to accept it on her behalf.
We're also gonna be
featured in Harper's Bazaar,
and I'll need to book a couple
photographers for that shoot.
-Are you available?
-For this?
-Absolutely.
-Oh, fantastic.
I'm also gonna invite the family
and Caleb
to New York Fashion Week.
I think it could be a good idea.
-Miguel, they would love that.
-Okay. Great.
My assistant booked
a block of rooms at the hotel,
so just give me
confirmation on who can come.
-I'm on it.
-Great.
Can I ask you a favor?
Yeah.
Do you think after
the show I could keep one?
Consider it done.
Yeah. Yeah.
Hey, baby Brody
- Brody, look who's here.
- Hi.
-Look who's here.
-Hello.
Oh.
Look who's here-- oh!
Thanks for coming.
I could use some fresh air.
-And it's such a beautiful day.
-It is.
So what were you up to today?
Oh, I was just at the studio
with Miguel.
Oh, by the way,
uh, you and the family
are invited
to New York Fashion Week.
They're gonna be honoring
my sister with an award
and I'm gonna be there
to accept it on her behalf.
Nice! Yeah, send me the dates.
Yeah.
Are you--
are you a designer as well?
No, no.
I love clothes,
but I can't make 'em.
I don't even know how to sew.
Um, but I am in the industry.
I thought so.
I just wasn't sure.
I'm a fashion photographer.
Oh, nice. Yeah.
And speaking of,
I have yet to take pictures
of this little guy.
-Oh.
-Hi.
Hi, baby.
Oh, wow.
Yeah. You're a natural.
You know what, Brody,
if you get the height,
we're gonna put you to work.
Oh, yes, we will.
Oh, hey. Hold that.
Hmm?
Oh.
You have a really nice features.
Thank you.
I, um, I guess
I missed my calling.
Maybe.
Here. Brody.
Hi, baby.
Can-- can I see that?
Yeah.
Oh, wow. These are--
these are pretty amazing.
Maybe I could be
in the next top model, huh?
Maybe you can.
I'll-- I'll call around for you.
Well, this is a first for me.
I've never had pizza
delivered at the park before.
Wow.
This is surreal.
What is?
I mean, I'm here with
my sister's baby and with you,
but she's not with us.
Yeah. I could've, um,
never imagined it would've
turned out this way.
This must be so hard for you.
And for you too.
Yeah.
I'm sorry, I-I gotta get this.
Okay?
Of course.
Hello?
Yes. This is Caleb.
What?
No, no, no.
The-- the owner of the building
told me it was
an electrical shortage.
Are you sure?
Please, if you find out
anything else, let me know.
Is everything okay?
That was an arson investigator.
He said that the fire
at Fiona's baby shower
was due to arson.
I told him,
"No, you must be confused
because the owner
of the building told me
that it was an electrical
shortage."
And he said
that I was misinformed.
Oh my God.
I just got chills.
And that there's no leads and...
that the case might
come to a close.
Wait. So do they think
it was, like, a fluke thing?
Like an accident?
Or they think
it was intentional?
No.
Uh, arson is no accident.
I know, but that
doesn't make any sense.
I mean, who would do something
like that intentionally,
and at a baby shower no less?
I don't know.
But I'm gonna find out.
It does seem odd,
but it's not exactly proof.
If she was behind this,
you'll find out eventually.
But I don't know, man.
Arson?
Doesn't sound like Celine.
Well, she vandalized
her house during that time.
She was--
she was acting pretty crazy.
Allen] Yeah. You both
have been through a lot.
I wouldn't stir the pot unless
it's absolutely necessary.
Yeah. Yeah. You're right, man.
Thanks.
All right.
We'll talk later, okay?
Any movement,
make the call out.
Copy that.
Do not drop.
Damn it!
Suspect has fled
in a black vehicle headed south.
Yeah, we--
we've been over this.
Can you come back early?
Why spend
two extra days in New York?
Because I could really
use the break.
I invited you to come,
and you still can.
What? What was that?
It's really loud in here.
- I love you.
- I love you too.
We'll talk soon. Okay?
Ooh, those are great.
-Yes. Ah!
-Nice. Huh?
-I love that one.
-Yeah.
Ooh,
I think they're ready for us.
Oh, okay.
Alright. Well,
we're gonna head backstage,
-but enjoy the show.
-I will.
There you are.
There you are. Okay.
Um, male model,
I forgot his name.
-Um, number three--
-What? Spit it out.
-He didn't show up.
-And you're telling me this now?
I think he's hungover
from last night or something.
I don't care.
What about Eric?
-Can't he just--
-No, we tried that.
He's first in their segment
and it's not gonna work.
-Fabiola?
-Yes.
Male model, waist size 32.
Do you know anyone?
We need him in makeup
in five minutes.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'll be right back.
-Go do something.
-Okay.
Hey, um, could I actually
borrow you for a minute?
-Yeah, of course.
-Okay.
Um, are you guys
sure you want me?
I-I am not a model.
You can pretend to be.
And don't be so stiff. Relax.
They'll show you how to do it.
-Just good call, Fabiola.
-You'll be great.
-Shot?
-Yes, please.
-Cheers.
Oh God.
God, that's strong.
-Oh my God.
-Showtime.
Okay, let's go.
You ready?
Okay.
God, I hope he doesn't trip.
For the most
innovative, creative,
and inspiring fashions
of the year,
I present Miguel Munoz
and the late Fiona Hernandez
of Spark Fashion Line,
this award
for Designer of the Year.
Fiona's sister,
Fabiola Hernandez
is here to accept the award.
Thank you.
Oh my God. I-I was so
nervous, but I-I did my best.
Oh, I know. I was like, who is
that coming outta nowhere?
-You were fantastic.
-You did so great.
Yeah. And you picked
up that walk so fast.
-Thank you.
-Oh, you were fierce.
Good evening.
This show was fantastic.
Thank you.
It was phenomenal.
Let's set up something.
Let's talk.
Of-- of course.
Have a wonderful night.
- Thank you.
- You too.
I think I'm gonna faint.
-Oh, my God!
-What? Who was that?
Frederic Raphael.
What--
He's one of the hottest
designers right now.
The hottest. Oh my gosh.
Well, this is unreal.
Amazing.
Okay.
This guy is officially obsessed
with the Hernandez family.
Mm.
Damn!
That was a nice hotel, huh?
Yeah.
I'm really glad you came out.
I had a great time
with the show and--
-and getting to know you.
-Yeah, me too.
I'm definitely gonna add,
uh, modeling to my resume now.
This is one of the best weekends
I've had in a long time.
Yeah.
Just wish it didn't have to end.
Um, so, you know,
maybe we can do some lunch
or coffee back in LA?
Yeah.
And you'd bring Brody.
He would love that.
Oh, it looks
like that's your taxi.
Yeah.
Alright. Well, I'll--
I'll see you back.
Um, have a safe flight.
Okay?
Okay. You too.
I couldn't be happier.
I mean, sales
are already through the roof.
I know. Ever since
the photo shoot was published,
I've been getting
calls from all over.
Right on, girlfriend.
Okay.
Now for the nitty gritty.
What the fuck
is up with you and Caleb?
I can't even believe I'm having
this conversation right now.
Oh my God, this is so weird.
Okay. First of all,
you cannot tell anyone.
You sound like Fiona.
Oh my God. I know. We always
had the same taste in men.
I remember, girl.
Look, but the second thing is,
I am not seeing him, okay?
I am not about to let this guy
have an ongoing affair again.
That chick better
have a side piece by now.
He's a catch.
I can see why my sister
was hung up on him.
This is like the never-ending
soap opera.
I mean, what is this guy's
dick made of? Gold?
-Hey, I did not sleep with him.
-Yet.
Deja fucking vu.
So how's that new position
at work coming along?
Uh, it's demanding
and challenging at times.
But the, uh, creative freedom
makes it enjoyable.
Nice.
You want seconds?
Yeah, sure.
I mean, well, I'm a little full,
but yeah, why not?
These are really good.
Thank you, sweetie.
I appreciate it. Okay?
And now for our top story.
A local doctor makes America's
Most Wanted list
for the murder
of one of his patients.
Dr. Simon Smith, who worked
at Lagoon Medical Center
for the past ten years
is now a fugitive
who has been on the run
for the past two months.
If you have seen this man,
please contact the authorities.
A $50,000 reward
is being offered.
Are you hearing this?
That doctor
is wanted for murder.
That's terrible.
Yeah.
He murdered one of his patients.
And it's at the same hospital
that Brody was born at.
Was he an obstetrician?
No, I don't-- I don't think so.
But I feel like
I've seen him somewhere.
Really? Where?
I don't know.
He just looks really familiar.
That happened to me once.
I kept thinking that
I saw someone wanted for murder.
Strange how the mind works.
I was just hoping
you know that I saw him
'cause people like that
deserve to be caught.
What a crazy ass
world we live in.
-I hope they catch his ass.
-Me too.
Hey, babe.
Hey.
- Is he asleep?
- No, he's uh, with Elena.
- Oh.
- Come sit down.
Okay.
Oh, this looks amazing.
I love it when you cook.
May I?
Yes, please.
Hmm.
Try some.
How do you like it?
It's delicious.
Okay.
Celine,
how do you know Dr. Smith?
Who?
Don't act stupid.
I-- I don't know
who you're talking about.
I want you to be honest.
I am.
I don't know a Dr. Smith.
Hmm.
He's the man
that's wanted for murder.
I saw you talking
to him at the block party.
Um, you lost me.
Cut the shit, Celine.
You were talking to him
and it wasn't
about fucking decorations.
He was the man wearing
the blue Hawaiian shirt.
Uh, that guy.
Um, yeah.
Uh, uh, he was looking
for something.
I remember him because he had
a bottle of wine for the booth.
I-I don't remember him
and I certainly
didn't know he was a doctor.
He said something to you
and I noticed
because you gave him that look.
The same look
you're giving me right now.
So I'm gonna
ask you one more time.
How the fuck
do you know Dr. Smith?
I don't know him.
You're fucking lying to me.
Let me go, please. Stop.
Stop, Caleb.
You're not gonna leave this
house
until you
tell me the truth!
Caleb, please, let me go.
Please, let me go.
Please, let me go. Please.
What did you give me?
It's gonna wear off
in a few hours, okay?
You drugged me.
I'm sorry, baby.
Just tell me the truth.
Tell me what happened, okay?
And then we can
go pick up Brody.
Huh?
I didn't wanna do it.
I just wanted you back
and I wanted to have our baby.
I paid Dr. Smith
to take Fiona out.
I did it. I did it for us.
You are happy, Caleb.
I know that you are.
And-- and--
and it is in the past.
And I'm not a murderer.
I'm not a bad person.
Oh, Celine.
I'm so sorry
if I caused you to be this.
Untie me.
We don't have to tell anyone.
We can, um,
we can move past this.
And the fire?
I-I didn't wanna hurt anyone.
I just wanted to scare them.
She was pregnant.
You could have killed my son.
You could have killed my son,
you crazy bitch.
Oh my God.
You killed Fiona.
You killed my wife.
I'm your wife,
right here in front of you.
We have a beautiful family.
What was your plan, Celine?
Huh?
What do you think?
When they catch the doctor,
what do you think,
he wasn't gonna sell you out?
So what?
Are you gonna go to the police?
I am leaving,
and I'm taking Brody with me.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Caleb.
Caleb, please.
You can't. You can't.
You can't take
Brody from me, please.
Please. I'm-- I'm--
I'm his mother. I'm his mother.
I'm sure he is gonna be
thrilled to learn
that his mother is no
longer here because of you!
I was taking my life back.
That bitch
got what she deserved.
You should rot in hell.
Caleb. Caleb, please.
You love me.
I know that you do.
How could I ever forgive you?
You murdered my angel.
So you're gonna tell her family?
No. And not because
I wanna save your sorry ass.
Because this would crush them.
I'm done with you.
I'm done
with everything, Celine.
No. No, no, no, no.
Caleb. Caleb. Caleb. Caleb.
Caleb! Caleb.
Caleb, please come back!
Caleb, no! No, Caleb, no.
No! No! No!
Caleb! Caleb!
Caleb, please
don't leave me alone.
Please don't
leave me alone, Caleb.
Please don't leave me alone.
Daddy, daddy,
look what I can do.
How about
we show your daddy outside?
Why?
Because I might break something?
-That's right, buttercup.
-Exactly.
-Good morning, sunshine.
-Good morning, baby.
Couldn't wait
to put on your costume, huh?
He is very excited.
Come on, Daddy.
Let's go play outside.
All right. You go first.
All right?
Remember what I taught you,
okay? Let's go.
You've been practicing.
Let's show Daddy.
Future champion right here.
All right, Brody, you ready?
Everything I've been teaching
you.
All right. Here we go. Let's go.
Yes. Good job. You see?
You got the-- you almost
got the spin right there.
-Good job!
-Here we go.
Yes! Good job.
Yes! Yes. Good job.
Look, one-handed like daddy.
Oh, that takes
a little bit longer at practice.
Good job, dude.
Oh, yes. Good job.
Here. Go catch. Oh, good catch.
You're doing so good, Brody.
Yes. Just by the laces
like I taught you. Yes.
Daddy is showing off.
Yeah.