Imperial diary, year 10191, third comment.
The battle for Arrakis
took everyone by surprise.
There were no witnesses.
The Harkon and Operation was
perpetrated overnight, without warning.
Or a declaration of war.
The warning, the Atreides were no more.
I'll guide in the dark.
And the Emperor said...
Since that night my father
has not been the same.
Nor have I.
His inaction is difficult for me to accept.
By the calculus of power.
This would not be the first time the
Harkonans have done his dirty work.
The end of House Atreides.
Shouldn't you go back to the stars?
Be with him?
I'm afraid I won't have enough time
to fix things before you're coming.
This world is beyond cruelty.
Stay here.
Don't be a cop! No, no, no, no.
The Harkon and Operation are over.
How are you? I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Are you okay? I'm fine.
I'm fine.
Never stand with your
back towards the open.
How many times do I have to
tell you that, huh? You okay? Yeah.
How about her? She's fine.
I do not usually venture this deep.
I want to make sure no Atreides escaped.
You think too much of yourself.
No, no, we are in the deep desert.
Only freemen can survive here.
They were here for us, not for you.
Don't worry.
I'm taking you somewhere
they will never find us.
Filthy water.
It's full of chemicals, but good
enough for cooling system.
Turn it out.
You okay?
Don't let that out.
Don't let it out! I can't.
No, I can't.
I'm okay.
Are you sure?
You fought well.
Once you woke up.
I wasn't sleeping.
Subtitle made by Master_Blaster for https://subscene.com/
I'm sorry.
No, no, no.
I'll die.
Now that the spies found
some insecurity, I strongly
recommend bringing all troops
out of frame and territories.
We're losing too many men to the desert.
Rats.
I beg your pardon?
We're losing them.
They're rats.
For freemen, I can't confirm our
communications are hectic in the open sands.
Your orders.
We need to control the whole planet.
We are.
That's the only half of it.
As you may recall, the South
is an uninhabitable minority.
May I suggest you get some rest?
Rats!
Kill them all!
He's asking why we're so late.
We're going to have to get out of here.
He thinks your spies are so late.
They're not going to be here.
He's over there.
I got that.
Thanks.
Stay close to me.
You're welcome.
They'll come.
I will come now.
U.S.S.
S has been Some of them
already think I'm their messiah.
Others... False prophet.
I must sway the non-believers.
If they follow me, we can
disrupt spice production.
That's the only way I
can get to the Emperor.
Your father didn't believe in revenge.
Hell, I do.
What's happening?
The way he's on his electsets.
What is it?
There's slicing up food.
It's a year for Howard Gino to a fever.
It's a rifle.
I'm not sure what the bottom is, does she?
Woman, come with me.
Dying thirst would ever drink this water.
This is sinking.
We have thousands of places
where we have enough water.
The lizanal cave will
change the face of Arrakis.
It will bring back the trees, it
will bring back a green paradise.
Yes, that's, that's, that's.
I'm going to get you a water
away, not even for the dead.
Why are you showing me this?
Because you were benedigess of it,
because you understand the prophecies.
The mother of the lizanal
cave will be our very mother.
However, mother is dying.
You want me to take
her place? Yes, I do.
Do you believe in Paul?
There are signs.
Yes.
What if I would refuse?
There is not lizanal cave, and
you have no purpose to serve.
What else is left to do then
but return your water to the well?
Oh.
It's an honor, isn't it?
I think you should feel honored.
Well, it was a choice between this or
death, so forgive me if I'm not flattered.
How does one become a reverend mother?
It's different from one culture to another.
Here on Arrakis, I have no idea.
You're afraid.
The reverend mother is a
task withholding the memories
of all the reverend mothers
that came before them,
so I'll be given centuries
of pain and sorrow.
Is it dangerous?
It's lethal for men, that's for sure.
What are you guys
laughing about? Don't bother.
You don't believe in
all this? No, we don't.
These are all southern beliefs.
Southern beliefs?
Southern tribes believe that messiah
will come to deliver us from evil.
You don't believe in them, lizanal cave?
We believe in Fremen, Bilal Kaifa.
You want to control people?
You tell them a messiah will come.
Then they'll wait for centuries.
No, we must pray.
What about him?
Stovar? He's from the south.
He didn't notice his accent.
What will happen to my mother?
She's from the south.
He's from the south.
He's from the south, but you can't
tell him that he's from the south.
It's a It's a It's
a It's a It's a
It's a It's a
It's a
It's a What is it? 5, 6.
..
6...
She's right!
It's no miracle.
My mother was trained to do that.
Poisoned transmutation is something
advanced men in Jezeroine can do.
I'm not the Mahdi.
I'm not here to lead.
N'zia hajika.
Gef dak.
Let me fight beside you.
I'll wait.
I'm not the Mahdi.
Gef dak.
I'm the Mahdi.
I'm in the Mahdi.
I'm not the Mahdi.
How is she?
She was frightened, but she's...
She's okay.
Paul, she talks to me.
She believes in you.
She says,
they go inside that rock,
and she will hold you.
You're so close now.
Only one step remains,
and you will become the Goi-Satat Rock.
Only one step remains.
You must do what I did.
You must drink the water of life.
For your mind, it's gonna... It's
gonna open, and you will see.
Oh, yes, you do.
You sweet jerk!
If you wanna fight with us,
first thing you must learn
to be one with the desert.
So, here is a tent
and enough food.
I want you to cross
that small egg and come back.
Travel by night.
You know how to use a paracombas.
Yes.
Anything else I should know?
Beside the worms and the harconins,
beware of the trapdoor spiders.
Centipedes are very nasty.
Not the big ones.
They are harmless.
But the little ones,
you have to worry about.
Don't ever,
ever listen to that jian.
The jian?
Jian, desert spirits.
They whisper at night,
on and at somewhere.
The king says you.
Really, be careful.
They are demons.
Gah! But it's true.
Don't listen to them.
If you don't listen to them,
you have to listen to them.
What do you want to give them?
I don't want to.
I don't want to give them anything.
I want to give them anything.
Jamis.
Sandwalk like a drunk lizard.
I'm doing pretty good so far.
You're not even in worm territory yet.
You have to break up your rhythm.
Like this.
Now that's interesting because
in the film books I've studied,
the anthropologists say in
order to properly sandwalk,
you actually have to...
Never mind.
Please keep going.
You know, I'm the only one who believes
you're going to make it until summer.
Everyone else thinks you
won't make it two weeks.
If you want to follow us in the desert,
you need to know how wind traps work.
So listen to me.
They're simple.
They require constant attention.
This right here in cash is the question.
Here's the answer.
These are the answers that needs
to be changed every three weeks.
One.
Stop looking at me like that.
If we want to protect your brother,
we need all the Fremen
to believe in the prophecy.
We must convert the non-believers.
We need to start with the weaker ones.
For fun.
Fuck! I got you.
You're the only one! I got you.
..
No... ... ... ... ... ... ...
... ... ...
...
... ...
... ... ...
...
... ...
... ... ... ...
... ... ... ... ...
...
... ... ...
The ways of thinking.
You know everything about the desert.
You harness the very power of it.
We can stop them together.
Bury them in the sand where they belong.
So that this planet can be yours once more.
What will you have us do?
What would you do? Still there?
I would strike even further north.
Then I will go further north.
The further north you go
the more likely it is you die.
The future will not be over either.
You know everything about the desert.
Still there.
Also there's the very power of it.
Please give your attention.
Have a little bit of time.
Give it!
You shall be known
among us as Usul, and now
a Fedeikin is a fighter
and needs a warning.
You shall be known among
us as Usul, and now a
Fedeikin, and now a
Fedeikin, and now a Fedeikin,
now a Fedeikin, and
now a Fedeikin, and now a
Fedeikin, and now a
Fedeikin, and now a Fedeikin,
now a Fedeikin, and now a
and now a Fedeikin, and
That is a powerful name.
Now you are our brother...
...or Muad'Dib Ussul.
Oi! Your hands.
Oi, I think Ussul.
Go ahead.
Ussul.
It's breathtaking.
Look.
Hide there, Spice.
The rakis is so beautiful
when the sun is low.
Where are you from?
Does water really fall
from the sky? Oh, yes.
Sometimes it rains for weeks.
I'm coming down.
Where do you see sand
here? Imagine water.
Our castle stands on cliffs,
high above the sea.
If you dive in, you can't reach the bottom.
You dive in?
Yes.
It's cold swimming.
I don't believe Ussul.
Ussul.
What's your secret name? Sihaya.
Sihaya.
What does that mean?
It means desert spring.
Desert spring.
I love it.
I hate it.
It's from some stupid prophecy.
I prefer Johnny.
I prefer Johnny too, then.
Do you think Silver
will teach me? To write.
No.
Only from in write parts.
By name, not by blood.
Your blood melts from
dukes and great houses.
We don't have that here.
Here.
Or equal.
Men and women.
Home.
More deep, Ussul.
Maybe you could be from him.
Maybe I'll show you the way.
I want to know how you feel.
I wish I was gonna say no.
For emen attacks, on your
watch, your orders were
to restore spies'
production to full capacity.
Do you know what it means if you fail?
The emperor will take
spies out of our control.
Tighten your grip, Revan.
I'll call.
Or feel mine on your neck.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. It's okay.
I'm here. I'm here.
It's been a while since you've
had one of those nightmares.
Tell me, what was it about?
Nothing's clear. It's only fragments.
I'm in the south, and
I'm following someone.
And it triggers a holy war.
Millions and millions of people
starving to death because of me.
You've been exposed to spies for a
long time. They can create weird dreams.
It's a big day.
But can I still work on it all?
No. I'm fine. I'm sorry.
I do met myself. Here.
Thanks.
Don't try to impress anyone.
You're brave. We all know that.
Be simple. Be direct. Nothing fancy.
Nothing fancy?
Hey, I'm serious. Nothing fancy.
You will shame my teaching.
I will shame you. I understand.
Shai Hulu decides today if you
become Fremen. Or if you die.
Hey, what's up? What's going on?
What's going on?
What's going on? It's me.
Ah! Hey, what's
going on? I'm sorry.
I'm trying to get out.
Let me tell you something.
I will not kill you.
Give it up!
They believe in Paul.
Now we go south.
There are millions of
fundamentalists there.
They will protect
him when he comes.
The quiz that's happening
will be born in the south.
As long as I breathe, I'm sorry.
There will be trouble.
What are you talking about?
Finally, what do you mean?
The way they look at you.
They were from you now.
The night you make out your
victories is so you can see the future.
I suppose he's not okay.
I don't know, Messiah.
I'm a Phidican, I've see-stopped.
Yet we have a penny just
right among us, fanning
the flames of your legend,
saying you're the one.
She says you should be coming with us.
No, I can't.
She's asking why?
Because I must
continue fighting in the
north to protect you
down there in the south.
She says she can tell when you lie.
Tell her that's because our mother
keeps spreading dangerous tales.
What is she saying?
She says you're blinded by
love, and she reminds you that
you must reserve your hand
for the most strategic alliance.
She's also wondering why
you don't believe in who you are.
I do believe.
I believe I matter to these people.
I believe I'm making
a difference in this war.
We're nearly at the gates of the city.
That's not what she means.
I know what she means.
Do you not think I also feel
the weight of the prophecy?
It's a story that you keep telling,
but it's not their story, it's yours.
They deserve to be led by one of their own.
What your people did to
this world is heartbreaking.
We gave them something to hope for.
That's not hope!
We should not leave the security perimeter!
Security perimeter! The rest hope so!
Or should I give them my word?
Today, we'll keep doing it!
We'll keep doing it!
One day!
Show yourself!
No!
It's unlocked! It's unlocked!
So no, Fremen prophet.
It's not the first time we've
had frictions with the Fremen.
None of this magnitude.
So, my dear daughter,
how would you deal with this prophet?
If this Muad'Dib is a religious figure,
you can't use direct force.
Repression only makes a religion flourish.
You'll only end up humiliating yourself.
You underestimate my side of God.
You underestimate the power of faith.
The Highness proves once again
that she was my most acute student.
It's an assassin's.
No.
Prophets get stronger when they die.
Let the conflict on Arrakis turn into war.
You then bring peace.
As a savior.
You'll be a formidable empress.
Muad'Dib,
the prophet, the one who points the way.
These are our own
religious patterns, aren't they?
This is our doing.
Muad'Dib means kangaroo mouse.
An unusual warning for a Fremen.
What if all the treaties were still alive?
Enough!
This must not come out.
Even to your father's
ears, understand? I do, Rep.
Mother.
If Paul is alive, he
likely knows the truth.
And should the great
houses learn that your
father was behind the
liquidation of the Atreides,
your father will face
war and lose the throne.
Then what hope is there? Hope.
We are Bene Gesserit.
We don't hope.
We plan.
Paul is not our only prospect.
The Baron's youngest nephew,
Fade-Rotha Harkonnen, will inherit Arrakis.
He may be the answer.
Fade-Rotha? He's psychotic.
That's irrelevant.
The question is, can we control him?
And I intend to find out.
Would you like some fresh
meats, my darling? Thanks.
Lungs.
A liver.
What would you like?
I hear they're big today.
Your new blades.
For this very special day.
Napa and Fade-Rotha.
And not your bones.
It's the dip.
Should be sharpened.
Come!
I won't die like a fool.
Kill me now.
No drug for you today, Atreides.
Take this long, oldie.
What do you want?
This fight's all for sure.
But we'll get a good look at him.
We can cancel the fight.
I'll explore my nephew's birthday.
Who's there?
I said it!
Why'd we not stop the fight?
Transloping plans?
Show me who you are.
...
... ...
Don't be hasty.
I have another gift for you. A bigger one.
A ruckus.
What about Robert?
He has failed to protect Spice production.
Robert would be reassigned.
Claim a ruckus fight.
Free the Spice. I'll make you Emperor.
How?
The Emperor helped
me destroy their traitors.
And led his own army to the course.
A serious crime.
If it came to light, the great
houses would rise against him.
And then... Who will sit on
the throne? Fade Rawthog.
Park it in.
You're following me.
Am I?
I may have gotten lost.
Will you show me the way out at this maze?
My Lord Nabarin.
We've met, our dream.
I don't think so.
I'm Lady Margot Fenry.
I'm here to honor your coming of age.
You're not allowed in this section.
How did you get past
the guards? The guards.
May I ask what are you doing here?
You're not taking part
in your own celebrations.
You're better desert.
And why?
I dreamed about you last night.
A pleasant dream I hope.
Don't mock me on that.
Why would you dare?
Right now you've been a jesser in tricks.
And what do you know about
the name of jesserit? Tell me.
Is something wrong?
I don't recognize this place.
This is the guest way.
Where are you going? To my room.
Put your right hand in the box.
A sociopath of high intelligence, driven,
cruel, but strongly motivated by honor.
He yearns to be hurt.
He loves pain.
Can he be redeemed?
He can be controlled.
He's sexually vulnerable.
And?
The bloodline is secured.
A female, as you requested.
You did well, Margot.
Respectfully, why didn't
you test him yourself?
Well, I'm a mother, Eichika.
And based on what
happened between him and his
own mother, I didn't
expect to be effective.
What happened between him
and his mother? He mad at her.
Desire and humiliation.
Those are his levers.
If Fade Rother prevails on Arrakis,
we shall know how to control him.
Fade Rother.
Bring me a misremend, gamer.
These idiots, I blame.
A still suit is full of piss.
It's caked in sand.
Save me for these better
morons than I ever were.
Juicy.
Juicy, Juicy.
Oh, that was nice knowing you.
Oh, yeah?
All right, that was clear, man. Come here.
Jessie, Jessie.
Yeah, I got a meter reading a point.
Hey, guys, words are on their way.
I got a meter reading a point.
Fade!
Come on, Fade!
You're your pup.
You're your pup!
Well, after the Battle
of Arrakeen, I was able
to negotiate a trip back
home for the survivors.
Thanks to these guys.
Why'd you stay? I wanted blood.
Rabon's head.
Since Muad'Dib has been
driving Rabon crazy, the
smuggling business
has been quite profitable.
Guardian, I like the smuggler.
Paul Muad'Dib.
I've heard many stories about Muad'Dib.
None of them pretty.
You'll see the fear.
That our resources are limited.
Fear is all we have.
How many men with
you? Two hundred.
Two hundred!
Shh!
Do you realize what you were able
to achieve with two hundred men?
Incredible fighters.
Duncan said there were millions of them.
In the Deep South.
Yes.
Well, what are you waiting for?
With thousands of these guys, you
can take control of the entire planet.
It's your father's dream.
What are you afraid of? Fate.
Worship, Gurney.
I used to be friends.
Now they're followers.
Muad'Dib, the prophet.
Why is that a bad thing? Use it.
It's not that simple.
You have the power to avenge
your father and you're afraid to use it.
Spice opened my mind, Gurney.
I can foresee things.
If I go south, all my
visions lead to horror.
Billions of corpses
scattered across the galaxy.
All dying because of me.
Because you lose control.
Because I gain it.
That's a lot of water.
Johnny.
What? Academy's hopeless.
He's family.
What?
Really?
You don't need to be a
prophet to see what's ahead.
Your path leads to war.
You know that.
So war is coming.
What will you do when you
feel its breath upon your neck?
If you don't want to raise an army in
this house, you still have an option.
Fire power.
Which you don't have.
And here I am.
I know where your father
hid the family atomics.
Every house possesses an atomic arsenal.
And I thought ours had been lost.
It's huge, Johnny.
It could change everything.
And I could aim the bombs
at the main spice fields.
He who can destroy a
thing has the real control of it.
So you can control it and not us?
You promised me you didn't want power.
No matter what I do,
you still don't trust me.
Because you're a foreigner.
You're your friend.
I'm not a foreigner.
Not to me, but to the desert you are.
My allegiance is to you. To the Fremen.
I'm doing this for all of us.
Do you believe me?
I'll talk to you so far.
There.
It's right under everybody's noses.
Not clever.
That's the idea. Nobody would ever
look in there because it's obvious.
Not clever.
Did you find it?
I didn't look for it.
How many heads exactly?
Enough to blow up the whole planet.
It's a figure of speech.
You know what I mean.
Only with your genetic heritage.
Your great-great-grandfather's legacy.
The 92 original Atreides
family's atomic warheads.
But that... That is power.
Imperial diary.
Near 10,191.
Eighth comment.
Reports from the south
of Arrakis arrive rarely.
These are barren, burnt lands.
Hidden by sandstorms which stretch
a thousand miles across the equator.
Nothing can live there without faith.
Which is why our Bene Gesserit
missionaries have been so productive there.
Through them we are receiving
reports of a mysterious figure taking
grip on the imaginations of the
southern fundamentalist tribes.
A new Reverend Mother from the north.
Spreading word of the imminent
arrival of the Lusan Al-Ga'ib.
The voice from the outer world.
With religious fervor
rising in the south, and
Wadiib strangling spice
production in the north.
Everything points to the escalation of war.
A young, young woman who has been
a young, young woman who has been a young,
young woman who has been a young woman.
What is it?
With eyes?
You give that child a chance.
Listen carefully. Soon
a man is going to visit
your temple and he may
want you to perform the rites.
Reven mother, it is forbidden.
He mother shall let me.
An old fashioned artillery, a genius, they're
literally melting rock on their heads.
I want to go on the ground.
Prepare my troops, Lord.
I would recommend you stay inside those.
Bring his body to my quarters.
My poor Darnax are hungry.
There's no food for them on the flight.
What are you doing here?
It's early morning.
It's my feet, brother.
You humiliated our family.
You humiliated me.
In case...
I... ...won't die.
We're even up.
And there is our family one more time.
It will be the last.
We'll be back in a few minutes.
We've been waiting for a long time.
We're waiting.
We'll be back.
Ushul, in the south, only
leaders are allowed to speak.
You must take my place.
I can't do that.
It is a good time to cross blades with me.
I am weak, I am an easy kill.
I'd rather cut off my own hand.
We need you, we need the list
of Ganga'ib to lead our people.
You know what I think of all that so long?
I don't care what you believe, I believe!
I didn't see it coming.
The Harkins aren't done here.
They just went back to reload.
We're setting thumpers.
We'll be moving everyone to the south.
I'll stay behind and cover your retreat.
What are you talking about, Johnny?
I can't go with you.
You know why? I'll stay too.
Nobody stays with me.
Paul, that's an order!
Gurney, how it goes south?
Protect my mother.
My lord.
What's the matter?
I don't know what to do.
He's afraid of the fundamentalist.
He should be.
Don't resist.
Oh, son, son of a...
You see what you've heard of us.
You cannot see the future.
You have seen the past.
You are all your mind.
You need to drink the water of life.
And you will see everything.
The good hunter always learns
the highest tune before his hunter.
He needs to see.
As far as he can see.
You need to see.
You must drink the water of life.
Your mind and the world
has made choices for us.
Tell them I'll lose you.
You will never lose me.
Not as long as you stay where you are.
Spy, left behind.
No trace of the others.
They've gone south to hide in the storms.
Send this message to the Baron.
The North has liberated and secured.
Horace spies at will.
Yes, no Baron.
No sir.
You killed nine of my
men with one single blade.
She won't talk.
Tell her that's fine.
I already know everything I need to know.
All in pleasure, imagine.
So is she in the detail exit.
Is that who you are?
Who are you so like
to us? Without men.
Without men, they are just as bad as men.
How do I have to talk to her?
So close!
I won't go down to them.
Don't tell them to.
She's coming to me.
Paul? Paul? I'm here.
I'm here.
What happened?
What happened? He's dead.
His vital signs are so
low they can't be detected.
But he's alive.
What did you do
to him? No, not that.
Why would he do that?
Why would you do
that? I don't know.
He's dead.
I don't know.
Johnny, his body is fighting the
poison and he needs your help.
You do it.
You did this to him.
You did this to your own son.
You do it. Fix it yourself.
Johnny, you might not believe in
the prophecy, but you're a part of it.
You're the poison.
You and your lies.
Why would you do
this? She's a mother.
Someone just.
..
She's a mother.
You're not going to kill her, are you?
You're not going to kill her.
Because it's very tears.
She'll come to understand.
I've seen it.
You can see.
The visions are clear now.
I see possible futures all at once.
Our enemies are all around us.
And in so many futures they prevail.
But I do see a way.
There is a narrow way through.
I saw our bloodline mother,
written across time.
Did my father know?
I found myself until he
took the worm's poison.
This is how we'll survive.
By being our argument.
We will survive.
Do you hear me?
You have the power to stop this.
No, I'm willing.
You're not going to
speak inside the circle.
If you were to speak, you know what to do.
Still not, please.
I can save him.
This prophecy is how they enslave us.
How they dominate us.
You'll get yourself in trouble.
This is not your business.
My bond harkening
himself killed my family and
gave me a bit of a start
of remembering mine.
This is all of my business.
You must take his place by defeating
him and returning his water to the well.
You think I'm stupid enough to
deprive myself of the best of us.
Did you not give me work somehow?
I've taken my life or so long.
It is the only way.
I'm pointing the way!
Ooh, that ass suck!
Ooh, thou fizzy!
They free pit!
Call money!
Die!
Do you think you could have a chance?
It's not the judge.
It's the judge.
She says that she's the only
one who wants to make it.
You're the one who wants to make it.
I'm going to take it.
I'll take it.
Or I'll take it.
The room.
Is that the case?
When you are ready,
the judgeless want to make it.
He will be the judge.
You see the game, Shadi?
I suck like I am.
I should've been hooked.
This is my father's ducal signet.
All my demon trees, duke of Arrakis!
Everything did not have seen at me!
Let me start my game!
Ruined the ghetto!
I should've been hooked.
While Atreides is still alive,
he challenges my father.
You've never been on Arrakis.
It's quite impressive, you'll see.
Was this all upon your advice?
What?
Did you counsel my father
to exterminate the Atreides?
Of course I did.
Why else would it have happened?
You tried to sacrifice an entire bloodline.
And I was right to do it.
The Kuisatzhaderak is a form of
power that our world has not yet seen.
The ultimate power.
The ninety generations we
have supervised have Atreides.
They were promising, but they
were becoming dangerously defiant.
Their bloodline had to be terminated.
That is why we have put
many bloodlines at work.
Several prospects.
But it's backfired.
Paul is alive.
And if he defeats
Vader Arthur, my father...
Your father will lose the
throne, no matter who prevails.
But there is one way your
family can remain in power.
And through you, the
continuation of our stewardship.
One way are you prepared?
He's been preparing me my
whole life for every mother.
You heading north with
the others? I'm for Dyken.
I follow my leaders.
If fighting goes north, I go north.
Paul didn't have a choice, child.
I won't be fighting for him.
I'm fighting for my people.
I came to wish you best of luck.
I wish you the same.
But it seems you've won your battle.
You took the bait.
The river is very obliging.
It's right on time.
We're changing it more deep.
I've sealed my colleague.
It's production under control.
What do we do?
Send messages to the great houses.
Tell them that our
arachis is on a sonic attack.
Tell them the future hangs to the balance.
Tell them that our
arachis is on a sonic attack.
When the storm hits this ridge,
Gurney will open the way for you still are.
So you can enter the basin from the west
and distract their defense systems.
Johnny, I want you and your
Phidike into that attack from the east.
Inside the basin,
I'll strike from the north, head on,
with the fundamentalist troops.
And I'll serve her a king for dessert.
Remember, I need the Emperor alive.
I don't wish he has something.
No, no.
You have any idea who this party could be?
Something that is your majesty.
That's all we know.
More, more.
Give me more.
He's a madman.
Mad?
Or a familiar man.
That's all you know.
Really?
No, Dave is dead.
Or he went hiding in the southern storms.
This means the same thing.
Your majesty,
the sandstorm that's approaching
threatens the integrity of our shields.
We recommend going back into orbit.
The mountains will
protect us from most of it.
Your majesty.
Baron, have you ever investigated
the south regions of Aragas?
While the entire region is uninhabitable,
it's well known, your majesty.
Your uninhabited south
exhibits evidence of human activity.
I wasn't aware of this.
I swear to you, I wasn't aware of it.
Baron, Dave is alive.
I must find him.
He's alive.
It's more than a day away.
I'm here.
Let's go.
I'm not going to touch you,
this is the end of it.
We have to keep going.
Amadri! Amadri! Amadri! Amadri!
.
And my friends.
I will love you as long as I breath.
You're facing a full invasion, Franklin.
How can you be so sure the
great houses are here for me?
They may be curious to hear my
side of the story, don't you think?
I am Paul Atreides, son of
Leto Atreides, Duke of Arrakis.
Gurney, my lord.
Send a warning to all ships.
If the great houses attack, our
atomics will obliterate all spice fields.
You're out of your mind.
He's bluffing.
Consider what you're
about to do, Paul Atreides.
What am I?
This upset, my lord.
As a servant of the Imperium,
you would know it might beat.
Your fate!
You'll be lucky to keep your head.
I'll take the hand of your daughter.
She will remain safe, and we
will rule together over the Empire.
But you, you have to answer for my father.
I killed him, because he was a
man that allowed us not meant to rule.
In other words, your father was a weak man.
Stand, or choose your champion.
I am here, Atreides.
I need a blade, except mine.
Do not stain your hands on the sand.
Why does he take such risks?
What deep lids?
You wouldn't be the
first Rajiv I've killed.
May thy knife chip and shatter.
I'll take the hand of your daughter.
She's your pet?
Any special attention for the pet?
I'll take the hand of your daughter.
You thought well, Atreides.
Listen, I gave you!
You should have believed.
You chose the wrong side.
Side? You all people should know.
There are no sides.
Reverend Mother.
My lord, the great houses have answered.
They refuse to honor your ascendancy.
We have waited your orders.
Lead them to paradise.
Hold on! Hold on!
Listen to me!
Now we all begin.