History proves that as a solution
to every scariest problem...
A lethal person arises.
I can't narrate a tale about that person.
Because I heard about
him in a series of stories.
[upbeat music]
A cotton cloth from Delhi serves as the
starting point for this series of stories.
It is a rare cotton.
Only grown in India.
It's lovely.
But I'm sure you are not from India.
Yes.
This cotton is very famous in Europe.
But in India, no one knows about it.
What?
It's true Madam.
This cotton is from our Talakona forest.
Thriving exclusively in
specific climatic conditions...
This is a rare and
exquisite cotton variety...
Even though nature supports the growth
of that cotton, the government doesn't.
However, a person arrived and
undertook the cultivation of cotton,
Eventually exporting it abroad.
[upbeat music]
[ship honks]
But he's not around;
I don't know what happened to him.
After hearing that, as a journalist...
I aim to support both the cotton crop and
the man responsible for its cultivation.
It's a rare wild cotton plant which grows
in Talakona region in Andhra Pradesh.
It has huge demand but provides less
income for those who cultivate it.
The man who motivated the
tribes to cultivate them...
has been missing for one year
under suspicious circumstances.
Who reads such articles these days?
- You said today's World Cotton Day.
- Yes, sir.
Accommodate it in some
fillers on the last page.
That neglected article alerted
the intelligence bureaus.
[suspenseful music]
[bomb blast]
Made the PMO take cognizance,
[telephone ringing]
and stopped the printing
of a national newspaper,
causing the CBI to visit the office
and interrogate them for 16 hours.
Check all the mails and phones.
No one leaves the premises.
Come on guys, hurry up.
She is Nalini.
Take her to the editor's office.
[suspenseful music]
I want your employees' list.
Sure, sir. We'll submit the documents.
But bringing up an investigation like this
will bring a very bad repute to our paper.
Please understand, sir.
We are on it, sir. We will be doing the...
You...
Do you have any idea what you
have researched and written about?
Sir, it was just an article about cotton.
It was not just an article,
it was a national secret.
Such secrets can potentially
topple the government.
In 70 years, the publication of our
newspaper has stopped for the first time.
The PMO has had to
take cognizance of this.
All because of your damn article and you!
Now, just get out of this office. Get out!
You have got nothing to do here.
Who gave you this information?
No one did. A cotton cloth inspired me.
What did you see in it?
I got to know about the factory then.
Explain this article.
After hours of investigation, they told
me that I had nothing to do with it.
But what they don't know is,
they have entwined me with this issue now.
I will pull everything out.
Now this is my story.
[upbeat music]
They were not scared of
the cotton or the place.
But the person who cultivated the crops.
I need to learn about this person who
has sent chills down so many spines.
[upbeat music]
How to get to the Cotton
textile factory on the hill?
There is no factory up
there anymore. Take right anyway.
[suspenseful music]
[eagle squeaking]
[upbeat music]
Grandpa, who is he?
What is this ash?
What happened here one year ago?
That was a rare eclipse.
The moment, similar to the
beginning of the Kurukshetra war.
No prayers saved lives that day.
Throats couldn't screech
and legs couldn't run.
The green hill turned red.
Many lives were
sacrificed to the fire deity.
The star burnt bright that day.
[helicopter whirring]
The God of death had awakened that day.
Lord Shiva, the God of death...
had awakened!
[eagle squeaking]
[gun shot]
POLICE STATION
TALAKONA
Sir, I need to meet the CI.
[indistinct chatter]
He is free, you can meet him.
Thank you.
Stop arguing with me or else I'll get your
theatre shut for showing obscene films.
Sir...
I'll call you back, bye.
You look like a courageous woman,
I don't think it's an eve-teasing case.
This isn't a city where your
sentiments would get hurt,
What happened, madam?
Did someone steal your purse?
No, sir. You know about
the hill there, don't you?
Can you tell me about the
person who lived there?
What happened there a year ago?
It's not a small matter
that you can take notes on.
I can't praise him for what he has
done nor can I ever forget that.
He is not a human!
He is a natural calamity!
I can't tell you anything more.
Please leave from here. Go.
- Sir...
- Thank you.
You don't look like giving up on it,
do you?
There are a lot of influential
names associated with this.
The MLA was helpless. An MLA!
You are very pretty.
Listen to me, go back home.
Hello, guys. Enjoy cooling party.
In the background,
you see Talakona Police Station.
Here all police officers
drink the famous cardamom tea.
Live visuals from Elapenta.
Over a strong flame,
Tea leaves and cardamom
powder are mixed in milk...
And then he continuously stirs everything.
Brother,
I have to go to the MLA's residence.
- Will I get any taxi here?
- Ladies?
Famous Luna Suresh fans!
Subscribe to Luna Suresh. Bye!
He's working and I'm up for it.
You want a taxi? Here is the taxi.
Is this a taxi?
Here, these are the taxis. Cheap rates.
Are you a journalist?
From Delhi.
Oh, Delhi ladies.
You got a water tanker
but didn't get water, is it?
You can fetch some when it rains.
Get lost.
What is it, Luna?
Brother, she is from Delhi.
She has come here to interview the MLA.
Are you really from Delhi?
Slowly bring it down and slowly raise up.
Almost...
Now move this little finger.
Very nice! Good progress.
Treatment...
He is responding well to the treatment.
It's done, sir. Your treatment is done.
I feel so relieved, doctor.
Who is she?
Sir, she has come to take
your interview on our victory.
She's from Delhi.
From Delhi?
- Sit down.
- Please, sit down.
Congratulations on your victory, sir.
This village looks very beautiful.
But I have a doubt about
one particular locality.
Which one?
That hill...
[groaning in shock]
His BP is high!
- Relax! Relax!
- Check him!
Don't panic. Don't panic.
Press this. Press this.
Hey Vikas.
- Didn't you tell her not to mention hill?
- No, Doctor.
Don't you think before you ask?
How can you talk anything
before a people's leader?
Cacophony! Destruction!
Danger board...
[blasting]
Take her away. Take her away.
I'll take her away.
Come with me. You wait. Carry on. Slowly.
The tension is back. The tension is back.
Calm down. Calm down.
She's gone. She's gone.
Luna, start the vehicle.
Get her on the Tirupati bus,
Let her take any flight from there.
- You won't get any interviews. Leave.
- Why, Bro?
Look, my hands are shivering.
Start the vehicle.
Leave from here.
I made a mistake taking you in.
Leave, please.
You won't get any information here.
I'm not leaving from here.
I will dig out this scam completely.
Which scam?
You have a number tattooed on you.
It must be a special number.
It's not a special number.
It's my birthday...
Look,
I'm quite sure it must be a locker code.
P stands for Punjab National Bank.
Hey, it's CFO is my friend by the way.
One call and all your Benami
assets will be public.
Your MLA will get you killed.
Got it.
Why here?
This is not a public announcement!
Safer with the buffaloes.
It was dawn.
East-side Hills.
It's the title...
Listen.
[tribal music]
There was a peaceful farmhouse on a
10-acre green land on top of the hill.
Beside that was a cotton textile factory
A gentleman who provided
employment for two tribes there.
The place had fresh air,
impeccable people, and top-quality cotton.
The tribal people considered him as God...
Stop your narration and tell me about him.
The point is, not even an ant was allowed
into the premises without his permission.
Not even an ant?
Let me tell you the introduction.
The way you have held the bow,
you'd miss the target.
You have to take the wind into
account and then aim the arrow.
Development personified!
We have yet another opportunity to
elect our beloved leader of Madanapalle.
Let's vote for our beloved leader
Chillar Someshwar Reddy's symbol 'mic'.
[crowd]: Hail,
Someshwar Reddy's leadership!
Hail!
Brother, should I throw the pamphlet in?
[sloganeering continues]
Wait and see, the sound will bombard and
the pamphlets will be inside the gate.
It's time for you to have
a demo of perfect aim!
Steady wind.
The target is in the North.
Definite shot!
[groaning in pain]
The weapon-wielding hands must find a
reason and the aim will not miss the mark.
Some need a tender touch
and some need a strong blow.
[upbeat music]
He has hit an arrow to my bottom,
condemn him...
Hey!
You didn't hit the arrow to his bottom;
it hit my ego.
First the Parishad elections, then the MLC
elections and now the Assembly elections.
Not once has our pamphlet gone in.
Is this a temple where even a
piece of paper is prohibited?
It is just a cloth loom.
Hand-loom garments are crafted
with hands, hearts involved.
It is a cloth woven
out of a farmer's soul.
Indian cotton is beautiful.
The place where that is
cultivated is definitely a temple.
You won't understand it.
The elections will come again
but I should not see you here.
Go!
Hey, Sahadev...
I'm holding myself back just because
you have 300 votes under your control.
Otherwise, I would have seen your end.
Jai, I like this line.
Tell me this when I ask
you to crack me a joke.
Go.
Interesting...
Is that what you got from it?
It was a warning as it was just
a pamphlet, had it been a man...
Can't imagine!
Is it?
Yes.
Who entered then?
The continuation of that story
happened at MLA's residence.
During my childhood, people were so loyal
that they would take money and vote twice.
The inflation is nominal but the
greed has risen exponentially.
Damn! Humans have become very cruel.
How will we get so much money though?
- Sir...
- Yes.
Businessman Rajesh Rumani
has come to meet you.
Who is that chap?
How did he become an MLA!?
This guy, sir.
Oh my...
He is equivalent to the Ambanis.
Yes.
Why did he come to me?
He wants to speak to you personally.
I had to come down, Someswar Reddy.
[suspenseful music]
It is called bauxite.
A rare mineral.
This hill lies in your constituency.
There's a farmhouse on its peak and
two tribes residing at its base.
This information can be
found on Google Maps.
But our research says that the hill
contains a Bauxite reserve beneath it.
If you can vacate them and give me the
hill, I'll give you three billion rupees.
100 million is your token amount.
Sir, there is another piece of information
beyond Google Maps and his research.
A man lives there and both the
tribes honour his words to death.
But he won't bow down to us, sir.
I am tired of killing
people for my projects.
I thought it would be a better deal to
give three billion than taking 300 lives.
- Sir, you are not getting it.
- Shut up!
Don't give me silly excuses when
there's so much money involved.
I will make them vacate.
Thus our MLA got entangled in this.
The problem started from that day.
Okay, I got my answers.
It's all about bauxite.
Hello, madam... Listen!
Thank you for your ride.
No mention.
Delhi lady, subscribe to Luna Suresh.
Sure.
Do you know where you are and about
whom you are running an enquiry on?
The slang is not quite there.
This is not your Delhi, shall we go?
Don't panic.
I'm from the Government, public friendly.
I'm here to put sense
into your head. Come.
Talakona's sweet honey is the
favourite dish of Lord of Kanipakam.
[upbeat music]
Last entry, 17th July 1997.
Ranger, signing in.
Are you from the CID?
Looks like you watch a lot of web series.
Shouldn't you be watching
some international ones too?
- RAW?
- Yes, we exist.
Why do you have a safe
house in Madanapalle?
We apprehended a sleeper cell
behind the Kakinada military hotel
and a criminal near the Sircilla petrol
bunk, with the help of such safe-houses.
So, now you apprehended me.
To stop me from publishing about Bauxite
and revealing the names of your bosses.
If it was about Bauxite,
it would have been a national treasure.
But not a national secret.
The person you are inquiring
about is bigger than the Bauxite.
Do you know who resided there?
World's most wanted assassin.
Eagle.
Eagle?
Ma'am...
Recently my daughter has started drinking
this beverage along with her Yoga routine.
She calls it some kind of coolant.
If a coder like her drinks it,
then decoders like us should
definitely try it, shouldn't we?
Ma'am, you appointed me in
Europe as permanent undercover.
And as asked, I have built a network
with all the mafia out there.
Now, all of a sudden you
called me back to India.
Any reasons, ma'am?
Any red flags? Am I exposed?
Sit down.
Sit!
There was an incident at the Goa port.
[ship honking]
The customs officers are
habituated to letting things pass through.
This time they let a
container pass through.
That container travelled to a
godown situated 75 km from there.
Later, an arms dealer was killed there.
[gun shots]
As per the information that we
received from our department,
It was loaded with
hundreds of illegal guns.
Not only that...
Three weeks ago the same arms dealer
was supposed to supply a consignment...
to Naxals in Chhattisgarh
which was captured by someone.
Gustavo black arrow,
the favourite bullet of snipers.
Considering the wind
speed at the location,
There is only one man who could have
taken this shot from as far as 800 meters.
Eagle!
[shots fired]
Ma'am, I heard this name
when I joined as a rookie.
But I think he's been inactive
for the last 10 years.
But he's been active here
since the last 10 years.
The magnitude of the armoury
gone missing is such that...
A whole district can wield a gun each.
He's a ruthless assassin.
But what is he building now?
But ma'am, how can I help in this case?
You have built an underground
network in Europe, right?
Find out why he went inactive from there.
Understood, ma'am.
[upbeat music]
Last time, I made a profit of a
million pounds because of your tip.
One favour. Tell me what you want.
Brother, shall I kill him?
Hey, put the gun down. Guns inside!
Why are you overreacting?
I just asked about Eagle, that's it!
Shut up and get in the car.
[suspenseful music]
Open the basement.
Close the windows and turn off the lights
Fix my drink.
How dare you ask about
Eagle in an open square!
We all would have lost our
lives because of your stupidity.
His bullet pierces to every nook
and corner where light can reach.
The trees in a dense forest
communicate through their roots...
Such is his network.
His forest... All of this is his forest.
So? Will he hunt us?
15 years ago, a powerful drug lord,
four layers of security around him,
the whole house was bulletproof,
yet got himself killed.
[gun shot]
He shot the bullet in between the
gap of the blades of an exhaust fan
rotating at a speed of 12
rounds per second to shoot him.
Once he agrees to the assignment,
no matter who the target is,
He will surely get his coffin ready.
He's out of your range.
My range is to get Mexico's most wanted
Kingpin, Bob Pascal, killed in Europe.
His father, Pedro Pascal.
Let's talk about him.
He arrived with a sizable group
at a gas station near the forest.
[upbeat music]
Bring me his eyes.
I'll give 10 million for each one.
Go in there...
find him.
[eagle squeaking]
The wind speaks to him,
he is extremely sensitive to any change
in wind speed and temperature variance.
[suspenseful music]
[speaking in foreign language]
Getting apprehended, being killed,
everything is an illusion.
Everything is a trap.
Obviously, he won't be in that cabin.
He'd be nonchalantly puffing his
cigarette nearby and planning his attack.
[upbeat music]
He's a predator that attacks in stealth.
[music]
[beeping]
[shot fired]
[shots fired]
He's a ruthless devil who
walks amidst the dead bodies.
He's the Eagle you are asking for,
2092.15 meters.
[upbeat music]
[shot fired]
Did you show him hell?
You are already in it.
How would they approach him?
No phones. No meetings.
He won't meet anyone.
If you want to meet him,
you have to give an Ad in the
newspaper saying 'wanted painter',
The Ad contains the location coordinates.
He will call you with his military
embedded phone before coming.
That too only if he wants to.
We gathered all the newspapers
containing the Ads of wanted painters.
Ma'am, he communicates through
the ads in the newspaper.
He publishes an Ad saying
'Wanted painter'.
Can you see the phone number there?
That's not a phone number,
Those are the coordinates of an area,
latitude, longitude, and place.
His men would come to that
place to collect guns.
If we follow them,
we can get to Eagle's lair.
We waited to find the next
'wanted painter' Ad.
Finally, our wait came to an end.
Sir, painter Ad.
It's published in the Coorg newspaper.
As expected, while the weapons were
being exchanged at the given location,
Eagle's man killed the arms dealer
and loaded the weapons into the truck.
We followed the container to
a farmhouse in Madanapalle.
Which means,
Eagle was at that place for sure.
[upbeat music]
That means, Sahadev was Eagle.
The relevance of whether Eagle and Sahadev
are the same person is now obsolete
Because Eagle is dead now.
I'm warning you from writing anything
about Bauxite or the scam behind it.
[sighing]
Sister,
here's the milk and curd you asked for.
Put that in the refrigerator and
give the address of Amma Devi bar.
Bar?
[peppy music]
Brother, I'll take it.
Chilly chicken.
You followed me here too?
Can't I damage my liver at peace?
I told everything I knew,
don't ask me anything else.
Yesterday, I was taken away by RAW agents.
Did you give away my name?
What could happen to you,
if I give your voice recordings to them?
But you are not giving me any details,
what should I do?
Stop your acting.
I will tell you. Not here though.
[music playing]
Nice place, now let's talk.
With all the technological advancements,
I have stopped trusting humans.
Swear on your mother,
only then will I continue.
Here we'll have the party symbol
and here the polling date, sir.
Hey AP,
the mic is okay but where are the rings?
I will add them, sir.
He's not a farmer,
this is not the right deal. Listen to me.
Let coins shower in the background.
Okay.
[gun shot]
[shots fired]
What the hell is going on?
[gun shot]
All OK, sir.
What happened outside was my
way of introducing myself.
If you still don't understand what I'm
about to say, be ready to be annihilated.
I'm a farmer who cultivates cotton,
my name is Sahadeva Varma.
I focused my attention on
you for just 10 minutes,
And your foundations have a crack in them.
I can predict the market just by the news,
I know that you are not a farmer.
Who are you?
I consume poison,
wander the world, take lives,
and also a protector!
I'm destruction, also I am the
catastrophe that stops all destruction.
[upbeat music]
I will leave the Bauxite alone.
His transactions can be traced to Turkey,
Japan and Germany,
he is not an ordinary man.
Do not meddle with that Bauxite reserve.
Sir, breakfast for party workers and
some additional money for their travel...
Okay sir.
- Add another 3000 rupees...
- Please grant me the money.
Pay from your pocket,
you can reimburse it later.
Hey, Penchula...
Uncle?
He was scared as soon
as he got the warning.
Now that he is out of the way,
we can dig out the entire 3000
crores instead of just 300 crores.
Sir... no, sir.
That's a remote controlled gate.
He won't open it for us.
Hey, PA... be in your limits.
Even High Command listens to me,
who is he!?
Only those summoned by the
Lord may witness his presence.
Hey, what are you staring at me? Call him.
The MLA has come, open the gates.
- Okay.
- Hey!
Where is everyone?
What do you think of yourself?
Shut up.
Clad in a Ponduru Khadi Kurta,
adorned with Dubai fragrance,
I clinched victory as an MLA with a
resounding majority of 12,000 votes.
Despite my triumph, I am denied entry,
while a half-nude man was granted access.
What does he think of himself?
Sir, if you keep blabbering here,
the gates will get closed again.
Sir, let's go in fast.
If the gates close, both your Khadi
and fragrance will be a waste.
Come. Come fast, sir.
Come quickly, sir.
[communicating in whistles]
Uncle, sit here.
This stool is bigger than his.
Sahadev, your name echoed in my compound.
Since you belong to my constituency,
I came down to your
place to speak with you.
The matter is,
I want to flatten this hill.
Don't worry, I won't grab it.
It values less than six million
for an acre but I'll pay you ten.
I'll give dish TV to the tribal people.
What was that...?
OTT.
Yeah. OTT, I'll give that too.
Amazon, Aha, and all the channels,
they can watch everything.
You have seen a lot of life;
I believe you need not
be told anything else.
Someshwar Reddy,
[heavy metal thud]
The land feeds us people.
Selling it would leave
everyone facing hunger.
You can't digest Bauxite.
Leave it.
Do you already know about it?
I know everything,
that's why I'm advising you.
Don't get the lava down from the hill.
It will decimate both the
village and your existence.
[upbeat music]
Sahadev, I might look like a puffer
fish but I'm actually a whale.
Think it through.
What unfolded thereafter was...
[Theater bell ringing]
You stop speaking to even
the tiniest of sounds.
Shall we go to the cemeteries?
There won't be anyone there.
If I keep telling you
everything you ask for,
We will eventually land up there for sure.
I won't talk.
Don't ask me anything more, madam.
Look at my limbs shivering.
Vikas...
Did you tell her?
Did you tell her everything?
Why are you cornering me?
You gave her the idea to meet the MLA,
didn't you?
Now you are blaming me?
- She is now thinking of meeting Rumani.
- Rumani?
So, did you also tell
about Naxalite Padmakka...
- now working as a government teacher?
- Shut up.
- I didn't tell her.
- Padmakka...
You told her about MLA and she came here,
if you tell her about Padmakka and Naxals,
will she keep quiet?
She will trace them too.
Did she hear us?
You have also given this information...
Hey, where is Padma teacher?
In that room, madam.
There?
- [kids reciting lessons]
- Thank you
I can predict the danger
just by a whisper.
Who are you?
Reading the Bhagavad Gita only
requires knowledge of the language.
But understanding it requires
dedicated exploration of its meaning.
The story's meaning varies based
on the intellect of the reader.
Since you are a journalist who
empathizes with our ideals,
I would tell you the story that I know.
It requires wind to turn
a spark into a wildfire.
Similarly, to keep our ideals alive and
continue our rebellion we need weapons.
We have lost our armor consignment
to someone three times now.
Our supplies are almost empty.
We have to get him at any cost.
Padma...
you should go to Ghaziabad and meet Altaf.
He has stopped many of our Jihad
attacks while being in stealth.
A total of 12 consignments.
That means,
he has stolen 10000 weapons from us.
We need to catch that Kafir at any cost.
I came for the consignment promised to us.
Your war is different from ours.
But we both have the same enemy.
[upbeat music]
I have attached a tracker to the
consignment that I'm delivering this time,
you have to track him down and catch him.
They kept a GPS tracker in the
consignment to trap the Eagle.
As usual, Eagle's men killed the dealer's
men and took over the consignment.
[shot fired]
The tracker got me to
the house atop that hill.
I found a way to get
into the house somehow.
Sir, this is much more than
what the middlemen offer us.
The crop and the cultivator
both should survive.
This is the last harvest
of the season, right?
Organize a Chandi Carnival.
Okay, sir.
Sir, remember I told you about Padma?
She is the one.
She lives in the forest.
Give her some work, sir.
Look at the scars on her
hands and boots on her legs,
she doesn't seem fit for household chores.
The Carnival is near,
you would require personnel,
give her some work there.
[suspenseful music]
I got inside the house.
The tracker would always point
towards the cotton factory
but I never found guns in it.
The one who writes
"all are equal" changes 10 people
but the one who treats everyone
equally changes a thousand people.
I saw one such man there.
I couldn't figure out whether
to suspect him or not.
Stop.
You are talking about weapons.
Someone talking about Bauxite.
Someone else talks about Eagle,
the assassin.
How can one man have so many stories?
How can he have so many
different versions?
Didn't I tell you, the story
depends on the reader's maturity?
You won't understand the
story that I tell you.
When you get the maturity, you will
find meaning in every word that I said.
Stop probing all of them, sister.
The night the destruction happened on the
hill, Venkanna and Penchula were present.
Let's go to Venkanna
and ask him on his face.
If he denies it, let us ask Penchula.
Where is your grandpa?
He has gone to the shop.
Buddy, I want a secret information.
Did you ever see the man
residing on the hill?
He is my friend.
He used to play PubG with me.
Yes!
But he never won.
Beating him in PubG is impossible.
- Buddy...
- Yes.
One Sunday, I was standing beside
a coconut tree as I was thirsty.
I heard a huge noise.
[gun shot]
There was a coconut fallen beside me.
The next Sunday,
[gun shot]
I saw the scarecrow's
head blown into pieces.
[gun shot]
Since then, every Sunday, it was routine.
I would watch the scarecrow,
the head would get shot down.
- What are you talking about, buddy?
- Yes, buddy.
- Was there someone else living there?
- Govind...
So far, the people you have
met have told you only events.
Story is not a bunch of events,
it is the motivation behind those events.
I'll find the motivation and be back.
What happened to your legs in that fair?
When I see you, I remember the chaos
brought upon by that gentleman.
Go sit at the northeast corner,
I'll feel better.
Hey, Luna. Since you are heavy,
go and sit at the southeast corner.
Jealous!
What are you talking about?
Vastu.
I've spent thousands of
rupees to learn this.
You don't have to ask me anything.
I'll tell you what I know
and what I've witnessed.
I learned Vastu that day...
and witnessed an Action movie.
[upbeat music]
Instead getting him killed in the fair,
why are we here to meet the Vellore Gang?
They have sent us this location.
What's so special about them that
we should come looking for them?
No cop in the surrounding districts has
the guts to catch hold of that gang. Come.
Kadhir, don't wash it.
Blood is auspicious for us.
Hey, what is this public violence?
There's a police station nearby.
The one lying dead is
the CI of that station.
Impressive! Impressive!
This is how the murder should be.
This is how it should be.
Tonight's Carnival will be the
last celebration for that farmer.
"Warrior has become furious
The bear has jumped ahead"
"Bulls followed one after
another The weapon is now found"
"All the screams and satires have
gone quiet in one blow, watch it"
"All the thunders have played the
beats tightening their fists, beat it"
"Come on,
call even our Lord for the dance"
"Come on dance dude, dance with life"
"Cross over the train style and whistle"
"Come on watch dude, see the sensation"
"The warrior mixing up wine,
sweet and the mass beat"
"Ferociousness is his best quality
He's dashing ahead for the war"
"He is like the vast sky
His fight is worth watching"
"His movement is worth praising"
"Ferociousness is his best quality
He's dashing ahead for the war"
"He is like the vast sky,
His fight is worth watching"
Assemble all three defence heads,
also inform the PMO.
I'm on my way to the war room.
"He's the courage of weapon"
"He will wipe out atrocities"
"He will fire up the torches"
"He's the light at the edge of heat"
Hey, pace up the beat
"Come on dance dude, dance with life"
"Cross over the train style and whistle"
"Come on watch dude, see the sensation"
"The warrior mixing up wine,
sweet and the mass beat"
What is the status, Mr. Achyuthan?
Did the agent send the location?
I'm following the truck, agent.
Hey, wake him up.
Venkanna...
The MLA is here.
Hey, Venkanna. I have a ritual to attend,
make me a nice tea.
The hunt is on, PA!
Ma'am, the truck we are
following entered a farmhouse.
75th interception, accomplished.
I think the wolves have
followed the truck, have they?
Yes.
How many?
25 to hunt down and one for the bait.
[upbeat music]
Hey! Sahadev...
Didn't you say even a pamphlet
won't enter your premises,
I have come in with a whole gang.
8 directions, and there are three
people per direction, Sahadev!
He is talking about directions,
let's teach him Vastu. Lift the curtains.
Straight, west. 9'o'clock.
Pull.
[gun shot]
Southwest. 7'o clock. Inhale, half-hold.
Shoot.
[gun shot]
North-east, 2'o clock. Straight clean.
Pull.
[gun shot]
6'o clock, South. Crosshair on target.
Pull.
[gun shot]
Who is bursting crackers, Vikas?
Not exciting enough, we need some spice.
(Energetic music)
Bon Voyage.
[gun shot]
Hey, Penchula.
You said he's just a farmer.
He is pulling a Hollywood
Action Film on us!
Hey, what is this?
He is not a fabric that you
have wound him into a coil.
This is cheating.
How can swords compete against guns?
Jai...
What are you waiting for?
We have received the weapons.
Take them and gun him down.
Pick up the weapons. You are done!
Pick it up! Pick it!
Shoot. Shoot him.
Pull. Pull the trigger.
That's not cracker's sound,
those are gunshots.
But didn't we give them only swords?
Whatever.
They must have planned something
special for their beloved leader.
[shots fired]
Jai...
There should not be any damage caused to
the truck and the armoury in the truck.
Everything should go to the Godown.
Let me fix the situation here.
[upbeat music]
It was then that I understood why the
tracker would point towards that factory.
I had no idea about
the basement till then.
Padma,
ready for the show?
It's your foolishness to think that tying
me down will stop the incoming assault.
You have to face our whole gang.
Padma, your assumption is very small
compared to what is about to unfold here.
Everything that enters
this gate belongs to me.
Be it the weapons or be it your lives.
Leave me and I'll be your slave.
Spare me and I'll run away.
You came in just because you were
confident walking out, isn't it?
[machine gun firing]
10 items, 25 dead bodies, one ego...
and the truck which got all these here,
should be out of my premises
within the next two minutes.
Hey, Penchula...
Mr. Penchula... Mr. Penchula...
What happened?
Run away, Uncle. Run away.
Run away? Why?
Why is he running like that?
Looking at the set-up,
I think we would require two snipers.
Two snipers are not enough.
We are talking about the Eagle.
I have sent the whole force.
Landing at the Renigunta air base.
Team Tango, on your trucks.
[Helicopter whirring]
Thank you, ma'am.
Now you listen to me.
You have the entire National
Combat Force behind you.
Burn him down.
Sir, blood...
Sir...
Hey, go check that out.
Go.
Okay.
[gasps in shock]
Why has everyone put
vermilion on their foreheads?
Hey, Vikas!
That's not vermilion, that's bullet
wound. He has killed all of them!
If we stay here anymore,
he will kill us too. Come fast. Come...
Hey, start the vehicle.
Let's go... He will kill all of us.
Come...
Sir, come fast.
Start the vehicle.
Fast. Take me out of here.
Start the vehicle. Fast.
Let's go. Let's go.
Sir...
What?
There!
[upbeat music]
Even the King of a region is a piece
of meat when he is in the forest.
You will be staying here
for the next 24 hours,
you'll be witnessing a
light never seen before,
a sound never heard before,
and the pace of heartbeat
never experienced before.
If you disregard my order and move, I'll
give you a death no God can save you from.
[upbeat music]
If you find a danger sign, that means
it's dangerous to enter the premises.
If you still enter despite
knowing about the dangers,
You won't meet the man,
instead you will witness an explosion.
[upbeat music]
As soon as I mentioned
Sahadev Varma from Talakona,
Your PA connected me to you
on the spur of the moment.
Astonishing!
I know what happened in your locker room.
If you want me to not write about that,
Then I want something
more interesting than that.
Some wild animals make peculiar sounds
to announce their claim over a territory.
If you don't understand that,
you'll be attacked.
He gave me an opportunity
to escape one such attack.
He asked me to get an inmate, who had been
in prison for the last 10 years, released.
He was, Kali Pratap, the bitter past of
Sahadev who could potentially stop him.
A big influence wants you out.
I believe you are reformed.
I hope you won't kill anyone hereafter.
No. I'm going to kill him.
You measure time in dollars,
how can I help you in any way?
Sometimes even with an enormous amount
of money to balance the equation,
you cannot stop the light chasing you.
In other words,
you cannot stop the bullet from his gun.
I'm doing what I have been told to.
[suspenseful music]
This is the only tip I can give you.
I should not get any
call from you from now.
Go and ask the MLA what
happened after that.
- Hey, kiddo...
- Hmm...
Was the MLA present there the
whole time after being warned?
Even though the mosquitoes were biting
him, he still didn't leave his ground.
He was there the next morning as well,
brushing his teeth.
Take this. You might want to get lighter.
There, behind the bushes.
Hey...
Why should we oblige to his ultimatum?
What else then?
Shall we leave and
never disturb him again?
Let's ask for forgiveness and leave.
Ready, steady, call for him.
Mr. Sahadev, he is asking for forgiveness.
Louder!
The MLA is asking for forgiveness.
Did he hear or not?
He didn't say no, that means a yes.
Let's go.
[gun shot]
Sir, is this response enough?
Sir, I can't imagine you in place
of that poster. Come, sit here.
Come on!
Okay, Kiddo.
You may leave, I got what I want.
Are you asking me to leave?
The actual story happened later that day.
What happened?
If I have to sum up the entire event,
he played PubG in real life.
Three groups came that day.
The first group was the pro group,
they were camping around the place.
[suspenseful music]
Are you the captain here?
Yeah.
What is with this tent and set-up?
We are supposed to be camouflaged.
Don't you think it is already
too much for one person?
We are 30 in number. We'll finish the
job before you can finish your coffee.
You are supposed to listen to us.
Hello, we don't take orders from you.
Ma'am...
This team is very aggressive.
We have civilians outside his house,
I'll be the first soldier.
Let me go in and confirm the subject.
Go ahead. Chief.
Team Alpha, hold.
Roger that, sir.
If he is inside,
I'll press this and communicate with you.
What if you get killed before that?
I'll still find a way, But if I do fail,
then talk to my Ma'am.
Alright.
[suspenseful music]
- Why is the idly so bad?
- This is what we get here.
Hey, where are you going?
That gate is remotely controlled
It won't open to everyone.
Who are you?
I never saw you in the village.
I came to survey the Airfone network.
What?
I have come to survey the Airfone network.
No matter who you are,
nobody is allowed in. Sit here.
He won't...
[gate opening]
The gate has opened sir
What is this, sir?
The gate did not open for us
- Hey, Venkanna...
- Sir...
Maybe your boss just hates
public representatives.
Apart from me,
everyone is allowed to enter.
Sir, I have come for the
installation of fibre cable.
Without this,
your call quality will decrease, sir.
Jai, this is nice. Remember this
and tell me I ask you for a joke.
Trust me,
this is of superior quality, sir.
You could enter because we let you in,
now you will go out if and
when we want you to go out.
That won't work here, Pramod.
Impressive!
So what I've heard about
you is absolutely right.
This might not work here,
but if I don't exit before one hour,
the whole force will barge in.
Things won't change even if you kill me.
He seems very curious,
arrange the live telecast for him.
Okay.
Ma'am, your ranger has not come out yet.
Allow us inside,
we'll sweep and finish it.
My agent will communicate with you, wait!
We have seen many people like you.
All those people have
lost their lives to him.
Police or Special Force?
AirFone technician.
Is it?
Then who are those people holding guns in
those tents outside? Your co-technicians?
[upbeat music]
I see movement at 10 o'clock.
50 armed men.
Ma'am, we have company.
Now let me tell you about
group 2 and group 3.
One is the Naxal group and the
other is the Terrorist group.
They came together.
Altaf,
Inside the premises, there might be
innocent people along with our comrade.
You cannot shoot blindly.
We are not here to conduct a shootout.
We are doing Jihad to catch that Kafir.
If your comrade dies in this,
that would not be a death but a sacrifice.
No! Don't move in.
[suspenseful music]
Hey, Vikas.
Where is the guy who went inside?
Did he get shot too? What is it?
Sir, look over there once.
Who are these bearded men?
They don't like our voters.
- They are Pakistani voters.
- Pa...
They are terrorists for God's sake!
What is happening here? Does he
have enemies all over the country?
You said, your Naxal group will come.
But they look like terrorists.
We had to join hands with
them for these weapons.
In another 10 minutes, his secured
fort will be decimated to the ground.
Naxals are here too.
Why are the Naxals here?
How many people are eyeing the Bauxite?
Do you think this is Rumani's
set-up to deal with him?
[upbeat music]
Rajanna, the MLA is here.
Our aim is that Dacoit.
Jai...
[Siren wailing]
What is this?
Siren?
[Siren wailing]
Hey, Govind. Time to shut the shop.
Wind direction, North East. Speed,
20 knots. Head...
We are not aiming for any direction today,
it will shower from everywhere
What is happening here, Venkanna?
That is not just sound, it's a warning.
If you want to be alive, lie down.
No. He asked us to stay back for 24 hours,
we will stay,
but we are following any other
instructions beyond that.
Vikas, what are you doing?
He is the senior here.
And, I want to live.
You too come here.
The terrorist jumped the fence
and entered the premises.
Before they could enter Pochinki,
they all died.
[gun shots]
After witnessing that,
I realized that it's not Pochinki,
there was a huge mission gun in action.
Now let me explain it to you in detail.
[machine gun fire]
What's happening here?
It's a warning. Now, lie down.
[upbeat music]
There was a gun on the window,
door, even on walls...
the terrorists were destroyed in seconds.
Remove those tents and get camouflaged.
Instantly,
the pro team got themselves camouflaged.
Copy that.
[upbeat music]
What is happening here?
Who knows... just sleep.
We closed the gate. We even gave a
warning sound. They didn't listen.
When death's calling you,
you don't listen to anything else.
This is nice,
let's talk about this in the evening.
Ma'am, it is confirmed.
Eagle is inside. 20 casualties.
Had I listened to you,
our men would have been in their place.
Wait until sunset and plan your tactics.
But Ma'am, we are prepared.
You are on his ground and he
is prepared for a decade now.
To beat a crocodile in the water,
you need brains, not brawn.
Copy that.
Thus that chapter finished.
He had spoken about the
murder a long long back.
[mobile phone ringing]
Tell me, Chengal Reddy.
Vikas, what happened to that
murder MLA was talking about?
This is not the right
time to discuss this.
Why should we spare them?
Ask him to come and see this movie...
I heard it. It seems you are
having fun. I'm on my way.
Thus,
CI Chengal Reddy started from the station.
[mobile ringing]
Thank you.
We got the land documents. Let's go.
If we find out who owns
the farmhouse land,
We'll understand the
reason for this story.
I hope all our doubts
get clarified with this.
In the story that I'm looking for, the
depth and the reason that you asked for...
Is that girl.
Her name is Rachana.
The proof is these land documents.
How is she related to him? Where is she?
[suspenseful music]
She is not a part of the story,
she is the cause of this story.
She is the reason why our
livelihood is still alive.
He came here 10 years
ago with her memories,
he accomplished all
that she had envisioned.
I'm just his attendant.
The only person that can
answer your questions is Jai.
He is responsible for spreading our cotton
imports from Europe to the entire World
[upbeat music]
Excuse me, sir.
Yeah. Yes miss.
Do you know this address?
Address? I'm not sure of it.
- This person is from India. Jai.
- I've not come across him.
His name is Jai. He imports cotton.
You should check in corner.
Hey... Hey, stop.
Hey...
Nalini, suspended Journalist.
We started to stalk you the
moment you spoke to Mallanna.
We thought you would reach
up to MLA or even Rumani.
But now that you have come so far,
I guess I understand
what you are looking for.
What is the relationship
between Rachana and Sahadev?
Why did Sahadev come to
Talakona for Rachana?
If your value has to be recognised,
you must come into light.
If you think your story is valuable,
tell me the truth.
Some sights are so powerful that
they have the power to take lives.
The lives of such people start from here.
Wind speed under 1, eye on target.
According to our contract, we had to
kill a police officer named Kali Pratap.
Wind direction, 36.2 degrees.
Hold the shot.
Target is moving.
His life consisted only of deaths but
suddenly a lively woman entered his life.
I repeat, hold the shot.
Target is starting to move.
Wind speed is the same.
The window is closing.
I repeat, take the shot.
The window is closed.
Brother...
For the first time, Sahadev lifted
his finger from the trigger,
and couldn't take his eyes off of
the girl, her sarees and her world.
Brother...
From that moment,
he started following her.
Time afforded them the
opportunity to meet on that day.
Money... Money...
Give me your phone.
Money...
More!
Your chain, faster.
Bag.
- Give me.
- No...
Do you want to die?
Please...
Perhaps the fact that she valued
cotton sarees more than her life...
That act got Sahadev to like her more.
Make it fast.
[gun shot]
[pleasant music]
Her name is Rachana.
She is from Madanapalle.
She works as a teacher
in a daycare centre.
Both her parents went bankrupt in
their cotton business back in India.
But yet she is very
passionate about cotton.
She is so passionate that she is importing
Indian cotton to design dresses here
In order to gain international
recognition for Indian cotton.
But no one would understand that,
she won't get any recognition.
And the first prize goes
to Tosha from Austria.
[applause]
[gun shot]
Okay.
She was a queen indeed,
no matter how the world saw her.
With that bullet, he conveyed that to her.
This is the rainbow that brought
together the sky and the joy.
He always viewed people
from a bird's eye view.
She brought him down into people.
[romantic music]
This small girl became a
bridge in their love story.
Hey, Romeo. I know that you are
trying to impress my teacher.
Don't you have any homework? Go on, scoot.
Tell her.
I am tired of watching her being single.
If you try sincerely,
I'll help you with your love.
Do we have a deal?
Deal?
[upbeat music]
Do you know,
my teacher got rejected today?
Indian sarees don't fit our fashion.
We are forward thinkers.
Who would encourage sarees
in this age and era?
She didn't have breakfast today.
Do something.
Romeo, go and make your presence felt.
[gun shot]
Yay!
Video blog -01.
I thought you were a saviour.
But never knew you
were safeguarding me too.
"It's lost. My heart is
lost. Just a while ago,"
"It succumbed to the gaze of your eyes."
"It's lost. My heart is
lost. Just a while ago,"
"It succumbed to the gaze of your eyes."
"Struggling and restless echoes persist."
"He, a silent shadow, a magic untold"
"Refuses to depart,
lingers like an unspoken vow."
"You, the earth's flower,
"I, a cloud yearning;"
"Dare I descend from the heavens,"
This doesn't seem to be a love story,
it looks more like an 'I spy' game.
"Baby you're my love, baby you're
my heart, baby you're my dream"
Stop showing tantrums...
Hey, leave me.
- Not you, I decide the price.
- Don't touch me. Get lost!
- Get away from me.
- Okay.
How dare you to do this from me.
[gun shot]
He would watch the beautiful spectacle
but be apprehensive of approaching it...
because he would fear that if he nears
the spectacle, it will be dilapidated.
Blog -12.
What is with you?
Why would you not meet me?
You have been disturbing me in my
dreams as well, but without a face.
Do you know that?
This dummy gun is enough for love.
I am having a headache with all the sirens
that go off each time you fire this.
Please go ahead with it.
"Is it blessings whispering scripture,"
"or the melody bestowing auspiciousness"
"upon the union of bride and groom?"
"Is it a ritual that
illuminates joined steps,"
"or a life that entwines
two hearts apart?'
"It's lost. My heart is
lost. Just a while ago,"
"It succumbed to the gaze of your eyes."
Who is he?
Tomorrow is the finale
of her fashion show.
What she lacks and what
she needs is confidence.
I have gifted her that.
[upbeat music]
You are not wearing a cloth,
you're wearing a culture.
You have to understand it to embrace it.
[upbeat music]
His love story is on snooze.
We have to do something to fix it.
Yes!
I have an idea.
What is it?
Cable car.
Why have we come to the cable car, Suhana?
Wait, ma'am.
Hey, Suhana
Ma'am, ma'am... He comes to our
school every day and stalks you.
I've caught him a couple of times.
Hey, Romeo.
Ma'am, he is the one.
He is the mysterious gunman
who is trying to impress you.
You are done!
Hey, Suhana... Suhana...
Where are you going?
They didn't require any words
to take their story forward.
Their silence was a sigh of approval,
and their eyes locking with each
other symbolized their marriage.
"A celebration resounds where
Earth embraces the sky,"
"where silence harmonizes with voice."
"You are a bond enduring a hundred
years upon this sacred land"
"I'm the music that might leave anytime"
I never expected such a sensitive
love story for such a ruthless killer.
Didn't he ever reveal to
her his real profession?
By the way, what is your profession?
I provide secret services to
police in their operations.
Why are you so hesitant about it?
Because I work in the shadows.
There is no nobler job than a job
done to help without being seen.
[mobile ringing]
If you are found speaking to a criminal
who escaped Indian jurisdiction,
you'll find yourself
in international jail.
Even my recommendation
letter won't save you then.
Are you here?
I'm making this call from a
phone I found at the crime scene.
Return immediately.
By the way,
why did you leave Pramod alive?
If you want to find that out,
Then you have to know about the
annihilation caused by the demon that day.
[upbeat music]
It was a chilly night in the winters...
No one can narrate this
chapter like I can.
I'll tell you everything in detail.
Listen to it.
The pro team started flying
out drones to look out.
They even identified the MLA lying
down outside using their drones.
Ma'am,
we have the local MLA among the civilians.
Brainless fellow.
There is another one also coming, ma'am
Even the CI Chengal Reddy
came to that area on his bike.
One more brainless fellow.
Sir, what is this mass
killing that I'm seeing?
How can you be at peace
after killing so many people?
That's how he understood it?
What about him? He must have gotten
scared and hid inside, didn't he?
He is done for.
Listen, this is CI Chengal Reddy.
I will count till 5 and everyone inside
the building should surrender themselves.
5...
What is that sound pollution?
He is Chengal Reddy,
like an ad that appears before a movie.
3...
Let's greet him.
2...
1...
He won't understand until he
sees the demo for himself.
[gun shot]
He showed him.
After the demo,
Chengal Reddy joined the MLA and gang.
After that, there was full
reverse attack from the pro squad.
They started shooting left and right.
[gun shots]
Our hero too started
firing left and right.
[gun shots]
Duck and its ducklings.
What do you mean?
He has designed a mother gun which
would trigger all the baby guns.
To give you an analogy,
it is like all the tires turn
when the steering is operated.
Our hero was very considerate...
And purposefully shot on the legs of
the pro team in order to not kill them.
Meanwhile we were praying to the Gods.
What is happening in my area
without my knowledge, sir?
What do you know about anything?
There has been a Godzilla residing
here since the last ten years.
You are busy watching comedy
or entertainment videos always.
Did you ever bother to check
what's happening in your area?
We are witnessing a
live surgic oil strike...
- It's surgical strike.
- Stop correcting me.
[suspenseful music]
It's been five hours;
what have you been up to during this time?
He should have been there on the hilltop.
Can't you use your cop skills
and pull us out of here?
Are you out of your mind, Someshwar Reddy?
Even the military is unable to do anything
there, what can a police officer do?
- How dare you call me by my name!
- Hey!
We are in a cemetery not a meeting.
Do you still care about
respect in the face of death?
[gun shots]
The pro team smartly tried to
trick the hero with a smoke bomb.
There was smoke all around.
They marched ahead while the
hero was blinded by the smoke.
Meanwhile,
there was a huge noise and heavy wind.
- I looked up to see what was happening.
- Sir, sir, Helicopter
The helicopter has come
to airlift me I guess.
Why would they airlift us, idiot?
It came to airlift the
Godzilla who is inside
The pro team started shooting the
guns protruding from that house.
There will be a delay of one second in
the firing of main and secondary guns.
Do you see anything?
If you observe that,
we can hit the main gun.
Meanwhile, a sniper spotted our hero.
I got him on my sight.
Take the shot.
[gun shot]
Every great love story
has an unexpected ending.
He didn't know that he was seeing
her for the last time in his life.
The accidents that we see in the news
happened to us that day in real life.
[gun shots]
A shootout by terrorists broke out in
the daycare centre where Rachana worked.
[ambulance sirens]
Suhana!
Out of the eighteen
children who died that day,
one was Suhana.
Suhana!
Along with them...
Rachana! Rachana!
Sahadev!
Rachana!
I want to tell you something.
No.. no.. no...
Don't talk... Don't talk...
This is not the right time to talk.
Had you been here,
everyone here would have been alive today.
There will be life wherever you are.
You should never change, make sure
that no one witnesses such a fate.
[ambulance siren wailing]
Who did this?
I want their details in 24 hours.
The war that comes to us when we are least
prepared are the ones planned by destiny.
Karma came back to us in the form of a
contract that we undertook 6 months ago.
- What's the contract?
- Illegal guns are being traded.
We must interrupt the ones who
are trying to intervene the deal.
Police! Police!
We should have shot him that day itself.
He is Suhana's father.
Why shoot him? Let's stop him.
[gun shots]
Back then we didn't know what we had done.
The ones whom we helped
to secure the guns...
They were the same terrorists
who ruined our lives.
If guns fall into the wrong hands,
that becomes an irreversible mistake!
That incident showed me a man in
him that I had never seen before.
From that moment he was
not the Sahadev I knew.
Do you know when would the
bullet from the gun stops?
When the bullet hits
the wielder of the gun.
Blog 18.
Today I'm going to speak
about what I think about you.
You filled hope in people
with the sound of bullets.
You made the gun a sign of protection.
If so many people are
having a peaceful sleep,
that's because a saviour stands in
front of them wielding a weapon.
I'm very proud that
that one person is mine!
The one who creates destruction
with weapons is Evil.
The one who stops that
destruction with weapons is...
God.
Even God is omnipresent, just like you.
What you are doing is nothing short
of being a God. You are equal to God.
She loved me without even knowing me.
She saw a saviour in me.
Her belief should not be let down.
Should not!
To do that, every weapon that an
unworthy person is wielding...
Has to be destroyed.
As long as Rachana was alive,
his life was a lie.
But after her death,
his life found a purpose.
That made him a warrior.
I'll do all I can,
to honour her dying wish.
I'll become what she wished me to be,
I'll not let such tragedy happen again.
My aim used to take lives,
now it should save lives.
Every weapon-wielding hand must possess
the responsibility to support the needy.
The one who does not possess that
responsibility should not touch a weapon.
Responsible shouldn't leave the weapon.
An irresponsible
shouldn't hold the weapon.
For that oath he had taken to
destroy the illegal arms...
You should know how many
people he stopped that night.
[gun shots]
The special forces broke down the gate.
The gate is down.
Godzilla is dead I guess.
We have got Eagle.
[applause]
Down! Down!
But before them,
the terrorists marched upon the weapons.
The Kaafir is down.
We should enter the building
before the special forces.
We must take control of all the weapons.
The Special Forces halted to
analyse the counterattack.
Ma'am, the rogue batch is barging in.
But they were unaware that
Sahadev would defeat death before
accepting defeat from his enemy.
[upbeat music]
[gun shots]
Bird, clear shot. Take him down.
Do you have him on your sight?
Shoot!
[machine gun firing]
Jai!
Sacrifice.
"The explosion is disastrous
and knows no limits."
"Dissent is expansive,
it often flows out."
This is a sacred war.
We can't win it.
"Shining hot like the sun
and reaching targets always"
Fall back!
"He is like the eagle
who causes disasters"
Abort!
Tango to Charlie... Tango to Charlie...
Bird is losing control. Do you copy?
"The explosion is disastrous
and knows no limits."
"Dissent is expansive,
it often flows out."
Abort!
[upbeat music]
I've seen many wars.
For the first time, I'm witnessing
stubbornness against defeat.
He is the boundary.
He is the guard.
It is impossible for anyone
to trespass on his premises...
or take weapons out of the
premises without his permission.
Ma'am...
Won't won't leave his ground.
He is not going to give up.
If we move in, We lose our troops.
Ma'am, we have only one option.
Air strike!
We know he's a criminal.
And we know that he is in there.
What are you waiting for?
Launch the missile.
[suspenseful music]
10 years, 56 operations, more than a
hundred thousand weapons stolen,
you are an assassin who finds a place
in the wanted list of 16 countries.
What do you know about illegal
arms that you are doing all this?
You can't change your record by
altering your location and attire.
I didn't leave that place,
I left that world.
There are more than a million weapons
being manufactured every year.
Country defence purchases only half of it,
the other half gets sold
on the black market.
There are more than a billion
illegal guns in this world.
There are 8 billion people in this world
and there are 8.5 billion guns on sale.
That means, more than one gun for a life.
Killing is quite cheap
but protecting is costly.
If there's no wall stopping this,
no voice condemning this,
there will be a day when people will
buy guns like they buy mobile phones.
Wars will take more
lives than any pandemic.
This must be stopped or I shall stop it.
Misplacement of a weapon
is the first step towards chaos.
The guns which entered trains,
roads, hotels, temples and schools,
Will soon enter houses.
This nation shouldn't become another
America which has more guns than people.
When a child leaves the town
for their higher studies,
they should get a call from their
parents enquiring about their well-being
but their parents shouldn't receive a
call from that their child is no more.
When a death happens in a family,
two people die.
One leaves this world and the
other yearns to leave for eternity.
Death should not have a
reason but have meaning.
Gun should mean responsibility
and a bullet, a beacon of hope.
For that to happen, the weapons should not
fall into the hands of unworthy people.
Period.
Do you know how it feels to lose a
loved one to an irrational reason?
You can't even imagine it.
The one who causes destruction
with weapons is a demon.
The one who ceases all
destruction with weapons is God.
But this God is not noble,
he is very stubborn.
[upbeat music]
Only I will decide who get these
weapons and where should they go...
If someone else tries to do otherwise,
the same chilly night of
the winter will repeat.
Sahadev... Pratap!
[gun shots]
You have killed 12 people,
misusing your power.
You are dismissed,
ordering asylum for you.
[upbeat music]
Let him in.
Within 10 years,
you grew from being a contract killer
to a Kingpin who controls the
grey markets of the world.
You got India's powerful
billionaire to get me out.
Don't live in a fallacy
that I will forgive you,
because it's not a
memory that you gave me.
It was a scar.
I stand in front of you.
Get me.
You should not die to a bullet.
You separated a father and his daughter,
You ruined many lives and
still continue to wreak havoc.
I will turn back your 10 years of life,
send back all the weapons
to their original place,
and bury down your ambitions right here.
12 intelligence bureaus,
16 governments couldn't stop me,
How do you think you can do that?
I've never backed out of any
contract that I undertake.
This contract is my wife's dream,
it's a lifetime contract.
Let the entire country come and
stand against me, I'll still stop them.
Come.
So far, you lived for vengeance but
now onwards you should live for love.
The loving father within you should
hopefully look forward to each day.
I have nothing to look forward to...
When I hit a shot, it's business.
When I miss a shot, it's purpose.
Since the last 10 years,
a life has been waiting for you.
[suspenseful music]
Sahadev took a decision that no one
could take to correct his mistake.
That decision brings your book to an end.
Only one can explain that decision to you.
[suspenseful music]
Who is that slice of life that has
been waiting for you for 10 years?
Please complete the story.
Who is that slice of life that has
been waiting for me for 10 years?
Pause your game and get to the point.
I will... why the rush?
Let the school bell ring
[school-bell ringing]
[suspenseful music]
Daddy!
What are you waiting for?
Will you just stand here?
What took you so long?
Her name is Bhoomi. Sahadev's favour.
Your daughter.
Right from addressing her to raising
her... She remembers only you.
Bhoomi is the price he paid to
you for the damage caused by him.
A father like you who treats his
daughter as his world, is his guarantee.
God sends a cyclone to uproot a tree.
The same God sends rains
helping it to sprout back again.
Before Rachana died,
She presented Sahadev their
symbol of love... their daughter.
The girl has had a happy life so far,
but she treats you as her father.
You were always with her. The form and
memory she knows of her father is yours.
He distanced himself as a
father and gave you a daughter.
I started this for my daughter.
But when I found out that he
sacrificed his daughter for me,
all my vengeance and anger got belittled.
Everything vanished that second.
I saw my daughter once again.
[emotional music]
When I went there,
there was nothing but ash on the hill.
How did he die that night?
Jai, we don't have time.
Activate all the explosives. Untie them.
[suspenseful music]
Not just win or lose,
even his death was under his decision.
Everybody, out.
He communicated to them that no
missile was necessary to stop him.
He made the decision to
destroy his place by himself.
He activated the detonator powerful
enough to impact a 100 metre radius.
[upbeat music]
War base prime station.
Tejas 23 abort.
He has detonated himself. Abort.
[upbeat music]
I, who understood him clearly,
could not believe that he was dead.
Is this the fate for someone so stubborn?
We didn't find any remains of his
body in that dilapidated farmhouse.
He planned a decade-long mission,
won't he plan his exit too?
I didn't believe in it either,
just like you don't.
On the next day after the blast,
I went out in search of Eagle and his men.
Only then I understood.
- Ma'am.
- He is not a single man.
12 men are shot dead in Denmark.
Even the armory has gone missing.
This bullet was found there.
Operation Denmark...
Halfway done.
I ended many Eagles.
I run Denmark. I decide lives.
Eagle is a system.
And a system has an army.
[Helicopter whirring]
That army has not just a chief,
but it is dictated by a dictator.
[upbeat music]
Now you are in the
shadows of that Dictator.
[upbeat music]
Illegal weapons cannot pass that dictator.
He altered the definition of the weapon.
A weapon isn't about taking lives;
it's a tool for leading
people onto the right path.
He became a beacon of
hope to the handloom workers.
He made the governments
rethink their strategies.
Natural disasters are nature's way of
balancing things out on this planet,
He is one such disaster!
The man is everywhere.
[helicopter blades whirring]
Can I meet him?
He is invisible yet omnipresent.
He must be watching us from a distance.
Rather than being hidden in files...
This story needs to be known by
the children of this generation.
They are the heroes who are
going to handle future dangers.
The future heroes should be
aware of the present heroes.
Sahadev...
If you try to stop a disaster,
you shall be its first victim.
This is the war you called for.
Get ready.
I'm coming.
The war has begun.
What you know is just the
middle part of the story,
but what happened at the start of
this story is pure catastrophe.
And the end of this story
will witness obliteration!
Mom, I like this superhero story.
He came like a shadow and took
away all the weapons with him.
Did you read about him?
Yes, I did.
But, Mom... Why did he choose India?
He didn't choose India,
he started his mission from India.
These are the weapons
targeted to reach the militants.
He trusted us to be sincere
and handed them over to us.
From where was the shot taken?
850m.
It sounds unbelievable, right?
No, it fits very well
with the tales I've heard.
Stop your elevations and tell
me about the consignment.
But why, Sir?
Even if we chased him,
we wouldn't find him.
When we think he is in our grasp,
he will vaporize like clouds;
If you watch from afar he will
spread all over like rain.
Because of him, the mafia and
rowdy-sheeters are finding no weapons
which has drastically
reduced the crime rate.
When he is doing our job,
why should we stop him, sir?
I say, you should have these
peanuts and just chill.
Your theory sounds right to me.