[MUSIC]
[LAUGH]
That's right, it is
I, I love you, Carrie.
I have returned to take what is mine,
which is everything that is yours.
If you know that the highest mountain to
the lowest valley, the Thai long lives,
and no one will stand in his way, but
even the great dragon warrior.
[MUSIC]
Oh, where is Paul?
He was supposed to be here hours ago.
Hey, will you please just relax?
I am relaxed.
Okay, I'm sure Paul is fine.
What if he's sick?
What if he's hurt?
What if he's hungry?
Don't get your noodles in a twist.
I know our son, he's probably just
kicking back and catching some rays.
[MUSIC]
[NOISE]
That's bad.
Getting worse.
[NOISE]
[MUSIC]
Okay, big guy, we're really
gonna have to wrap this up.
[MUSIC]
And next time, keep
your surf off their turf.
[NOISE]
I'm late.
[MUSIC]
What is it always will be?
We love you, Dragon Warrior.
And I love you too, adoring fans.
So much more.
Okay, okay, I'll do whatever you want.
[MUSIC]
Master Sifu, here, let me
just, there, that's much worse.
We have to talk.
Absolutely, let's talk.
Right after the ceremony,
ceremony, what ceremony?
For the staff of wisdom given to me by
Master Oogway himself,
it is said that whoever possesses this
staff has the power to
travel between the realms,
the power to unlock the
door to the spirit realm.
And now, the power to open the all new
Dragon Warrior noodles and tofu.
[NOISE]
We're the brass-ass bitch.
The women's feet hurt
the knoth development.
[NOISE]
Dragon Warrior, will the
curious five be hurt too?
Unfortunately no, they're off on super
cool kung fu missions.
Tigris is taking on the free-range
chicken with that monkey's hawk on the
trail with the missing the cact.
Crane was crowned
king of the crocodilians.
Long story.
Viper is wrapping up his talks between
the cobras and the mongooses.
Or is it mongeez?
And man says, well, he's just trying to
keep his blushing right
from biting his head off.
Just because they're not here in person
doesn't mean they're not
here as a lifestyle cut out.
Now who wants a picture?
I'll tell you okay, one at a time.
Uh, you.
My turn, my turn!
And then you.
You really captured
your disapproving scandal.
We need to talk to...
Now.
Hey, can I get one of
those in a wallet size?
Who?
Coming!
Do you remember the first time you
finally stepped into a J-Force?
How could I forget?
I thought I'd never make it to the top.
Yes, but you persevered, and once again,
Destiny calls for you to take the next
step on your journey.
The next step?
What are you talking about? I've already
taken all this stuff.
Haven't I?
It is time for you to
choose your successor.
Successor for what?
A successor to be the
next Dragon Warrior.
Oh, yeah, I get it.
Funny, because I'm the Dragon Warrior.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, wait, wait.
You mean I'm not going to be
the Dragon Warrior anymore?
Exactly.
Then what am I going to be?
Once a successor is chosen, you will
advance to the highest
level in all of Kung Fu.
Spiritual leader of the Valley of Peace.
Whoa!
I don't know what that means.
It's just like Master Uglie before you.
You will oversee the Valley, passing
along wisdom and aspiring hope.
Look, I appreciate the promotion.
I think it was just going to stick with
the whole Dragon Warrior thing.
Dragon Warrior thing?
What is it you're hoping?
Our cooking?
Other hand.
The Staff of Wisdom?
It was given to you by Master Uglie.
You couldn't really think it was so you
could open a
restaurant for both textures.
You wasn't super specific?
Uglie entrusted you with that staff.
So you could follow in his footsteps and
become something
better than you already are.
You take it.
No.
Uglie did not give it to me.
Paving the next Uglie is not my destiny,
which I have accepted
and am at peace with.
Really, it's fine.
You don't sound fine.
I'm very fine.
It's okay to be your prize.
This is an honor.
Uglie chose you as his successor and now
you must choose yours.
Master Shifu, I finally found something
I'm good at and now you want
to just take it away from me?
No one was taking anything away, Po.
Who you are will always be
a part of what you become.
Yeah, but where's this caduce?
You know what I mean?
The shh of worry!
I don't want to seem ungrateful, but I
don't know anything about passing on
wisdom or inspiring hope.
All I know are two things.
Kicking butt and taking names.
And if I'm being completely honest, I'm
not even that good at the name taking.
Like, who's that
fire-breathing crocodile?
I want to say Steve?
You were chosen to
bring peace to the valley.
And there are other ways to bring peace
than simply kicking butt.
Well, sure, but not any fun ones.
Please!
Being the Dragon Warrior is all I know.
It's who I am!
Not anymore.
The Valley of Peace needs a spiritual
leader and Master Uglie chose you.
You'll start interviewing candidates
first thing tomorrow morning.
Candidates? What candidates?
Awesome!
Got you.
Fantastic pose.
Woo hoo!
Nice!
Master Poe will now
choose the next Dragon Warrior.
So many great candidates.
I'm gonna let the finger decide.
Wait.
Whoa, whoa.
What is happening?
The Dragon Warrior!
It's me!
If I could have not told you,
I'd have to choose a successor.
Nothing about them
says Dragon or Warrior.
You will know what you know.
How do I know when I know?
You know?
When I'm conflicted, I come here to ask
the universe for answers,
just as Uglie did before me.
I'm not conflicted, I'm
just not ready for a next step.
What is that you're holding?
The Staff of Wisdom?
Otherhand.
A Chewed-Up Peace Bed?
Exactly.
Every pit holds the
promise of a mighty tree.
How is this gonna help me find answers?
Don't ask me.
Ask the universe.
Be the pit, Poe.
Be the pit?
Yeah, there we go.
Alright, universe.
Give me some guidance.
Inner peace.
Dinner, please.
Dinner with peas.
Snow peas.
And a sesame soy glaze.
Argh!
Inner peace.
This is not working at all.
Maybe focus on your breathing.
I'm trying, but it's kinda
hard when you keep talking to me.
Technically, you're talking
to you if you think about it.
Will you two be quiet?
I'm trying to concentrate here.
Wait, if my Poe's inner
voice, then who are you?
Uh, I'm Poe's inner voice.
How many voices do I have in there?
You do not want to know.
I just love you.
What am I gonna be?
Are we alone in universe?
Did I talk about something?
I'm not gonna be.
You are gonna be.
Universe?
Is that you?
Attention mysterious fandier.
The dragon warriors
here took her for justice.
I know you're in here just a matter of
time before I find you.
Ooh.
You can't hide from justice forever.
The dagger of Dengua.
You've got excellent
taste. I'll give you that.
But I can't give you that. Give it back.
If you insist.
Oh no! He's got a walking stick.
What are you gonna
do, stroll me to death?
This stick is not for the strolling.
It's the staff of wisdom.
The dragon warrior is gonna be mad when
he finds out you took his stick.
I am the dragon warrior.
I'm just gonna say nothing
about you says dragon or warrior.
Yes!
You desecrate the holo-gira.
Who's desecrating what now?
That's your ostrich you say.
No, it's not bad.
You destructible chain
hammer of faster fangirls.
Whoopsies.
[gasping]
[laughing]
Beat the hand of whispering warriors,
which I've already broken. Twice!
Why would you keep an urn of souls?
Feels kind of creepy.
Are you doing okay there, big guy?
You're looking a little tired.
I've never felt more.
The warrior of faster chubac?
You're gonna pay for that.
[gasping]
Hello?
[grunting]
You faker!
It's not faking. It's called method.
Catch you later, panda.
No!
[grunting]
I think I'll catch you now.
Whoa!
[grunting]
I'm not a guy!
Whoa!
Told ya!
You got me. Oh, great, a
powerful dumpling warrior.
That's dragon warrior!
Let go of me!
Just tell me one thing. How could someone
like you become the dragon warrior?
That's a mystery for you to solve during
your two years day at
the Valley of Peace Prison.
Valley of Peace Prison?
Sounds like a daycare.
It is a daycare on the
weekends, but it's also a prison.
There it is!
Dragon warrior!
My oldest, my long-nest returned.
He demanded all of our items, then
destroyed our quarry!
He's supposed to be the spirit world.
Well, he's fastened, and he's not going
to stop until the Valley of Peace falls,
and the dragon warrior bows before him.
He's fastened!
Please, you've got to do something!
Looks like I'm not the only one around
here with a mystery to solve.
Well, you know what they say.
Every step leaves a
footprint, no matter how small.
Every step leaves a footprint, no matter how small.
Very clever, Fox. You know something.
Maybe I do. Maybe I don't.
Okay, I do. I really, really do.
Tell me.
And why should I? I don't
know what's in it for me.
The peace of mind knowing
you did the right thing.
You're adorable. I
don't ever tell you that.
And I don't even just
look at my cuddly side.
I don't have time for games.
Tylon is running loose
in the Valley of Peace.
Maybe, or maybe she wants
you to think it was Tylon.
Wait. She?
Mine.
The Empress of the Sky is capable of
taking any form, mimicking anything.
The Master of Deception.
The lizard of lies with
the glowing teal eyes.
Stop talking about the chameleon.
This is kind of a private conversation.
Who's the chameleon?
Only the most powerful
shape-shifting sorceress.
So she's shape-shifted in the Tylon!
But what does she have
against me in the Valley of Peace?
These are good questions.
You should ask her.
You're right.
How do I find this the chameleon?
She isn't someone who can be found.
At least not without someone in the know.
And how do I find someone in the know?
No. It's me. It's
obviously, it's me. I'm in the know.
I mean, I'm in the know.
I'll find her on my own.
Good luck. After all, how hard can it be
to find someone who can look
like anyone blended anywhere?
Fine. You lead me to the chameleon and
I'll see what I can do
about reducing your sentence.
Deal.
What do you think you're doing?
There's this
shape-shifting sorceress on the loose.
That's a job for the Furious Five.
Well, they're not here and someone needs
to protect the Valley of Peace.
Look, I know the change is difficult and
that you enjoy being the Dragon Warrior,
but your job is finding a successor.
The Dragon Warrior and I have a deal. My
drone business, squirrel.
Mr. Shifu is not a squirrel.
I'm a red panda.
You know what? I love that for you.
Poe, this is your decision, but I think
you know the choice Master
Oakley would want you to make.
Thanks for the freeze day.
What do you mean?
Not bad for a daycare.
Wait, not bad for a daycare.
There she goes.
Okay, please. Don't worry. I'll have her
back before you even know she was gone.
You were supposed to be passing along
with her and inspiring all.
Just think of it. It's one last Dragon
Warrior adventure. I'll be back soon.
Tell my dads I love them. I
can't hear you anymore. Bye!
Yeah! It sure is good
to be a free fox again.
That's a yay, backscratcher.
Yay!
So does this really unlock
the door to the spirit realm?
It doesn't work like that.
It has to be given in
order to gain its powers.
Gotcha. Given to gain. So, can I have a--
No! What do you take me for?
An easy mark.
What's an easy mark?
Someone who's easy to steal from. Usually
because they're generous
and too trusting. Like you.
Ah, thank you.
I heard the chameleon is a monster with
an appetite of a thousand predators and
her favorite food is panda.
And I say this chameleon, Erica has
magical powers. If you say her name three
times, she'll take you away in the night.
This new one?
How should she look like anything?
It is you for you.
Mr. Lee, Mr. Lee, is it true?
I was going to take
down an evil sorcerer?
Don't know chameleon.
Dragon Warrior's work is never done.
I'm thinking Paul using up with the
commitment fella to take down an evil
sorceress. Who wasn't such a great idea?
Relax. Poe has faced demons, demigods,
and everything else in between. He's
always coming on top.
And you're right. You're right.
I thought if you're wrong--
Calm down, Ping. How bad
can one evil sorceress be?
Who is she to summon us?
Classic power move. We're the heads of
Jina for Citi's most
prominent crying family.
Is she just a bug-eyed, power-hungry
reptilian who runs--
You left out the evil sorceress part.
We used to run the city. Now we pay her
half the money for the twiddle.
It's like a primo can't
make an honest living anymore.
Yeah, but what can we do?
Together, we can take her down.
Oh, no.
But not if she's a shape-shifter.
She could be at this very
table, and we'd have no idea.
For all we know, you're the chameleon.
Or you're the chameleon.
Or maybe--
Oh, no.
Maybe.
Don't say it.
I'm the chameleon.
I said don't say it.
We obviously spoke out of turn.
Sorry, chameleon.
No, no, don't apologize.
You and your families prospered by
preying upon the weak.
So it doesn't feel good when
you're the one being squeezed,
especially when the one doing the
squeezing is just a
bug-eyed, power-hungry.
How was the rest?
Reptilian Runt.
Well, this reptilian runt wants more.
You already have the city. What else
could you possibly want?
I have something special in mind.
I am very close to achieving it.
As close as the blood moon.
The blood moon is two nights away.
So little times, so many expenses,
which is why I'll need to increase this
month's tribute to 60%.
No.
What was that now?
I mean, no disrespect.
Don't worry.
I forgive you.
For the impudence, and the backstabbing,
and the blatant
disrespect you've shown me.
I forgive.
But I never forget.
You might say I have the memory.
Oh, don't say it.
Of an elephant.
You think I pushed you too far?
Then you, my friend, can't begin to fail.
Just how far I can pull.
I'd expect your tributes by dawn.
Are we gonna stop for lunch soon?
Justice doesn't stop for lunch.
But it does take the
occasional time out for snackage.
Wanna split my almond cookie?
You're just gonna give me half of your
cookie out of the goodness of your heart?
Mm-hmm.
What's the catch? The rum, the bamboozle?
The bam-waddle?
You know, the fleece,
the rump, the flint-wam.
Do you want the cookie or not?
[mumbling]
I got my eye on you.
How much farther is it
to this, the chameleon?
Just a little.
[screaming]
Please! What are you throwing out here in
the middle of the night?
I... I didn't want a
mis-scurbing blood moon rising.
Oh, cool.
You are just as worried as I am.
Right, alright.
I know Panda's come across as calm,
gentle and chill, but...
The truth is, I'm kind of freaking out!
Who am I? Who is it too calm, gentle and
chill to face a sheepshifting sorceress?
What if he's captured?
What if he's tortured?
Our baby!
Okay, okay.
Maybe Po has finally met his match, but
there's still something that he has that
the comedian does not.
What's that?
Us!
Now, let's go find our son, my proposal.
You know, Nate, a wise goose, once said,
"Worrying doesn't make
the broth boil any faster."
Who was that?
Me, of course. I was the wise goose.
Oh, yeah.
Whoa!
That's the biggest
village I've ever seen.
That's no village. That's Cunever City.
That's where I'll
find the chameleon, huh?
Just a boat ride away, and I'm gonna lead
you right to our front door.
Are you sure we'll find
a boat captain in there?
For the right price. Those cup throws
will take us anywhere we want to go.
Of course, we could always opt for the
four-finger discount.
No stealing. The Happy Bunny Tavern.
That sounds inviting.
No!
Anybody lose a rabbit?
Oh, that's a giant bastard!
Welcome to the Happy Bunny Tavern.
I'll find us a ride, maybe you can get us
some food, and stay out of trouble.
Hey, what you guys playing?
Ah, John, at the stage, sir, hi.
Can I play?
Surely you'll go easy on a beginner,
because I'm near your beginning.
Hey there, what can I get you?
A boat ride to Cunever City.
Oh, this guy.
Who's he? He's the captain.
Thanks.
Oh, I want to get him.
Beginner's luck, I guess.
Emma, play me four.
Are you accusing me of cheating?
I would like to speak
to the manager, please.
I am the manager.
I'll give you a boat ride to Cunever
City, but I won't carry anything illegal.
I don't want any trouble.
Trouble runs for me.
Then he'll cost you double. I'm confused.
Should I have said that I like trouble?
In that case, he'll cost you triple.
Maybe we can go back to double price?
You got a deal. Great.
Do I shake his hand or your hand?
Can I give anything else to me now?
Yes, everything. Again, except for the
rock. It was very bland.
He's starting!
Whoa! One of
everything is my go-to order.
But how did you pay for this?
Freebilly, lawfully, fair and square.
I'm proud of you.
Oh, wow. Look at the time. Remember we
had to do that thing?
Now I'm out of place with that guy.
Did you actually think you
could drift a meal out of me?
There's got to be some sort of
misunderstanding here.
And apparently I'm the
one misunderstanding.
Please allow us to pay
for our meal and yours.
Because I am only hungry far.
Don't think spend it.
Well then, come and get it.
No, no, no, no! Don't come and get it!
Destroy them!
Yeah!
Ahh! I got it!
There you go.
Oh, Banner.
Gotcha.
You need to start it.
Ahh!
I'll take that.
I think it belongs to you.
Go, Steely!
Yeah, I think it's a
little too late for that.
It's never too late
to do the right thing.
No. Get them!
Yeah!
Whoa, nice move.
You gotta teach me that.
Yeah, guys!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Whoa!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Ahh!
Hello.
Who designed the timer on a glass?
We shouldn't have
eaten all those duck wings.
Ahh!
Huh?
Hell, ho!
Ahh!
Not that I'm worried, but...
What if the chameleon knows we're coming?
Well, she could be anywhere.
Anyone.
Lee, would you please
show a little backbone?
I'm sorry.
The bravery was never really my special.
Ahh!
You don't have to be brave.
You just have to act brave.
Act brave.
Got it!
Ahh!
Oh, baby!
Oh, this is nothing!
No!
I'm too real!
Ahh!
How was that for acty brave?
Keep prepping on it.
Juniper City, it's going to
be great to be back home again.
Does your family live there too?
They would.
If I had a family, it wasn't easy being a
little fox in a big city.
So I had to survive any way I could.
I'm being...chilling...gaffing...
Stop running!
Whoa, you're an orphan? So am I!
Well, I mean, I was.
My goose dad adopted me, and then later
my panda dad found me.
Goose dads! Panda dads!
Guess it takes all kinds. Right, mom?
Then, one day a local took me in, put a
roof over my head, gave me
clothes to wear, food to eat.
After that, I was never alone again.
I guess we both got lucky.
I guess.
Hey, tell me something.
Back in the Valley of Geese, what did
that angry little squirrel mean?
Red Panda.
When he said you had
to find your successor.
Now that I'm supposed to become spiritual
leader, I have to find a worthy successor
to take over as the Dragon Warrior.
That's where you want to stay, right?
No, it's just that...
What do I know about being a spiritual
leader? I can't even come up with one of
those cool sounding proverbs.
Life's greatest enemy
is...uh, I don't know...stairs?
Okay.
Everyone knows life's
greatest enemy is time.
I guess it's just easier to hold on to
the life you know than
move on to the one you don't.
Hey, that was pretty good.
Yeah, maybe she should be the spiritual
leader of the Valley of Geese.
Boom, that guy. He drinks like a fest.
Should he be driving? We've come to pay
tribute as you requested.
Looks a little light. Go
back out and get me more.
More?
For chameleon.
Go before I toss you down
another flight of stairs.
How bad was your flight of stairs?
At last, my destiny approaches.
I expand my rule from the city to every
city and town and village.
From here to the Valley of Geese.
And beyond!
We all know the name of the chameleon.
Shin, I had a vision.
I saw the chameleon.
She's gonna take over cities and towns
and the Valley of Geese.
A vision? While you were asleep. I'm
pretty sure that's just a dream.
Not a dream! A vision. Either I had a bad
dumpling before I went to sleep
or it's a dragon warrior thing.
We gotta get to the
chameleon and figure it out!
Well then, you're in
luck. Welcome to Juniver City.
This is the place where you can be
whatever you want to be.
Do whatever you want to do and steal
whatever you want to steal.
I think that's your thing.
Whoa! That came out of nowhere.
I'm sorry.
I've never seen so much traffic before.
You don't have rush hour
in the Valley of Geese?
No one's ever in that much of a rush.
Come on!
Get out!
The only thing that
matters is good to be home again.
The sights. The sounds.
The smells.
That's a wonton wonderland!
Yeah!
Paul!
Focus!
This city is the most
basic place I've ever seen!
I used to feel the same way until the
chameleon got her closet to it.
Tonight we take down the chameleon.
Oh yeah.
I'll show you where this villainous
sorceress lurks as
she dominates the city.
She lurking in that
villainous tower dominating the sea?
How'd you know?
Eh, not my first time
taking down a villain.
Let's keep moving.
Hey, Jen!
Hey Jen!
What kind of sea?
How you doing Jen?
Wow, you're quite the local celeb.
Yeah, I will.
Let's just say a face like
mine is harder to forget.
What?
You're a wanted criminal?
You sound surprised. Is it surprising?
I don't think this is surprising.
You never mentioned you were wanted.
Don't worry.
The law has better
things to do than look for me.
Hey, Fox. We've been looking for you.
Must be slow work week.
I'll handle this.
Morning officers. Dragon Warrior here.
The Fox and I are here on
official Dragon Warrior biz.
Dragon Who warrior?
What?
Dragon Warrior. Anyone?
Nothing?
Perhaps you know me better as...
The Time-boo Panda!
Wait, wait!
Oh my God.
Ah, come on!
Okay. So we tried it your way.
Now we try to time it.
Wait, what's your plan?
Sorry.
Come on, come on, come on, come on!
You can't run away from the
law. You're a wanted criminal.
Yeah, well, it looks
like I'm not the only one.
City Light really is fast-paced.
We gotta get out of here
before they call for...
Back up.
That's a lot of bull.
Run!
Let's go, let's go!
Yeah!
Let's go!
We're going!
Sorry.
Hey, hey, hey!
We don't have time for a truck so long!
We're trapped!
Hey!
It isn't much farther now.
You always see that
guy's always so much farther.
What is this place?
Home, sweet home.
Some of the best crooks and criminals in
all of Juniper City live here.
Careful. These guys will steal your pants
right out here and you'll never know.
Uh-oh.
Now you kids be
careful of those fireworks.
[screaming]
Wow!
So you're friends with all these people?
They're practically family.
Zinn!
Is that really you?
Ah, my old mentor.
I always knew someday you'll find your
way home back to the dead.
And when you did, I'd be sure to give you
a proper homecoming.
Family, huh?
More like distant cousins.
Alright, how should we do this?
Quick and painless or slow and painful?
Slow and painful!
Alright, you little scamps.
Slow and painful it is.
Yay!
You really don't want to do this.
And why's that?
Because if you so much as lay one claw on
me, you're going to have to answer to...
The Dragon Warrior.
Warrior, warrior, warrior, warrior.
Who?
Oh man, are my
adventures really that regional?
Introduce them, Bo.
To your fists!
Bo)
Remember, Po, there are other ways to
break peace than by kicking butt.
Oh, come on, really? Now?
Yes. Now.
Hold on. Shouldn't my inner
sheafoos have differing opinions?
We are in total agreement
with our mutual disappointment.
And you...
Wait!
He who resorts to violence now...
Will only find more violence later.
So what we're saying is, if we don't hurt
her a little now, we
can hurt her a lot later.
What? No, that's not what I said.
Yes! If more violence later, it's better
than less violence now.
No, no, no, no. I think you're
misunderstanding the fundamental point.
No, why? Why?
Why do you think it's
like my tummy jingle?
You know, that pantomie
is a lot of good points.
I like it.
No, no, no, wait! Come back!
I'll come up with better wisdom.
You have got to workshop those proverbs.
The Kung Fu Panda?
Nope.
The son of Mr. Ping and Lee?
No, so both very common names.
Mentored by Oogway?
Sorry.
Trained to my master Shifu?
Oh, Master Shifu!
Yes! Everyone's heard of the legendary
Master Shifu, but not you.
Can someone say legendary? Bring it in.
Look, Han, I know we've had our
differences, but we're really in a jam
here, and I was hoping
you could help me out.
Thank you.
Don't drink that.
We just need some place to lie low for a
while until the heat cools up.
And why should I help you?
Because deep down beneath that
iron-scaled exterior is a good-hearted
soul who still thinks of
me as one of the family.
Fine. But if he's still who by nightfall,
I'm calling the both myself.
Stay tight!
So tonight we take down the chameleon.
After you take your pants back.
Yeah, cool!
Guys, come on! Give them back!
Who's your custom?
Please!
[Laughter]
Yeah, this place
doesn't look very friendly.
Oh, oh, wait here!
I'm sure everything is fine.
This is a restaurant!
These are my people.
We speak the same language!
You wait here.
Salutations!
I'm so sorry to interrupt.
I know you're having a good time.
But I was wondering if a panda happened
to be passing by these parts.
There was a panda here.
Do you know him?
Know him? Why, I'm a stan!
You need to pay for what
your son did to my tavern!
My boy wouldn't have
done this for no reason.
Is it possible you're brought with plan?
Try it!
No, no!
The broth smells excellent!
You should not add a single thing,
especially the nothing!
Hands off the goose!
The panda's back!
He's back!
No.
But you're about to wish he was.
Because if you think he
made a mess of this place,
you have no idea what I'm capable of.
Everything he
learned, he learned from me.
Except one thing.
Mercy.
I don't know where he got
that because I don't believe him.
Now this can go one of two ways.
The easy way, in which
you tell me where he is,
or the hard way, in which
you tell me where he is.
But it's hard to understand what you're
saying because you have no idea.
Maja!
I eat Maja on tiles for purpose!
Mm.
Shida, sha--
(screaming)
- It is our son.
- He took a boat in Juniper City.
- It's right.
- You know a wise goose.
- Time to go.
- Yeah, right.
(screaming)
- Okay, let's try this again.
- Through the pot, roll
the wok, serve the dish,
and survive.
Hey, where's the golden dragon I'm
supposed to shoot at?
- Not gonna happen with the broom.
- Yeah, still not bad though.
- Yeah, but stir later, roll higher,
and the word is sk-boosh.
- Sk-boosh isn't a word.
- And sk-blam is?
(screaming)
- I gotta say, you're not
like any of the other masters
I've met.
- Yeah, no, there's not a lot of pandas.
- No, you're like a good guy.
- Listen up, the coast is clear, see?
Hit the streets, and you
two get out of my sight.
(eerie music)
- I know, I promise
that I'll lead you right
to the chameleon's front door,
but the back door seems
a little more practical.
- I gotta say, Jen, you
really are a fox of your word.
- A Judah peach pit?
- One from Master Oogway's
peach tree of heavenly wisdom.
That's a valley of peace thing.
It's supposed to remind me that every pit
holds the promise of a mighty tree.
Maybe it'll do the same for you.
(eerie music)
- Are you sure you wanna do this?
- The wise spiritual leader once said,
"How may one kick butt if one doesn't
seek a butt to kick?"
- You're a real piece
of work, you know that?
- Thank you.
Wait, was that a compliment by himself?
- Yes.
(eerie music)
- Oh.
- Ah, ah, ah, have you seen our son?
(giggling)
Ah, ah, ah.
- Sorry.
- Sorry, sorry.
- No.
- Tell us you've seen our son.
(giggling)
- Wait, why did he leave it?
He said yes.
Hey, look, Paul was here.
Amazing, Dean, but how can you tell?
- We parents have a gift
for seeing, others cannot.
Come on, there may be
more clues up ahead.
(eerie music)
(snoring)
- Shh.
Shh.
(gasping)
(eerie music)
(humming) (screaming)
(screaming)
- That was close.
- Look out.
Paul.
- Stand back.
(screaming)
Whoa.
- They're coming.
Hurry, help me with the cage.
(screaming)
- It's no use.
- We gotta raise it with something.
- Here, use my staff.
All right, stand back, here I go.
Jen.
Where are you taking my staff?
- I think you need my staff.
You gave it to Jen and
now Jen has given it to me.
- Given you gain, I
believe is how it looks.
- You were right, Jen.
She was his music mark.
- Jen.
- First roll of the streets.
Never trust anyone.
I thought her dead.
- And you thought my
apprentice was your friend.
- Apprentice?
She's the one that took you in?
- Best thing that ever happened to her.
- You should have seen
the little better Skype
before I found her.
- Name Jean had starred.
Hanging out with those
rejects from the dead of thieves.
(screaming)
- She had no fear.
Such a potential.
So I took her in.
I made her what she is today.
Stand up straight.
- Yes, master.
So you went through all of this
just to get me to give
you the staff of wisdom?
Why?
- I too paid from humble beginnings
and dreamed of becoming something more.
I wanted respect and power.
I wanted to be a master of kung fu.
- Say what?
- I was turned away from
every training hall I went to.
They would say I was
too small, too lowly,
and that kung fu was not my destiny.
And so I chose a different path.
Socially.
I grew.
I excelled.
And I got everything
I had ever dreamed of.
Everything except kung fu.
(screaming)
Just because I can look like Tai Lung
doesn't mean I can fight my king.
- You see, poo, kung fu
may be performed by the body,
but if she puts a house in the spirit,
and now that I have
access to the spirit realm,
- You're gonna steal Tai Lung's kung fu?
- His and those of every master villain
that came before me.
And once I do, no one will dare
underestimate me again.
You forgot about me?
(laughing)
- Don't bother, Po.
Those balls are
enchanted with some very old
and very powerful magic.
You'd need at least 10 dragon
warriors to get through them.
- Then I won't go through them.
I'll go under them.
(screaming)
- I'm not frustrated
with all sorts of reasons.
(screaming)
(screaming) (screaming) (screaming) (screaming)
- Po!
- Jen?
My staff, hand it over.
- I'm so sorry I lied to you.
I was just doing what I was told.
- Apologize later.
Right now I have to stop the chameleon.
- Po! - Po!
- Po!
- Jen?
(gasping)
(screaming)
- No!
- Well done, Jen.
- You never said you were gonna hurt him.
- Watch the second rule of the streets.
- Someone always gets hurt.
- And make sure it's never you.
- I just wish there had been another way.
- Third rule of the streets?
- Third rule?
- Some would say it's the most important.
No one is interested in your feelings.
- Chop, chop.
We have a spirit round the plundered.
- And smile.
Nobody likes a grouch.
- Honestly, Jen, I don't know where
it becomes such bad habits.
(ominous music)
(growling)
- Be careful.
- Get on me.
- Oh God!
(screaming)
- Don't save me.
- Ah!
- Hi, son.
(screaming)
- It's okay, we got you, Po.
We got you.
So you followed me.
It was his idea.
- Ah.
- Okay, okay, it was both our ideas.
- We only followed because we love.
- No.
- You followed because
you didn't believe in me.
- And because we love?
- Well, you're right.
I screwed up big time.
I trusted the wrong person.
I gave the staff of
wisdom right to the chameleon.
- Oh.
Oh.
That was a very big time screw up.
- Only I'd listened to Master Sheath,
who had stayed in the Valley of Peace.
The chameleon wouldn't have my staff,
and none of this would be happening.
I was just so determined to
keep things the way they were.
- Everyone is afraid of
the chameleon, even me.
There was a time not so long ago
when all I wanted to be
was the greatest noodle chef
in the Valley.
- So what happened?
- I became the greatest
noodle chef in the Valley.
- That's true.
- But I also became a
father, and nothing,
nothing's ever been the same since.
Change doesn't always
have to be a bad thing.
Why do you think I always
change the menu at the restaurant?
Because if things stay the same forever,
sooner or later, they
would lose their flavor.
- He's right, Po.
Since I left my village,
I've become a bit of a warrior.
Strong, brave.
(laughing)
- Oh!
- Move it.
This way.
Get those pages up there.
Come on!
- This looks bad.
- Really bad.
- Move it!
Come on!
- Don't tell me you
were actually starting
to become friends with that vendor.
- What?
No, it's just--
- When we want
something, we must use whatever
is at our disposal to get it.
That's all that kind of was.
- Something to use.
Is that why you took me in?
So I could help you get what you wanted?
I took you in because you were clever
and ruthless and unsentimental, like me.
And the day you
stopped being those things
is the day when, yes, you
stopped being useful to me.
So for both of us sakes, don't change.
(dramatic music)
- Tonight, when the blood moon rises
to its highest point
and the night's died,
I will open the door to the spirit realm
and all of its secrets will be mine!
(gasping)
Does the blood moon
always rise as slowly?
I seem to remember it rising faster.
No?
Just me?
Hmm.
Ugh.
It's just for dramatic effect anyway.
I think I'm just gonna
open the spirit realm now.
(dramatic music)
Bring me Tyra!
- I love you, big fan.
- Who are you and what are
you doing with that staff?
- This was given to me
by an old friend of yours.
- The puffy panda?
Poe might be an idiot,
but he never really had
a bookway staff to the likes of you.
- Who said anything about you, willingly?
(dramatic music)
- Apparently I misjudged you, listened.
Now, why have you brought me back?
- I summoned you here so
that you could teach me
your most legendary kung fu roots.
- I don't share my skills with anyone.
- There wasn't a request.
(dramatic music)
- Yes, I got it.
- The Tylung Nerve Strike,
the power, the precision.
(dramatic music)
- What have you done to me?
- All of your kung fu is now mine.
And the best part is,
I'm just getting warmed up.
- Bring me General Nye.
(dramatic music)
Bring me the Stomp of the Spring.
- Oh, why would this be reasonable?
- I'm not going anywhere
until I get my staff back.
- No staff is worth your life.
- As long as I'm
still the Dragon Warrior,
I won't let anyone else
get hurt because of me.
(dramatic music)
- Hope, you're alive.
Please, I made a mistake.
- So did I, trusting you.
- I'm sorry.
- Did your master
tell you to say that too?
- She's not my master,
I'm leaving for good.
It's the truth, I was
wrong about everything.
- What are you doing?
- Stop it, you.
- Get out of my way, Jen.
- No.
- Move.
- You want me to move?
- Move me.
- First you betrayed me,
and now you wanna fight me?
(dramatic music)
Why are you doing this?
- To stop you from getting killed.
(dramatic music)
- What do you care if
I get killed or not?
(dramatic music)
- Please, Pope, just
something to do with one thing right.
- You're not the only one
who's made some bad choices lately.
- You're really gonna go
through with this, aren't you?
- Afraid so.
- And there's nothing I
can do to talk you out of it?
- I'm afraid not.
- You can't beat her, you know?
- You're probably
right, but I have to try.
Get as far away from
this place as you can.
- How?
We should never have let him come here.
We are such a terrible father.
- At least you didn't lie and betray him.
- Well, that's true, you're worse.
- I am a terrible friend.
- A friend, I feel a
little generous, not about us.
- Let's just give up, surrender.
- We can't let him go in there alone.
- What can we do?
- There's just three
of us against an army.
- Then I guess we'll just
have to get an army of our own.
(dramatic music)
(screaming)
- Hey, lift me up, everybody.
(dramatic music)
(screaming)
- Thank you.
The Dragon Warrior's in trouble.
- Who?
- You know, Bo.
The Panda.
Now, now, a different Panda.
- I'm his father.
- I'm also his father.
Okay, that doesn't matter.
What matters is that
my friend's in trouble
and he needs my help.
So, I need yours.
- Why?
- Should we help you?
- Because, because it's
the right thing to do.
(screaming)
- Stop it, stop, stop laughing.
I know you think it might be too late
for a bunch of cheats,
thieves, and cutthroats like us
to change our ways, but a
good friend once told me
it's never too late
to do the right thing.
So, what you're saying is,
the more right we do now,
the more wrong we can do later.
- But, no.
- And with the communion out of the way.
- We can finally do
all the wrong we want.
- I think you're
missing the fundamental point.
- Violence, violence, violence.
- Are you guys ready
to do the right thing
for the wrong reasons?
(screaming)
- Now, you see the mistake
this dragon warrior fellow made
was underestimating his opponent.
- I never would have walked
into such an obvious trap.
- Hey.
- Now, you see the mistake
this dragon warrior fellow made
was shut up, Barry.
- This place is growing with more guards
than I've ever seen.
I'll never get to Paul in time.
- You just get to Paul.
- He'll take care of the guards.
- We will?
I mean, we will.
- But how?
- Just leave that to me.
(dramatic music)
(screaming)
- General Kine, Lord Shep,
those are all my old
nemesis' nemacy, nemacy?
- The chameleon is pulling
spirits from the spirit realm
and draining us of all our moves.
- And she's using your staff to do it.
- I'm here to get it back.
- I won't hold my breath.
- I'm sorry, do I know you?
- Do you know me?
It's Scott.
The fire-breathing crocodile.
- Oh, right, Scott.
Master Shifu and I were
just talking about you.
- And who made a mistake
choosing you as the dragon warrior?
I just didn't realize how
big a mistake it was until now.
- Whoa, Tai Lung?
I'm gonna get that staff
back, restore your kung fu,
and return you all
back to the spirit realm.
You'll see, all I see
is a broken promise.
(dramatic music)
- All right, you bunch
of cantankerous kamodos.
Now this can go one of two ways.
The easy way in which
you surrender willingly,
or the hard way where
you surrender woundedly.
The choice is yours.
(dramatic music) - I'm just kidding, I'm just kidding.
(screaming) - Oh.
(growling)
(screaming)
- I've been.
- I can't help.
- Is it too spicy?
- No, it's got the perfect.
- I can't send a death
suit to my mouth every time.
(screaming)
(laughing)
- That scandal is right,
more violence later is better.
(cheering)
- I believe you have
something that belongs to me.
- Can't you even die right?
- Can't you even kill wrong?
- Nope, we're playing
it and coming together.
Now about that staff.
- Take it, I already have everything I
need from it anyway.
I think this was destiny.
A final face off
between the new adversaries,
alike in so many ways.
- If only I had a
jumpling for every time a villain
told me how much we had in common.
- It's true, we've both
risen to the highest of heights.
It's a shame only one of
us can come out on top.
- It is a shame, for you.
- My combined power, sorcery and control
make me unstoppable.
And once I dispense with you,
I'll expand my rule
from Juniper City to--
- Every other city and town and village
from here to the
valley of peace and beyond.
Yeah, I know.
- But how did you know?
- I saw it in a vision,
because I'm the track and warrior.
For now at least.
But I've realized that it's
probably time I made a change.
And so should you.
I'm the chameleon, I
do nothing but change.
- Only on the outside.
Real change happens from within.
And if we're really as alike as you say,
then maybe we could
both let go of who we were
and become something
better than we already are.
What do you say?
- I say--
(dramatic music)
- I saw that coming.
We're very proud of you.
You climbed it our way.
Now, try it yours.
- Take her butt.
- I'm way ahead of you.
- That's a hell of a strong twist.
- Master Force, push some terror.
Master Force, make some fury.
(screaming)
Master Force, pour some gold.
(dramatic music)
- What?
- Recognize this move?
(screaming)
- Is that how I sound?
I don't sound like that, do I?
- You didn't hear the light, I almost--
I just fell off.
I can't come down.
- You know what left?
All right, Alpha Kai,
which one are you rooting for?
- I'm not sure.
This is all very confusing.
I'm stronger than every
opponent you've ever faced.
Because I am every
(screaming)
- Whoa, I gotta workshop
those heroic entrances.
- Nah, it was just right.
- I wish we had to do rotten
and gutter where you belong.
- Better to rot in the
gutter than under your thumb.
(grunting)
(dramatic music)
- Yeah!
- Who against one?
- Well, now, that doesn't seem fair.
I'll have to even the odds.
- Master Cobra, Master
Osprey, Master Scooby-O.
Master Moon, General Kai, Lord Shag.
- No, Lord Shag.
- That is awesome.
I mean, it's
disturbing, but it's awesome.
(roaring) - Whoa!
(screaming)
(screaming) (screaming)
- How?
(laughing)
- I thought we were friends.
Stand back, I'm gonna kick my butt.
(dramatic music)
(screaming)
(screaming) (dramatic music)
- Come on, Paul, get out of there.
- You have to do this.
- I can't beat the chameleon.
- A wise old tortoise once told me
that you never know what
you can do until you do it.
- The fate of the
world hangs in the balance
and you're here giving me
life advice on a tortoise.
- Be the pit, Jen.
Be the pit.
(dramatic music)
- And what do you think you're doing?
- Finishing what Paul started.
- Oh, please.
How many times do I have to tell you?
(screaming)
- Don't say much.
(dramatic music)
(grunting)
- You ungrateful little person.
That's all I've done for you.
You betrayed me for the panda.
- Yours for all his truth.
Never trust anyone.
- You can't defeat me.
I know all your moves.
- Not this one.
- Roll, I have stirred,
served, and stunk lamb.
(dramatic music)
(screaming)
- Second roll, someone always gets hurt.
- Now that's a cool move.
- Paul, you could've
gotten out of that cage
any time you wanted.
- You faker.
- It's not faking, it's method.
Besides, how's a peach pit
ever supposed to become a tree
if you never give it the chance to grow?
- Hey, you stirred
faster and rolled higher.
But for the last time, the word is...
(grunting)
(dramatic music)
- Maybe your way was right about you.
You are completely useless, actual.
- Oh my gosh, thank you so much.
(dramatic music)
(laughing)
- I'm done, I'm done.
I think it's time to send us home, pal.
(dramatic music)
- Jen, do something!
- Third roll, no one's
interested in your feelings.
- I see you on the other side.
Dragon Warrior.
(screaming)
(dramatic music)
- Put back some food
for your time in jail.
- Let's hope it's not your final meal.
- Thanks, guys.
I was thinking, after I serve my time
and I'm a free fox again,
maybe I'll open one of
those acupuncture places
that are all the rage.
- I think you better sit it for a job
with a little more room for growth.
(dramatic music)
- Key balance.
(blowing raspberry)
- Oh, out of all the
candidates you choose
to train as your worthy successor,
you chose the fox.
You know when you know, you know?
- Fine, do what you
want, for me, for state,
for carrot, I don't
even know why I bothered.
- I'm going to meditate.
- A what?
- Don't worry, he'll come around.
Probably.
- Maybe.
- Hey, you okay?
- He's right, what about
me says I'm ready for this?
- Well, as I learned from
working in my dad's kitchen,
sometimes the greatest dishes
come from the most unlikely ingredients.
- Hey, that's not bad.
Okay, I see you as spiritual leader.
- Yeah, I'm getting the
hang of this proverb thing.
One shouldn't do a deep squat
with a chopstick in one's pocket.
- Yeah, maybe you just
stick the cake in mine.
- Money can't buy happiness.
- But it sure can buy a lot of dumplings.
- Why does it always come
back to dumplings with you?
- When life gives you lemons,
make pear juice and
blow everyone's minds.
- We get it.
- You can't have your
mooncake and eat it too.
- Although, I guess
you could have mooncake
and then the border
men go putting on side.
- Can we just start the training now?
- Inner peace.
Inner peace.
- Hey, Master, she food.
- There's two of us.
- We're doing great, she food.
- We're not breathing with your belly.
- Are you tired?
- There's a piece you mentioned.
- I'm tired.
- You know what this world is about.
- Aah!
- Inner peace.
Inner peace.
(somber music)
- Are you ready to begin your training?
- Are you?
- Yes.
- Yeah, I brought a little help.
(dramatic music)
Hey, baby, baby
How was I supposed to know
If there's
something worth all I can
Baby, baby
I couldn't help that
Oh, oh, oh
And now you're in the south
You're showing me
how you want to be
You got your name here
Cause I need to know now
I know I don't need help
You're killing me
And I always came here
I still believe
When I'm known with you
I live my mind to be a spy
You've been
waiting for your dreams
Oh, baby, baby
You're a piece of pie
Girl, you've got
the power to stand
I'm thinking baby
There's nothing wrong with you
I'm going out there
And I'm going to see you
How you want to be
I tell you, baby
Cause I need to know now
Because I know it now
You're killing me
And I always have this
I still believe
When I'm known with you
I live my mind to be a spy
You've been
waiting for your dreams
Baby
Yeah
Oh, baby
I know that you still believe
I'm going out there
You're a piece of pie
(dramatic music)