- Mister Shoichi?
- His room.
Your mother's hospital's on fire!
Mother!
I'll go too!
Stay here, Mahito!
Mother...
Three years into the war,
Mother died.
Four years in,
I left Tokyo with Father.
THE BOY AND THE HERON
"Saginuma Station"
That's her.
She looked exactly like Mother.
Did you wait long?
We just arrived.
You're Mahito?
I'm Natsuko..
Sorry I'm late.
We had a flat tire on the way.
You've grown up.
I've met you once, when you were a baby.
The factory first?
Yes. I'll be back for dinner.
Perfect timing.
Come, let's go.
That's heavy.
After you.
To the residence.
Mahito, I'm going to be your
new mother. Did you know?
Your hand.
Go on, put it here.
Feel it moving?
A baby. Your little
brother or sister.
I'm so delighted.
Oh, stop here.
"May your luck last long in battle"
"Congratulations on your call-up"
Alright, we're here.
Take the luggage in.
Sure.
Mahito, let's go.
It's your first time,
so we'll enter from the front.
Look, over there.
That building.
Your father's new factory
Let's visit it sometime.
Oh dear, no one's in.
Bring your shoes with you.
How rare. It's never
flown inside before.
That nosy gray heron.
It must be welcoming you.
Well well.
Opened Shoichi's trunk again?
Well, m'lady...
The pedicab man came,
ya see!
He left it here.
Yup, yup.
Didn't know whose it was.
It smells so sweet...
So we just..
This is Shoichi's son, Mahito.
- What?!
- Canned beef!
Tasty when cooked with rice!
Canned salmon!
Gimme the bones!
Corned beef!
You can still get it?
And lastly...
- Sugar!
- Good for rice cakes!
Sweet bean paste!
- Sweet rice cakes!
- Pure white sugar!
Gimme a taste!
Me too!
We can go now.
So some places still have it!
He's his mother's spitting image.
Such a pretty boy.
I hope he stays safe...
You got smokes?!
Gimme one!
This is your room.
You must be tired.
I'll bring tea.
Mom!
Mahito... Goodbye...
Mom! I'm coming!
Mahito...
Mom...
Mahito!
Sonny!
Better head back!
The lady's worried about ya!
Sonny!
That used to be sealed off.
He'll get taken..
Sonny!
Thank goodness.
What is this?
There's a staircase.
What's this place?
Well...
Better head back.
The feathers are gone...
I was saving this story for
when you get settled in here.
That tower was built by
my mother's uncle, I was told.
He was a very smart man,
but read too many books,
and lost his mind.
One day, a long time
before I was born,
he disappeared, leaving only
an open book he hadn't finished.
They looked everywhere,
but couldn't find any trace.
Later, in a flood, a passage
to the main house collapsed
and beneath the tower,. a
maze of tunnels was found.
For safety, my grandfather
had the entrance sealed.
You mustn't go near it either.
Yes ma'am.
Thank you for the tea.
Good night.
Good night. Mornings are cold,
so sleep warm.
Yes ma'am.
Mahito, save me...
You're home.
I'm home.
Navy boys are all flustered.
They boasted Saipan
would hold for a year.
I pity those who died...
The factory's booming though.
We'll take the Datsun to school.
A transfer student arriving by car
will shock everyone.
Don't worry.
We've spoken to the teachers.
Off you go.
"Agricultural volunteers"
"Mahito Maki"
Mahito, tell me the truth.
Who did this to you?
I just took a tumble.
Rest assured. I'll avenge you,
So tell me the truth.
Shoichi...
I won't let them get away with this!
I'll go to his school.
Mahito!
Save me!
Ow!
Oh my!
Mahito!
Shut this!
Mom! Mom!
M'lady, please get some rest.
We'll take turns
keeping an eye on him.
What are you?!
Not an ordinary gray heron!
It seems the long-awaited
one has appeared at last.
I shall now guide you to your mother.
My mother?! How dare you!
My mother died!
A typical human trick.
She ain't dead.
Pardon me, but you did not
see your mother's dead body.
She is awaiting your rescue.
Please join us...
Join us...
Mahito!
Sonny!
Your presence is requested.
You're awake?
Thank heavens.
You were out for so long
and we were so worried.
The gray heron...
Gray heron?
Is it near?
A dream, perhaps?
Mahito!
You're awake.
Rest assured.
I'll catch who did this to you.
I was just clumsy.
Don't worry.
No school for now.
I donated 300 yen.
The principal was shocked.
Those teachers barely teach.
Too much voluntary labor.
That might leave a bald spot.
It'll get covered up.
Natsuko isn't feeling well.
She's probably tired.
Try not to worry her.
The railway's stopped again.
Always accidents.
Get well soon.
Take care of him.
Sonny, take it easy and lie down.
Bathroom.
But your bed pan's here...
Well, a lot's strange
about this place.
In many ways.
You well enough?
Yes sir.
Magnificent, aren't they?
Can't leave them at the station,
so we came here.
They're beautiful.
Natsuko's worried about you.
Go see her.
Yes sir.
Men, well done!
Rest, then return to the factory!
Ain't to your liking, is it?
It tastes awful
Straight talker, huh?
Oh, hey!
You got tobacco?!
Knotweed leaves.
Wanna puff?
Heck nah,
I ain't a caterpillar!
Tobacco's so scarce now.
Thanks for the meal.
The lady of the house keeps saying
she wants to see you.
Pay her a visit.
Is she very sick?
Morning sickness. Carrying a baby
causes some women a lotta pain.
Like when you were born.
Your momma had a tough time
I came to visit.
M'lady...
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have
let you get hurt.
Forgive me, big sister...
M'lady, don't make yourself worse.
Please get well soon.
"Hikari Cigarettes"
Your presence is requested!
A Cigarette!
You wily old flimflam man!
Sonny, sonny!
Come, come.
I'm busy now.
I got good news for ya.
Come, come.
Sonny, wanna real bow and arrows?
Something perfect for ya.
The genuine article.
Steel arrowheads, and
a mighty fine bow and all.
Nobody'll know it's gone.
For cigarettes?
Hikari.
How about one box?
Gramps has them.
And there were only two inside.
You gave 'em to that
wrinkly prune?! Hey! Sonny!
"To grown-up Mahito"
"From Mother
1937, autumn"
Mother's handwriting...
"How Do You Live?"
Mother left this for me...
- M'lady!
What is it?
The lady of the house
ain't in her room!
I'll go too!
She headed for the forest.
The lady did?
A while ago now.
It was bright out.
She must be in the forest.
Surely not!
No gray heron today.
Something's wrong!
Let's go!
Let's not! She wouldn't
have gone that way...
I can't see a thing...
Hey, sonny!
Clog prints...
Sonny!
Look.
Pave stones.
C-Can't see'em.
I got night blindness.
It's an old path.
Let's go back.
Ain't no way the lady
would come here!
Maybe she didn't have a choice.
"I was made by divine power"
L-L-Lights!
It's a trap! A trap!
Heron man! Here I am!
Return Natsuko to us!
About time you came.
Now, enter...
Go back, ma'am.
I'll go.
You mustn't go! We maids can't
hear the tower master's voice!
Only your bloodline can!
Then I must go! I have to
bring Aunt Natsuko back!
No! You think you'd be better off
without her, don't ya?
So what's the point in going?!
He says my mother's alive.
I know it's a lie,
but I have to see.
Wait! Ow ow ow!
My poor back!
Ow ow ow!
About time you came.
Step this way.
It's a trap! A trap!
I know...
If so, then why...?
Here she is.
Your mother.
Why not get closer and
make sure for yourself.
It's a trap. A trap.
Wait, sonny...
Mother...
Mother!
Mo...
What a waste...
One of my better efforts.
Shouldn't have touched her.
How can you do this?!
If you'd like,
I could remake her.
No! Don't dishonor my mother!
Angry? My heart is right here.
Best use your one arrow wisely.
Then it's my turn.
I'll bites your arrogant,
lying, swollen heart,
and rip it out!
Weakling, do your worst.
You fail!
Get away from me!
Drat! My molted feather!
This ain't good...
You got'em!
Nice shooting!
The arrow flew by itself.
No! Not my #7 flight feather!
Dang it!
That wasn't fair!
Don't laugh!
Behold my fearsomeness...
Be gentle...
Let's not do that.
Where is Natsuko?!
Sonny, skewer that turkey!
Hey...
Brilliantly done.
So tell me, how did you
figure out my weakness?
You just told me...
It's your #7 flight feather.
Whoopsie daisy!
Loose lips sink ships.
Take me to Natsuko.
I wouldn't go if I were you...
Foolish bird.
I command you to be his guide.
No going back now.
You might end up regretting it
Godspeed, soldier...
Not me too!
"Those who seek my knowledge
shall die..."
Go! Let's go!
Let's go eat!
Let's go!
Get up!
Walk! Walk!
Someone opened the gate...
Get back, damn birds!
On your feet.
Move.
Move!
The buried will wake.
Stand beside me.
It's gone.
Walk backwards.
Don't look back.
Why did you open the gate?!
The pelicans pushed me...
Show me that arrow.
The gray heron? No wonder
the pelicans couldn't eat you.
The wind is up.
The tide'll be high. Follow me!
Push!
We've caught the wind!
Come!
That scar...
My plaster came off.
I've got one too. Look.
A swamp thrasher got me.
"Swamp thrasher"?
A massive one.
I ate it though.
A big wave's coming.
After that, plain sailing.
Where'd you come from?
Up above...
Is it a nice place?
Not for me.
Have you seen a woman named Natsuko?
Are you sweet on her?
My father is...
I'm trying to find her.
And what are you called?
Mahito.
Meaning "sincere one"...
So that's why you reek of death.
Look.
None are real.
In this world,
the dead are the majority.
Stop rowing.
Who are they?
Buyers coming for our catch
They saw that flag.
They're not able to kill.
That's my job.
Get off.
Help me.
The warawara are coming.
No dilly-dallying!
That fish needs carving!
Lend a hand.
You try.
Right there.
Deeper!
Pull hard!
Don't spill the guts!
Warawara eat them so they can fly
Hey, get up and eat.
Don't touch those dolls.
They look like the grannies
at the residence.
They're protecting you.
Water's over there.
Kiriko.
How do you know my damn name?
It's Kiriko, right?
This world isn't like mine,
but some things are similar.
I've always been here.
The Kiriko I know is an
old lady, like those dolls.
Hurry up and eat.
Toilet?
Out there, in the yard.
Thank you.
Kiriko!
They mature, then fly.
They haven't flown for so long
Little ones see them off.
Where are they going?
- To be born.
- What?
Where you came from.
To be born up above.
As people?
What else?
I'm glad we could feed them well.
Pelicans! Dammit,
they'll eat them all!
Lady Himi!
The warawara are burning!
Stop it!
Don't burn the warawara!
Stop!
Damn birds'll stay away for now.
Without Lady Himi,
no more warawara.
Lady Himi!
Thank you!
No more'll fly tonight.
Let's eat..
Sorry grannies...
Young one, put me out
of my misery.
My wing is broken.
I can not fly.
You should've left
the warawara alone!
My kind were brought to
this hellscape.
So we would eat the warawara.
This sea has few fish we can eat.
My kind were all starving.
We flew as high as we could.
As high and far
as our wings could carry us.
But... it always ended the same way.
We could only reach this island.
Now our newborns
are forgetting how to fly.
We eat the warawara...
The fire maiden burns us.
The sea here...
is cursed...
Rest in peace...
It was such a noble pelican...
Ah! You still have that?
Hey, wait!
Natsuko isn't here,
you know..
I know.
How about I take you to her?
I'll find her myself.
Wait.
Hey, chief!
Arrogant little turd!
You'll bury it...?
Okay!
I'm such a pushover.
Stop!
Too far! Come back.
Alright.
Can't stomach this.
Don't blame me if
Natsuko gets eaten.
You said you'd eat my heart.
Sorry...
Ow!
Spit it out.
Where is Natsuko?!
I'll rip this!
Try it!
I'll tear you apart!
Ow ow ow!
Please stop!
You okay?
I hardly ripped it.
It's ripped now.
This is crummy tea,
but drink and make up.
We didn't fight.
He's a liar and a cheat,
but I know he took Natsuko.
I hate to say it,
but you overestimate me.
The wise cheat to survive.
A gray heron told me
all gray herons are liars.
Is that the truth,
or a lie?
- A lie!
- The truth!
It's the truth...
All gray herons are liars.
That's a lie too!
This lie is true.
You're a-fine pair...
Go search for Natsuko together.
I have to tend to the warawara.
The tower master
told you to guide him.
Stay vigilant,
and work together. Go.
It's Kiriko!
For good luck.
Take it.
Will we meet again?
Who knows?
Thank you!
Do your best.
Miss Natsuko!
I'll get some men to stay here!
No, the factory mustn't stop.
Please return to your work.
Alright! We'll always be on call!
Okay.
Thanks.
We've searched the pond,
the hills, everywhere.
Natsuko, Mahito, and Kiriko.
A triple disappearance is unheard of.
Say, Mister Shoichi...
Every now and then,
strange things happen here...
I've been working here
for a good 60 years now,
and that tower out in
the yard just ain't right.
That thing sure weren't
built by people.
Oh come on,
scary stories now?
Just before the Meiji Revolution,
it fell outta the sky!
Rumble rumble,
BOOOOOM!
With an earth-rattling crash.
Like thunder?
There used to be a big pond,
but the water all dried up.
That tower stands there now.
From what I heard,
Natsuko's clever granduncle had it built.
No siree,
it came down from the sky!
Everybody was too scared to go near.
After 30-odd years, the forest
grew back, and the thing got buried.
Then, the grand uncle discovered it.
He became obsessed with it...
Because it was so rare,
he built the tower around it.
So many people died or got hurt.
Plus, the granduncle
vanished into the tower...
He sure did.
Mahito's mother, Hisako,
also went missing once.
We searched the whole village.
Then after a year,
she came back, fit as a fiddle.
Looking the same as she was before.
No memory of it,
and grinning, but...
Bizarre, ain't it?
We have the tower key?
Yes sir, I think...
I'll go there now.
I'm pooped...
These legs weren't made for walking.
I won't be able to make it
to where Natsuko is.
If only I could block this hole,
I could fly...
Shove a stick in it or something.
Easy to say. The hole maker
has to fill it, or it won't work!
Is that lie true?
I never tell lies!
Be gentle.
Make that part smoother...
Shut up.
It's through! Gently,
or you'll break your beak.
How's that?
Look at me,
gorgeous and powerful!
Can you fly?
I ain't your friend or your ally, kid.
So long. You'll have to find Natsuko,
and get out of here,
all on your lonesome...
It came out?
No, it just.
It sticks out a wee bit, so.
Here! This part bugs me!
There! There!
Oh, don't take too much off.
Shut up.
It's a home.
The blacksmith's.
Shh! Duck down!
That's a big parakeet
Weird... Why are they
hanging around?
They ate the blacksmith?
They eat people?!
Elephants too.
Like the pelicans, the master
brought them, and they bred.
Gotta pass through there,
or you can't get to Natsuko.
I'll draw'em out,
then you dash in.
I'll try.
We have been waiting.
Is there a Natsuko here?
I'm looking for her.
This way, sir.
This way
Damn you!
Is this how you ate Natsuko?!
Natsuko has baby.
We not eat baby.
You not have baby
Eatable! Eatable!
Himi! It's Himi!
Stupid. Those parakeets
nearly stewed you.
You're Himi?
Thank you for saving my life.
You're that brat who
was with Kiriko.
I'm Mahito. I'm looking for
someone called Natsuko.
Natsuko...
My little sister?
"Little sister"?!
Come.
Time's wasting.
This is my home.
It's like a tower I know.
Sure, it's the same one.
It stands straddling
all kinds of worlds.
Come in.
Eat it.
Hurry, the jam'll drip.
Kiriki loves my bread too.
It's delicious!
It's like the bread
my mother used to bake!
Natsuko is your mother?
She's not.
Natsuko is someone...
my father likes.
My mother died.
As did mine.
Eat lots. We'll be going
deep inside.
Careful. You get lost,
you never get out.
It's guarded...
Careful. In here,
my power has limits.
This way.
Doors to where?
Quiet. You'll mess me up.
This one.
Don't get sucked in.
Father?!
That's your father?
If you want to go home,
open this.
But Natsuko...
I can't leave alone!
She doesn't want to leave.
She'll have her baby.
Parakeets!
We're trapped.
In here! Turn it hard!
You mustn't let go. Ready?
Grab the other knob! Shut the door!
Where are we? Hold on!
Once you let go, it's lost forever.
It's Mahito!
- Father!
- Want to stay?
Just let go.
Not without Natsuko!
Taste my blade, monsters!
Mahito turned into a parakeet.
Father, I'm sorry
Mister Shoichi.
Mahito's a budgie now!
Don't touch the stone.
It's not happy we're here.
The delivery room.
Natsuko's there.
The stone's aware of us,
and upset. I wouldn't go in.
I have to go.
I'll wait here.
Natsuko, it's Mahito.
Natsuko?
Natsuko, it's Mahito!
I've come for you!
Natsuko!
Let's go home!
You...
What are you doing here?!
Go back!
Now!
Let's go together!
I absolutely hate you!
Get out!
Go back!
Now!
Natsuko...
Mother!
Let's go home!
Mahito, run!
Natsuko!
Mother!
Master of the great stone,
hear my plea...
Let my sister lying there...
go home...
...with this boy who
will be her son.
Natsuko. Natsuko.
Come to me.
Up you get.
That's it. Good girl.
Come to me..
You have come,
my descendant.
My name is Mahito.
You're the tower master?
My great-granduncle?
Wait there.
Quietly.
Now this world...
...will last another day.
Another day?!
It only lasts that long?
Come.
My world,
my power, everything,
comes from this stone.
That stone created this sea world?
There is more to be done.
Worlds are living things.
Mold and bugs infest them.
And I have grown old.
I seek a successor.
Mahito, will you continue my work?
Me...?
My successor must come
from my bloodline.
That is my contract with the stone.
Whether this world becomes beautiful,
or an abomination,
is entirely in your hands.
You mean your blocks?
You may add one of these blocks to it.
You can make this world
a more harmonious place.
Those aren't wooden.
It's stone for making tombs.
It's malicious.
Correct.
That knowledge is why
I choose you.
Thank you!
Save the chit-chat!
Himi's been caught.
She'll be fine.
We must save her!
Is Himi alright?
They'll take her to their lord.
Their lord?
Your great-granduncle.
They'll use her
to make a deal with him.
A deal?
So they get everything.
The tower's full of parakeets now.
Your transgression
gave them an excuse.
"Transgression"?
The taboo.
You entered the delivery room.
A no-no.
But Himi didn't enter.
Taking you was taboo too.
This is a lookout.
Higher!
Subjects, this is far enough!
Await good news!
Let us accompany you!
Please let us!
Your sincerity is appreciated!
However, this is my duty.
Subjects, live well!
Three cheers for our parakeet king!
Be still!
We carry Lady Himi,
our lord's descendant!
Yield to us!
H-Heaven!
Our ancestors!
Paradise!
Your Majesty,
is this paradise?
Be silent.
Look at that!
So pretty...
So, you made it.
Have a seat.
No, we shall walk.
Entering the delivery room was wrong.
It is no laughing matter.
A grave transgression.
Unquestionably. The stone
is shimmering dangerously.
Nevertheless,
young souls are precious.
As king, I cannot
disregard a transgressor.
Give me time. I want Mahito
to become my successor.
Granduncle...
We must protect our world,
or it shall perish.
Mahito is a good boy.
It seems I must let him go.
Granduncle!
You must go too.
Th-That's it!
That passage.
I've been here before.
Yow! Youch!
I've never been this far in before...
We should return, Majesty!
I shall go. Make sure
you make it back alive,
and tell them I was a true king.
- We will!
- Fare thee well!
Hey chief, ain't it time
we got outta here?
This way.
Himi's calling.
I can't hear diddly-squat...
Himi!
Mahito!
Himi! Are you alright?!
Did they hurt you?!
No!
I thought I'd lost you.
I'm so glad!
Granduncle's waiting for you.
I know.
I'll go to him.
This feels wrong.
Don't...
Let's go.
Huh?
It's getting dark!
Stone blocks...
Better not touch them.
They're still powerful...
Granduncle,
I've brought Mahito.
Here I am.
Look. These stones
are not stained with malice.
I traveled the far reaches of
time and space to find them.
There are 13 in all.
Stack them once every three days.
Build your own tower.
A kingdom freed from malice.
Create a world of bounty,
peace, and beauty.
I made this scar myself.
It's a sign of my malice.
I can't touch those stones.
I'll go back with Natsuko,
my mother.
You'll return to a foolish world
of rampant murder and thievery?
Soon it shall be consumed by flames.
I'll make friends. Like Himi,
Kiriko, and the heron man.
Me?
Make friends. Return to your world.
But first, stack the stones.
There is no time!
I can not keep my tower standing.
Traitor! You would place the fate
of the empire upon mere stones?!
B-Be still. Still.
Damn you!
Himi! Mahito!
Return to the corridor of time!
To your own time!
Granduncle!
The planet's splitting!
Grab on!
Too much...
Granduncle!
Thank you!
Come on!
Hurry, hurry!
Miss Natsuko!
This is it! Mahito, you go in.
What about you?!
Mine's another.
I'm going to be your mother.
But you'll die in the hospital fire!
Fire doesn't scare me.
I'll be so lucky to have you.
No! Himi, you've got to live!
You're a good boy!
Holy moly!
- Mother!
- Mahito!
Thank goodness!
- Sister!
- All the best for the birth.
Now, hurry.
How adorable!
Hey!
This way!
Good.
The pelicans made it out too.
Hey, Mahito.
Do you remember where we were?
Of course I do.
That's bad.
Forget.
Why?
Forgetting is normal.
No keepsakes, right?
That's a powerful charm.
Way too powerful for me...
That's one of them stones.
From that field full of them.
Can't trust amateurs like you.
Well, that stone ain't powerful.
You'll forget in time.
You should.
So long, friend.
Ow ow ow!
Yeesh...
Kiriko!
The king?!
Natsuko!
Mahito!
- Shoichi!
- Father!
Two years after the war,
we returned to Tokyo.
Hey!
Mahito!
We're going!
Coming!
The clear sky on the day I was born
was so high, distant, and endless
The day I heard a voice
patting me on the back
telling me to go ahead
Faces I met in the seasons,
at times hurting one another
Shine by the light, the shadow extends
as the sky grows further away
I catch the wind and start running,
overcoming the rubble
At the end of this road,
someone is waiting for me
Dream of light shining through,
at any day of the week
Open the door this moment,
like revealing hidden secrets
Can't hold myself longing for more,
like the spinning globe
The person I loved
has gone to somewhere no one knows
With the usual kind
smile as any other day,
still somewhere far away
I take in the rain and start singing,
not minding if seen.
This road continues
because I wished it would continue
I dream of meeting again,
for ever and ever
I grasped the fragment firmly,
so the secret remains
I'll keep longing till the end,
like the spinning globe
It all starts from an innocent wish
made long ago
Carrying the loneliness in my heart,
I turn the corner
I catch the wind and start running,
overcoming the rubble
At the end of this road,
someone is waiting for me
Dream of light shining through,
at any day of the week
Open the door this moment,
like revealing hidden secrets
The joy of holding ones hand,
the suffering of losing one.
Can't hold myself from picturing,
like the spinning globe
English Dialogue by Don Brown
Subtitles by AURA
OCR & adjustments by pandamoon21